<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[USASearch]]></title>
  <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/all.atom" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-30T16:27:03+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/</id>
  <author><name><![CDATA[USASearch]]></name></author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Advanced Options to Add or Filter Specific URLs]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/domains-advanced.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/domains-advanced.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Manage Content > Domains > Advanced</p>

<h2>Add a URL</h2>

<p>Are specific web pages missing from your Bing web results? Tell us about these URLs and we'll append them to your web results. We offer two ways for you to tell us about the web pages that you want us to fetch and include in our web index, via an RSS feed (Supplemental Feed) or manually (Supplemental URLs).</p>

<h3>Supplemental Feed</h3>

<p>You can use an RSS feed to add URLs. The feed is useful if you'd like to automate the process, add multiple URLs, or both.</p>

<p>Enter the URL of your RSS feed. Click submit. We'll fetch each URL in your feed and index the title, description, <em>and the full text of the document</em> for the items you provide. We'll display the title and description you provide (not the page's title or a snippet based on the page's content).</p>

<p>Delete a URL added via RSS feed by deleting it as an item in your RSS feed. We'll remove the URL from our index the next time we fetch your RSS feed. If you need to remove it from our index immediately, you can take the additional step of deleting the URL by selecting Delete within the list of URLs on the Supplemental URLs page.</p>

<p>Note that you <em>must</em> delete the URL from your RSS feed. Otherwise, the URL will reappear the next time we fetch your RSS feed.</p>

<p>You can also delete <em>all</em> of the URLs added via the RSS feed by deleting the RSS feed itself.</p>

<h3>Supplemental URLs</h3>

<p>You can also manually add a a specific URL on the Supplemental URLs page. We'll fetch each URL you add manually and we'll index the title, description, <em>and the full text of the document</em> for the link you provide. We'll display the title and description you provide (not the page's title or a snippet based on the page's content).</p>

<p>Delete a manually added URL by selecting Delete within the list of supplemental URLs.</p>

<p>The source column in the crawl report shows how you added the URL, via an RSS feed or manually.</p>

<h2>Filter a URL</h2>

<p>You can filter <em>a single URL</em> from the results on your site. Use it for emergency reasons only (such as spillage of classified information or unintentional publication of a page). Note that this option should be used only if the <a href="/sites/manual/domains.html#filter">other options</a> aren't feasible as it can have an undesired effect on other features such as the display of spelling suggestions and relevance ranking.</p>

<p>It is not meant to fix the results for entire site, such as for launch or redesign problems. For tips on how to fix these more systemic problems, read our <a href="/blog/redesign.html">Checklist for a Successful Website Redesign</a>.</p>

<p>Entire the full path of the URL, e.g. use http://www.usa.gov/Citizen/Topics/Benefits.shtml, not usa.gov/citizen/topics.</p>

<p>You can later use the delete option to remove the filter.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Troubleshooting tip:</em></strong> We support RSS 2.0 and Atom feeds. Learn more and validate your feeds at:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://validator.w3.org/feed">W3C Feed Validation Service</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> (Atom &amp; RSS)</li>
<li>RSS 2.0 <a href="http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification">specification</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> and <a href="http://www.rssboard.org/rss-validator">validator</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /></li>
<li><a href="http://www.atomenabled.org/developers/syndication">Atom syndication format</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /></li>
</ul>


<p><strong><em>Troubleshooting tip:</em></strong> Are you seeing an error message in the crawled URLs report for your PDF that says, "No content found in document"? Your PDF is likely an image-only, non-searchable file that was created from a paper document using a scanner. See the resources below for more information on how to create searchable PDF files.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://blogs.adobe.com/acrolaw/2007/02/is_that_pdf_sea">Is that PDF Searchable?</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> (blog post)</li>
<li><a href="http://acrobatusers.com/tutorials/how-to-create-a-searchable-pdf-file">How to Create Searchable PDF File</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> (video)</li>
</ul>


<p><strong><em>Troubleshooting tip:</em></strong> Are you seeing an error message in the crawled URLs report that says your page is taking too long to load? Use <a href="http://tools.pingdom.com/fpt">Pingdom Tools Full Page Test</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> to test the load time of your page, analyze it, and find the bottlenecks.</p>

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> To help the public find your web pages when they search on Bing.com, we notify Bing about any URLs you add. While this helps with search engine optimization (SEO), it is not a cure-all. You should also register for and use commercial search engines' webmaster tools.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.bing.com/toolbox/webmaster">Bing Webmaster Tools</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /></li>
<li><a href="https://www.google.com/webmasters">Google Webmaster Central</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Edit Your Domains]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/domains.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/domains.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Manage Content > Domains</p>

<h2>Set Your Domains</h2>

<p>Enter the applicable domains, subdomains, or folders to return results specific to your website. You do not need to include http:// as we recognize domains with or without it.</p>

<h3>Entire Site</h3>

<p>List yoursite.gov (without www) to search your entire site, including all subdomains.</p>

<h3>Part of Site</h3>

<ul>
<li>List www.yoursite.gov to include only the primary 'www' domain.</li>
<li>List subdomain.yoursite.gov to include subdomains.</li>
<li>List yoursite.gov/folder to include folders.</li>
</ul>


<p>You cannot specify individual URLs.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Troubleshooting Tip:</em></strong> You can <em>exclude</em> specific subdomains or folders using any of the following options.</p>

<ol>
<li>List the excluded subdomains or folders in your <a href="http://www.robotstxt.org">robots.txt</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> file. This blocks them from all crawlers that follow the robots exclusion protocol, including Google.com and Bing.com.</li>
<li>Exclude them by omission. For example, to exclude subdomain3, list only subdomain1.yoursite.gov, subdomain2.yoursite.gov, and subdomain4.yoursite.gov.</li>
<li>E-mail us at <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#108;&#x74;&#111;&#x3a;&#85;&#83;&#x41;&#x53;&#x65;&#x61;&#114;&#99;&#x68;&#64;&#103;&#x73;&#97;&#46;&#103;&#x6f;&#x76;">&#x55;&#x53;&#65;&#83;&#101;&#x61;&#x72;&#x63;&#104;&#x40;&#x67;&#x73;&#x61;&#x2e;&#x67;&#x6f;&#118;</a> to filter them from your site's search results. Note that this option should be used only if the other options aren't feasible as it can have an undesired effect on other features such as the display of spelling suggestions and relevance ranking.</li>
</ol>


<p><a id="filter"></a><strong><em>Troubleshooting Tip:</em></strong> You can remove or filter specific URLs using any of the following options.</p>

<ol>
<li>Remove the page from your site and return a 404 (Not Found) 401 (Gone), or 301 (Permanently Moved) HTTP status.</li>
<li>Add a <a href="https://developers.google.com/webmasters/control-crawl-index/docs/robots_meta_tag?csw=1">noindex robots metatag or x-robots tag</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" />. This blocks them from all crawlers that follow the robots exclusion protocol, including Google.com and Bing.com.</li>
<li>Request the page's removal using the <a href="http://www.bing.com/webmaster/help/block-urls-from-bing-264e560a">Block URLs option in Bing Webaster Tools</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> and <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/1663419">Remove URLs option in Google Webmaster Tools</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" />.</li>
<li>Use the Filter URLs option under the <a href="/sites/manual/display-advanced.html">Advanced</a> tab.</li>
</ol>


<p><strong><em>Troubleshooting Tip:</em></strong> Are specific web pages missing from your Bing web results? You can tell us about any missing URLs via an RSS feed or manually (the Supplemental Feed and Supplemental URLs options under the <a href="/sites/manual/display-advanced.html">Advanced</a> tab, respectively). We'll fetch and index the pages and append them to your web results.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Add JavaScript for Your Third Party Web Services]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/third-party.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/third-party.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Analytics > 3rd Party Tracking</p>

<p>Do you want your search results page to run web services such as 4Q, AddThis, Foresee, Google Analytics, Omniture, Siteimprove, or WebTrends?</p>

<p>Input the JavaScript code you'd like to call from your search results page. Click submit to send us your request. We'll input your code for you and send you an email to confirm that we've done it.</p>

<p>Some tips for commonly used third party web services follow.</p>

<h2>Google Analytics Tip</h2>

<p>In your Google Analytics JavaScript, be sure to set your domain if you've requested <a href="/sites/manual/cname.html">domain masking</a> and you want to include your search subdomain (e.g., search.commerce.gov) with your main domain (e.g., commerce.gov).</p>

<pre><code>_gaq.push(['_setDomainName', 'commerce.gov']);
</code></pre>

<p>For more information, read Google's tip, <a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/gaTrackingSite">Tracking Multiple Domains</a>.</p>

<p>The code you submit should look something like one of the following two scripts.</p>

<h3>Google Analytics Code (Older Format)</h3>

<pre><code> &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
 var _gaq = _gaq || []; 
 _gaq.push(['_setAccount', 'UA-########-1']); 
 _gaq.push(['_trackPageview']);

 (function() { 
 var ga = document.createElement('script'); ga.type = 'text/javascript'; ga.async = true; 
 ga.src = ('https:' == document.location.protocol ? 'https://ssl'; : 'http://www') +      '.google-analytics.com/ga.js'; 
 var s = document.getElementsByTagName('script')[0]; s.parentNode.insertBefore(ga, s); 
 })();

 &lt;/script&gt;
</code></pre>

<h3>Google Analytics Code (Newer Format)</h3>

<pre><code>(function(i,s,o,g,r,a,m){i['GoogleAnalyticsObject']=r;i[r]=i[r]||function(){
(i[r].q=i[r].q||[]).push(arguments)},i[r].l=1*new Date();a=s.createElement(o),
m=s.getElementsByTagName(o)[0];a.async=1;a.src=g;m.parentNode.insertBefore(a,m)
})(window,document,'script','//www.google-analytics.com/analytics.js','ga');
</code></pre>

<h2>Digital Analytics Program Tip</h2>

<p>Does your federal agency participate in the <a href="http://www.howto.gov/web-content/digital-metrics/digital-analytics-program">Digital Analytics Program</a> (DAP)?</p>

<p>You don't need to upload the full DAP Google Analytics code. You can simply say something like, "Add DAP code."</p>

<h2>ForeSee Tip</h2>

<p>Coordinate with your ForeSee representative and USASearch to implement your customer satisfaction survey on your results page. The four general steps follow.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Email us at <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#105;&#108;&#x74;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#x55;&#x53;&#65;&#x53;&#101;&#x61;&#114;&#99;&#104;&#x40;&#x67;&#115;&#97;&#x2e;&#x67;&#111;&#118;">&#85;&#x53;&#65;&#83;&#101;&#97;&#114;&#x63;&#104;&#64;&#x67;&#115;&#x61;&#46;&#x67;&#111;&#x76;</a> to <a href="/sites/manual/cname.html">set up a CNAME</a> for search.{yourdomain}.gov.</p></li>
<li><p>Update the files path in your Foresee code to use an absolute path instead of a relative path.</p>

<p> Find => 'files': '/fsrscripts/',</p>

<p> and replace it with => 'files': '//{yourdomain}/fsrscripts/',</p>

<p> in the following five files.</p>

<ul>
<li>foresee-trigger.js</li>
<li>foresee-tracker.js</li>
<li>foresee-alive.js</li>
<li>foresee-qualifier.js</li>
<li>foresee-test.js</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Ask ForeSee to send USASearch your foresee-trigger.js file.</p></li>
<li><p>USASearch will send you an email to confirm that we've set up your CNAME and installed your foresee-trigger.js file.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>It should look something like the following.</p>

<pre><code> &lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://www.YourAgency.gov/library/foresee/foresee-trigger.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Access Your Raw Logs]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/raw-logs.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/raw-logs.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Analytics > Raw Logs Access</p>

<p>You can directly access your raw HTTP logs. The logs include valuable data on searches, clicks, and USASearch tag page loads.</p>

<p>With the raw logs, you can conduct in-depth, ad hoc analyses to answer any questions that you can't answer using the standard analytics reports in the <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a>. You can also automatically integrate your search logs with your other reports and business processes.</p>

<p>To access your raw logs, you'll first need to upload your public key on the Raw Logs Access page in the <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a>.</p>

<p>We'll set up your public key on our secure FTP servers and send you an email when your logs are available for download.</p>

<p>Once your key is set up, you'll be able access your log files via secure FTP. We upload your logs each day, usually within several hours after midnight GMT. After a week, we purge the older files.</p>

<p>We recommend that you set up a cron script to automatically download the latest files each day.</p>

<h2>How to Generate a Key Pair on Unix</h2>

<p>On Unix systems, you can generate a RSA public key with no passphrase by typing in the following command. Generate the key from the machine or server that you'll be using to download the logs. Once you've created a key, it'll be located at /home/user/.ssh/id_rsa.pub.</p>

<pre><code>% cd ~
% ssh-keygen -q -b 4096 -t rsa
Enter file in which to save the key (/home/user/.ssh/id_rsa):
Enter passphrase (empty for no passphrase):
Enter same passphrase again:
</code></pre>

<h2>How to Generate a Key Pair on Windows</h2>

<p>You can use <a href="http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty">PuTTY</a>, a free telnet/SSH client, to generate a public key on Windows. Download PuTTYgen.exe, Pageant.exe, and PSFTP.exe from the <a href="http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/download.html">PuTTY Download Page</a>.</p>

<p>Run PuTTYgen.exe.</p>

<ul>
<li>Select SSH-2 RSA as the type of key to generate.</li>
<li>Set the number of bits in the generated key to 2048.</li>
<li>Select Generate. Move your mouse within the blank area to create random movements until the key is generated.</li>
<li>Fill out your Key Comment, Key Passphrase, and Confirm Passphrase.</li>
<li>Copy your <em>public</em> key from the string in the Public Key for Pasting into OpenSSH Authorized_keys File. Paste this key into the Raw Logs Access page in the <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a>. (Note: Don't save this public key and send us the string copied from a text file. It adds lines in the file so it doesn't work.)</li>
<li>Save your <em>private</em> key.</li>
</ul>


<p>Run Pageant.exe. Select Add Key and upload your private key, the .ppk file.</p>

<p>Run PSFTP.exe and type in the following. You can find your site's handle on the Site Information page in the <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a>.</p>

<pre><code>open YourSiteHandle@198.61.238.46
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Activate Your Search by Adding Our Code Snippets to Your Website]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/code.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/code.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Activate Search > Code Snippets</p>

<p>Visit our <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a>, select your site, and click on the Activate Search option in the left-hand menu.</p>

<p>Add the following two snippets of code to your website to "hook" your website and our hosted search service together. You can add this code to your individual web pages or to the template(s) in your content management system.</p>

<h2>1. Form Snippet</h2>

<p>Include this snippet of code where the form for your search box appears. It should look something like this:</p>

<pre><code>&lt;form accept-charset="UTF-8" action="http://search.usa.gov/search" id="search_form" method="get"&gt;
    &lt;div style="margin:0;padding:0;display:inline"&gt;
    &lt;input name="utf8" type="hidden" value="&amp;#x2713;" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;input id="affiliate" name="affiliate" type="hidden" value="YourSiteHandle" /&gt;
    &lt;label for="query"&gt;Enter Search Term(s):&lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input autocomplete="off" class="usagov-search-autocomplete" id="query" name="query" type="text" /&gt;
    &lt;input name="commit" type="submit" value="Search" /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
</code></pre>

<h2>2. Javascript Snippet</h2>

<p>Include this snippet of code before the closing <code>&lt;body&gt;</code> tag. This tag enables type-ahead search in the search box on your web pages and powers the data on trending URLs on the <a href="/sites/manual/site-overview.html">Site Overview</a> page in the Admin Center. It should look something like this:</p>

<pre><code>&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
//&lt;![CDATA[
      var usasearch_config = { siteHandle:"YourSiteHandle" };

      var script = document.createElement("script");
      script.type = "text/javascript";
      script.src = "http://search.usa.gov/javascripts/remote.loader.js";
      document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0].appendChild(script);

//]]&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;
</code></pre>

<h2>Setting Up a Search Box for Specific Folders or Subdomains</h2>

<p>You can limit results to specific folders or subdomains by creating a collection, setting up an RSS feed, or passing in a hidden value.</p>

<h3>Collection</h3>

<p>Create a <a href="/sites/manual/collections.html">collection</a>. Then update your form code to (a) change the action to <code>action="http://search.usa.gov/search/docs/</code> and (b) add an input for this collection, <code>&lt;input type="hidden" name="dc" value="###"&gt;</code>. It should look something like this:</p>

<pre><code>&lt;form accept-charset="UTF-8" action="http://search.usa.gov/search/docs/" id="search_form" method="get"&gt;
    &lt;div style="margin:0;padding:0;display:inline"&gt;
    &lt;input type="hidden" name="dc" value="###"&gt;
    &lt;input name="utf8" type="hidden" value="&amp;#x2713;" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;input id="affiliate" name="affiliate" type="hidden" value="YourSiteHandle" /&gt;
    &lt;label for="query"&gt;Enter Search Term(s):&lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input autocomplete="off" class="usagov-search-autocomplete" id="query" name="query" type="text" /&gt;
    &lt;input name="commit" type="submit" value="Search" /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>The value is the number for your collection ID, which is visible in the URL when you edit your collection in the Admin Center as shown in the sample below.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/get-code-collection.png" alt="Value for the collection ID" /></p>

<h3>RSS Feed</h3>

<p>Set up an <a href="/sites/manual/rss.html">RSS feed</a>. Then update your form code to (a) change the action to <code>action="http://search.usa.gov/search/news/</code> and (b) add an input for this feed, <code>&lt;input type="hidden" name="channel" value="###"&gt;</code>.  It should look something like this:</p>

<pre><code>&lt;form accept-charset="UTF-8" action="http://search.usa.gov/search/news/" id="search_form" method="get"&gt;
    &lt;div style="margin:0;padding:0;display:inline"&gt;
    &lt;input type="hidden" name="channel" value="###"&gt;
    &lt;input name="utf8" type="hidden" value="&amp;#x2713;" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;input id="affiliate" name="affiliate" type="hidden" value="YourSiteHandle" /&gt;
    &lt;label for="query"&gt;Enter Search Term(s):&lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input autocomplete="off" class="usagov-search-autocomplete" id="query" name="query" type="text" /&gt;
    &lt;input name="commit" type="submit" value="Search" /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>The value is the number for your RSS ID, which is visible in the URL when you edit or preview your feed in the Admin Center.</p>

<h3>Hidden Value</h3>

<p>Leave your domain blank on the <a href="/sites/manual/domains.html">Domains</a> page and, instead, passing a hidden value for the domain in the search form code.</p>

<p>See, for example, <a href="http://www.ri.gov">RI.gov</a>, <a href="http://www.dmv.ri.gov/">DMV.RI.gov</a>, <a href="http://www.health.ri.gov/">Health.RI.gov</a>. On Health.RI.gov, the following hidden value is added to limit to only the health subdomain.</p>

<pre><code>&lt;input type="hidden" name="site" value="www.health.ri.gov" &gt;
</code></pre>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Troubleshooting tip:</em></strong> If your website is secured with https, you can add 's' to the two URLs above (i.e., <a href="https://search.usa.gov/search">https://search.usa.gov/search</a> and <a href="https://search.usa.gov/javascripts/remote.loader.js">https://search.usa.gov/javascripts/remote.loader.js</a>, respectively) so that searchers don't receive a security message in Internet Explorer.</p>

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> If you're using Drupal, be sure to check out our <a href="https://drupal.org/project/USASearch">USASearch Drupal module</a>.</p>

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> We offer <a href="/sites/manual/cname.html">DNS masking</a>, which allows you to show searchers your domain (instead of USA.gov).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How (and When) to Use the Search API]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/api.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/api.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Activate Search > API Instructions</p>

<p>We offer our search results as a hosted results page (using our <a href="/sites/manual/code.html">code snippets</a>) or as an <a href="http://www.howto.gov/mobile/apis-in-government/api-basics">application programming interface</a> (API).</p>

<h2>When to Use the Hosted Results</h2>

<p>Most agencies use our hosted search results page. We recommend that you to use our hosted page for the typical use case of returning search results on your website. Using the hosted page has many benefits such as allowing you to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Devote minimal development resources for the initial set up.</li>
<li>Benefit from new features automatically as they're rolled out.</li>
<li>Stay current with search best practices, such as type-ahead search and formatting of search results.</li>
</ul>


<h2>When to Use the API</h2>

<p>You may need to access our search results to present them outside of a typical search results page. We offer our results as an API for these use cases.</p>

<p>You can access the API and its documentation at <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Activate Search > API Instructions.</p>

<p>The API returns results from each of our indexes&mdash;web, image, document (ODIE), RSS (news), video, best bets (boosted content), related searches, and <a href="/developer/jobs.html">jobs</a>&mdash;in JSON, JSON-P, or XML.</p>

<p>We recommend you use our API for limited use cases such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>Displaying search results within a native mobile application (i.e., an Android or iPhone app).</li>
<li>Integrating USASearch results within existing applications (such as your intranet or publications catalog).</li>
<li>Creating data mashups.</li>
</ul>


<p>Examples of how agencies are currently using the API follow.</p>

<h3>Use Case 1. Display Results in Your Mobile App</h3>

<p>USA.gov and the White House use the Search API to render USASearch results within their mobile apps.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_me79cgQKOE1qid15q.jpg" alt="Screenshot of a USASearch results page in the USA.gov iPhone app" /><br/>
<em>Screenshot of a USASearch results page in the USA.gov iPhone app</em></p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_me78zp7y4v1qid15q.jpg" alt="Screenshot of a USASearch results page in the White House iPhone app" /><br/>
<em>Screenshot of a USASearch results page in the White House iPhone app</em></p>

<p><strong>Related Links for Use Case 1</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://apps.usa.gov/usagov.shtml">USA.gov mobile app</a></li>
<li><a href="http://apps.usa.gov/the-white-house-app.shtml">WhiteHouse mobile app</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/whitehouse">White House Github account</a> (information on and source code for the iOS and Android mobile apps)</li>
</ul>


<h3>Use Case 2. Integrate USASearch Results within existing applications</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.ri.gov">RI.gov</a> manages hundreds of distinct websites. The state provides a consistent search experience across all of its websites. Some sites are centrally controlled by RI.gov. Others are not. Using the Search API, RI.gov programmatically tells USASearch the site's domain from which the user searched (e.g., tmc.dot.ri.gov). RI.gov then highlights results from this specific domain within RI.gov's common look and feel.</p>

<p>See the sample results page below that shows a set of results displayed on Rhode Island's <a href="http://www.tmc.dot.ri.gov">Transportation Management Center</a> for a search on <em>traffic</em>.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_me7ej38m3P1qid15q.png" alt="Step 1. Searcher on &lt;www.tmc.dot.ri.gov&gt; types traffic in the search box" /><br/>
<em>Step 1. Searcher on <a href="http://www.tmc.dot.ri.gov">http://www.tmc.dot.ri.gov</a> types traffic in the search box</em></p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_me7el3bJin1qid15q.png" alt="Step 2. Searcher sees results on RI.gov with a common look and feel that highlights results from the original site" /><br/>
<em>Step 2. Searcher sees results on RI.gov with a common look and feel that highlights results from the original site</em></p>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> The Search API is available for government websites only. Visit our <a href="/developer/index.html">APIs page</a> for other, publicly available APIs (i.e., for use by anyone).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How It Works]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/help-desk.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/help-desk.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>USASearch is a hosted site search service provided by the <a href="http://www.gsa.gov/portal/category/25729">Office of Citizen Services and Innovative Technologies</a>, <a href="http://www.gsa.gov">U.S. General Services Administration</a>. You can use USASearch to power the search box on your federal, state, local, tribal, or territorial government website&mdash;at no cost.</p>

<ul>
<li>We provide a search box that searches across all of your <em>public-facing</em> digital content. We support an unlimited number of web pages across multiple domains and we integrate your RSS feeds, tweets, YouTube videos, and Flickr photos.</li>
<li>We provide a self-service Admin Center so you can review your search analytics and manage the search experience for your website, including telling us what content you want indexed, setting up the display of your results page, and curating recommendations.</li>
<li>We maintain a 99.95%-plus uptime and deliver nearly all search results in less than 750 milliseconds. Our system is certified and accredited.</li>
</ul>


<h2>How To Set It Up</h2>

<p>Browse through our <a href="/tagged/how-to">How To Manual</a> and <a href="/blog/go-live.html">Go-Live Punch List</a> for tips on how to configure the search experience for your website.</p>

<h3>Dashboard</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/site-overview.html">Site overview</a></li>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/users.html">Manage users</a></li>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/settings.html">Settings</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>Analytics</h3>

<ul>
<li>Queries - Help file is coming soon!</li>
<li>Clicks - Help file is coming soon!</li>
<li>Monthly reports - Help file is coming soon!</li>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/third-party.html">3rd party tracking</a></li>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/raw-logs.html">Raw logs</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>Manage Content</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/domains.html">Domains</a> plus <a href="/sites/manual/domains-advanced.html">advanced options to add or filter URLs</a></li>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/collections.html">Collections</a></li>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/best-bets-text.html">Best bets:text</a></li>
<li>Best bets: graphics - Help file is coming soon!</li>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/rss.html">RSS</a></li>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/youtube.html">YouTube</a></li>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/twitter.html">Twitter</a></li>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/flickr.html">Flickr</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>Manage Display</h3>

<p>Help files are coming soon!</p>

<h3>Preview</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/preview.html">Preview</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>Activate Search</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/code.html">Code snippets</a></li>
<li><a href="/sites/manual/api.html">API instructions</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Also be sure to read our <a href="/tagged/releases">release notes</a> to keep up-to-date with our new features.</p>

<p>Do you have other questions or comments about how our service works? E-mail us at <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#x6c;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#x55;&#x53;&#x41;&#83;&#x65;&#x61;&#x72;&#x63;&#104;&#64;&#103;&#115;&#x61;&#x2e;&#x67;&#111;&#x76;">&#x55;&#x53;&#x41;&#x53;&#101;&#x61;&#x72;&#99;&#104;&#x40;&#x67;&#x73;&#x61;&#46;&#103;&#111;&#x76;</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Punch List to Go Live with USASearch]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/go-live.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/go-live.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Your pre-launch checklist will be unique to your agency's workflow, requirements, and deadlines. A typical punch list to go live with USASearch follows.</p>

<h2>Connect Your Site to USASearch</h2>

<p>Most agencies add these two <a href="/sites/manual/code.html">snippets of code</a> to the template(s) in their content management systems (rather than adding them to individual pages).</p>

<p><i class="icon-check"></i> <strong>1. Does your search box point to USASearch?</strong> Update your search box form code point to USASearch so that, when users execute a search, they'll see your USASearch-hosted results page.</p>

<pre><code>&lt;form accept-charset="UTF-8" action="http://search.usa.gov/search" id="search_form" method="get"&gt;&lt;div style="margin:0;padding:0;display:inline"&gt;&lt;input name="utf8" type="hidden" value="&amp;#x2713;" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
     &lt;input id="affiliate" name="affiliate" type="hidden" value="YourSiteHandle" /&gt; 
    &lt;label for="query"&gt;Enter Search Term(s):&lt;/label&gt; 
    &lt;input autocomplete="off" class="usagov-search-autocomplete" id="query" name="query" type="text" /&gt; 
    &lt;input name="commit" type="submit" value="Search" /&gt; 
&lt;/form&gt;
</code></pre>

<p><i class="icon-check"></i> <strong>2. Do you have the USASearch Javascript tag on your webpages?</strong> This Javascript powers the <a href="/sites/manual/display-overview.html">type-ahead search</a>. It also provides data on your trending URLs on the <a href="/sites/manual/site-overview.html">Site Overview</a> page in the <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a>.</p>

<pre><code>&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
//&lt;![CDATA[
     var usasearch_config = { siteHandle:"YourSiteHandle" };
    var script = document.createElement("script");
    script.type = "text/javascript";
    script.src = "http://search.usa.gov/javascripts/remote.loader.js";
    document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0].appendChild(script);
//]]&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;
</code></pre>

<h2>Double Check Your Content Sources</h2>

<p><i class="icon-check"></i> <strong>3. Have you told us which domain(s) you want to search?</strong> List one or more <a href="/sites/manual/domains.html">domains</a> that you want to search on the first page of web results. Most agencies opt to leave out the 'www' to include all subdomains (for example, list usa.gov to include answers.usa.gov, blog.usa.gov, publications.usa.gov, etc). Some agencies especially department-level portals opt to also include their bureaus' websites (for example, Commerce.gov includes commerce.gov, noaa.gov, trade.gov, etc.)</p>

<p><i class="icon-check"></i> <strong>4. Have you told us about your RSS feeds?</strong> We love <a href="/sites/manual/rss.html">RSS feeds</a>. Tell us about all of your feeds, even if you opt not to show them (see #7 below). They're the quickest way for you to tell us about your new and updated content. Feeds also have well-structured titles, URLs, descriptions, and dates that we use to improve your search results page. (Tip: Preview your feeds from the RSS page in the <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> to confirm that we've indexed your content.)</p>

<p><i class="icon-check"></i> <strong>5. Have you told us about your social media accounts?</strong> <a href="/sites/manual/flickr.html">Flickr photostreams</a>, <a href="/sites/manual/twitter.html">tweets</a>, and <a href="/sites/manual/youtube.html">YouTube videos</a> are a great way to highlight your recent content. Tell us about all of your social media, even if you opt not to show them (see #7 below).</p>

<h2>Customize the Display of Your Search Results Page</h2>

<p><i class="icon-check"></i> <strong>6. Have you made the search results page look like your website?</strong> Customize the <a href="/sites/manual/font-color.html">fonts and colors</a> and <a href="/sites/manual/image-assets.html">image assets</a> (logo, background image, and favicon) of your search results page to create a seamless experience for users as they search and browse your website.</p>

<p><i class="icon-check"></i> <strong>7. Have you told us what to show on your results page?</strong> Turn on (or off) the modules (that is, the stuff in the center of the page) and sidebar options (that is, the facets in the left-hand column) you want to appear on your search results. You can change the default settings on the <a href="/sites/manual/display-overview.html">Display Overview</a> page in the Admin Center.</p>

<h2>Set Up Nice-to-Have Features (Optional)</h2>

<p><i class="icon-check"></i> <strong>8. Have you masked your domain?</strong> We offer <a href="/sites/manual/cname.html">DNS masking</a>, which allows you to show searchers your search.YOURSITE.gov (instead of search.USA.gov). If you leverage DNS masking you will have to change your search box form action from search.usa.gov to search.YOURSITE.gov.</p>

<p><i class="icon-check"></i> <strong>9. Have you added the Javascripts for your other third party web services to your results page?</strong> If you have a <a href="/sites/manual/third-party.html">third party service</a> running on your website, you likely want it to run on your results page. Agencies often include their 4Q, AddThis, Foresee, Google Analytics, Omniture, or WebTrends code, among others.</p>

<h2>Don't Forget SEO (Optional)</h2>

<p><i class="icon-check"></i> <strong>10. Have you optimized your site so we can find your content?</strong> We follow <a href="http://www.howto.gov/web-content/search/seo">search engine optimization</a> (SEO) best practices. Verify that you have a <a href="http://www.robotstxt.org">robots.txt</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> and an <a href="http://www.sitemaps.org">XML sitemap</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" />. These two files are typically located in the root directory of your website (i.e., agency.gov/robots.txt and agency.gov/sitemap.xml, respectively). Also verify that your robots.txt file allows our user agent (usasearch) to access your public content.</p>

<p><i class="icon-check"></i> <strong>11. Have you registered your site with the major commercial search engines?</strong> Register for both <a href="http://www.bing.com/toolbox/webmaster">Bing Webmaster Tools</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> and <a href="https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/home">Google Webmaster Tools</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> to maximize the coverage of your content in their search results.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Mask Your Domain]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/cname.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/cname.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We offer DNS masking, which allows you to show searchers search.YOURSITE.gov (instead of search.USA.gov). Follow these three steps to mask your domain.</p>

<ol>
<li>E-mail us at <a href="&#109;&#97;&#105;&#108;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#x55;&#83;&#65;&#83;&#x65;&#97;&#x72;&#99;&#104;&#x40;&#x67;&#x73;&#x61;&#x2e;&#103;&#x6f;&#x76;">&#85;&#x53;&#x41;&#83;&#x65;&#x61;&#x72;&#x63;&#x68;&#x40;&#103;&#115;&#97;&#46;&#x67;&#111;&#118;</a> and ask us to mask your domain.</li>
<li>Create a CNAME in your DNS records for <em>search.yoursite.gov</em>. Point it to <em>search.usa.gov.edgekey.net</em>.</li>
<li>When the setup is complete, change the code for your form action from <em>search.usa.gov</em> to <em>search.yoursite.gov</em>.</li>
</ol>


<hr />

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> By default, we set up search.YOURSITE.gov (such as search.nih.gov). If this subdomain is already used by another application, you can request YOURSITEsearch.YOURSITE.gov (such as usdasearch.usda.gov) or another pattern.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create an Account]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/account.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/account.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > My Account</p>

<p>You can use USASearch to power the search box on your federal, state, local, tribal, or territorial government website at no cost.</p>

<p>Access to our hosted search service requires authentication and verification that you're a government employee or contractor.</p>

<h2>Log In</h2>

<p><a href="http://search.usa.gov/sites">Log in</a> to an existing account or register for a new account at <a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">http://usasearch.howto.gov</a>. Select the Login option in the upper right-hand corner and fill out your information.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/login.png" alt="Login from USASearch.HowTo.gov" /></p>

<p>After you register, you'll receive an automatic e-mail. Click on the link in the e-mail to verify that your e-mail address belongs to you.</p>

<p>If you have a .gov or .mil address, you'll be able to access your account immediately after you verify your e-mail.</p>

<p>If you don't have a .gov or .mil address, we'll ask for additional information to confirm that you're a government employee or contractor. We'll notify you when your account is approved.</p>

<h2>Add a Site</h2>

<p>Once your account is approved, you can <a href="/sites/manual/add-site.html">add a site</a> in our <a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites">Admin Center</a>.</p>

<h2>Update Your Contact Information</h2>

<p>You can edit your name, agency, or email by selecting the option, My Account, in the drop-down menu in the upper-right hand corner.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Troubleshooting tip:</em></strong> We cannot retrieve any passwords for any account, because we don't have access to passwords. To reset your password:</p>

<ol>
<li>Go to the USASearch Login page at <a href="https://search.usa.gov/login">https://search.usa.gov/login</a></li>
<li>Enter your e-mail address.</li>
<li>Click on Forgot your password?</li>
<li>You will be prompted to reset your password and it will be emailed to you.</li>
</ol>


<p>If you have any problem resetting your password, e-mail us at <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#x69;&#108;&#x74;&#111;&#x3a;&#85;&#83;&#65;&#83;&#101;&#x61;&#114;&#x63;&#104;&#x40;&#x67;&#x73;&#97;&#x2e;&#x67;&#111;&#118;">&#x55;&#83;&#65;&#x53;&#x65;&#x61;&#114;&#x63;&#104;&#x40;&#x67;&#115;&#97;&#46;&#103;&#111;&#x76;</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Add a New Site]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/add-site.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/add-site.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > Add Site</p>

<h2>Homepage URL</h2>

<p>Tell us the homepage URL of your website. Enter a fully qualified URL, including http://, http://www, etc.</p>

<p><strong>Correct Syntax</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>http://www.whitehouse.gov</li>
<li>http://louisiana.gov</li>
<li>http://www.usa.gov/gobiernousa/</li>
<li>http://nimh.nih.gov/</li>
<li>http://www.ci.bloomington.mn.us/</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Incorrect Syntax</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>usa.gov (use http://www.usa.gov)</li>
<li>www.nasa.gov (use http://www.nasa.gov)</li>
<li>http://www.ftc.gov/opa/index.shtml (use the higher-level folder, http://www.ftc.gov/opa)</li>
<li>http://www.gsa.gov/portal/category/100000?utm_source=OCM&amp;utm_medium=print-radio&amp;utm_term=&amp;utm_campaign=shortcuts (use the higher-level domain, http://www.gsa.gov)</li>
<li>http://www.doc.gov (use the domain that resolves, http://www.commerce.gov)</li>
</ul>


<p>We use this homepage URL to (a) populate your primary <a href="/sites/manual/domains.html">domain</a> and (b) link the default logo on your results page to your homepage.</p>

<h2>Display Name</h2>

<p>Tell us the name of your website. Searchers see your site name on the results page, such as in your page title or best bets. We recommend using the plain language name for your agency or site, such as National Institutes of Health.</p>

<h2>Site Handle</h2>

<p>We use your site handle in the HTTP request to specify displaying your customized settings. We recommend making this handle short and unique, such as nih.</p>

<p>Handles can have lowercase letters, numbers, periods, hyphens, and underscores only. They can't have spaces and other punctuation.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/settings.png" alt="Site name and handle on NIH.gov's search results page" /></p>

<h2>Site Language (Required)</h2>

<p>Choose a language for your site, English or Spanish. We will only index and provide results for pages in your selected language. All display text on the results page will also be in your selected language.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Troubleshooting Tip:</em></strong> Once you've added your site, edit your display name on the <a href="/sites/manual/settings.html">Settings</a> page. If you later need to edit your site handle or language, e-mail us at <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#x69;&#x6c;&#116;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#x55;&#x53;&#x41;&#x53;&#101;&#97;&#x72;&#99;&#x68;&#x40;&#103;&#x73;&#x61;&#46;&#103;&#111;&#118;">&#x55;&#x53;&#x41;&#83;&#x65;&#97;&#114;&#x63;&#104;&#x40;&#103;&#115;&#97;&#x2e;&#x67;&#x6f;&#x76;</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Add Your YouTube Videos to Our Index]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/youtube.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/youtube.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Manage Content > YouTube</p>

<h2>Tell Us About Your YouTube Channel</h2>

<p>Provide us with the username for your YouTube channel(s). When you're on YouTube's website, you can see your username in the URL at http://www.youtube.com/user/YourUserName.</p>

<p>For example, the username for NASA's YouTube channel is <a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/NASAtelevision">NASAtelevision</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" />.</p>

<!-- START UPDATE -->


<h2>Opt to Display Your Videos</h2>

<p>When you add the username for your YouTube channel, we'll automatically index your videos&mdash;both your uploaded videos and playlists.</p>

<p>You can control the display of the videos on the <a href="/sites/manual/display-overview.html">Display Overview</a> page. You can show the videos as a (a) facet by turning on the option to show in the Sidebar, (b) GovBox on your main web results page by turning on the option to show as a GovBox, or both.</p>

<p>You can edit the default title, Videos, on the RSS feed on the <a href="/sites/manual/rss.html">RSS</a> page.</p>

<!-- END UPDATE -->


<p>See the sample results page below that shows video results displayed on the National Institute of Justice for a search on <em><a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?query=violence&amp;affiliate=nationalinstituteofjustice">violence</a></em>.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/social-media-video1.png" alt="Results page with videos shown as a GovBox" /><br/>
<em>Results page with videos shown as a GovBox</em></p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/social-media-video2.png" alt="Video results page shown when searcher opts to view videos" /><br/>
<em>Video results page shown when searcher opts to view videos</em></p>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> Do you have a multimedia gallery on your website for your agency's photos, images, videos, podcasts, or other multimedia content? Do you use a content management system, database, or media RSS (MRSS) feed to power this gallery? You can index <a href="/sites/manual/rss.html">MRSS feeds</a> so that your multimedia content is automatically included in your search results.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Add Your RSS Feeds to Our Index]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/rss.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/rss.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Manage Content > RSS</p>

<p>Would you like searchers to be able to search your news or multimedia content? Would you like them to be able to narrow results by date?</p>

<p>Tell us the locations and names of your RSS feeds. We index all new and updated content on your feeds within minutes.</p>

<h2>Step 1. Tell Us About Your RSS Feeds</h2>

<p>We love feeds! Tell us about <em>all</em> of your RSS feeds, even if you don't opt to show them in step 2 below. Feeds are the fastest and most reliable way for us to learn about your new and updated content.</p>

<p>Select the option to add a new RSS feed.</p>

<h3>Name</h3>

<p>Create a name for the feed. Within this 'bucket' you can list a single RSS feed or many feeds. For example, you can opt to list all of your agency's press releases separately (such as Police News, Fire News, EMS News, etc.) or you can list all three under one general name (such as News).</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/rss.png" alt="Add an RSS Feed" /></p>

<h3>Feed type</h3>

<p>Select the type of feed. The default option is RSS (for text content like press releases or blogs). Change it to <a href="http://www.rssboard.org/media-rss">media RSS</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> for multimedia content like images and videos.</p>

<p>Each item within a RSS feed must include a title, link, description, and publication date.</p>

<p>Each item within a media RSS feed must also include both a <a href="http://www.rssboard.org/media-rss#media-content">media:content URL</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> to specify a direct URL to the media object and a <a href="http://www.rssboard.org/media-rss#media-thumbnails">media:thumbnail URL</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> to specify a URL to the object's thumbnail.</p>

<p>Any items missing a required element won't display in your search results.</p>

<h3>Sample RSS Item with All Required Elements</h3>

<pre><code>&lt;item&gt;
&lt;title&gt;
Statement from Agriculture Secretary Tom Vilsack Regarding World Organization for Animal Health (OIE) Upgrade of United States&amp;apos; BSE Risk Status
&lt;/title&gt;
&lt;pubDate&gt;May 29, 2013 00:00:00 CDT&lt;/pubDate&gt;
&lt;link&gt;
http://www.usda.gov/wps/portal/usda/usdahome?contentid=2013/05/0106.xml&amp;contentidonly=true
&lt;/link&gt;
&lt;description&gt;
WASHINGTON, May 29, 2013Agriculture Secretary Tom Vilsack made the following statement about notification received today from the World Organization for Animal Health (OIE) upgrading the United States&amp;apos; risk classification for bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE) to negligible risk:
&lt;/description&gt;
&lt;/item&gt;
</code></pre>

<h3>Sample Media RSS Item with All Required Elements</h3>

<pre><code>&lt;item&gt;
&lt;title type="html"&gt;
&lt;![CDATA[ Great Lakes Beach Health ]]&gt;
&lt;/title&gt;
&lt;link&gt;
http://gallery.usgs.gov/photos/05_24_2013_gkb4Erq11X_05_24_2013_0
&lt;/link&gt;
&lt;guid&gt;
http://gallery.usgs.gov/photos/05_24_2013_gkb4Erq11X_05_24_2013_0
&lt;/guid&gt;
&lt;pubDate&gt;Fri, 24 May 2013 00:00:00 EDT&lt;/pubDate&gt;
&lt;media:description type="html"&gt;
&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;p&gt;As schools close for the year and summer weather beckons, many recreationalists head to the Great Lakes' public beaches. However, these coastal areas can become     contaminated with disease-causing bacteria that threaten public health, disrupt water   recreation, and pay a toll on the Great Lakes econ
]]&gt;
&lt;![CDATA[
omies that depend on summer tourism.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The U.S. Geological Survey &lt;a href="http://greatlakesbeaches.usgs.gov/index.html"&gt;Great Lakes Beach Health&lt;/a&gt; initiative provides science-based information and methods that help beach managers make more accurate beach closure and advisory decisions, &lt;a href="http://www.usgs.gov/newsroom/article.asp?ID=3063#.UZv3pSs_87A"&gt;preventing unnecessary beach closures&lt;/a&gt; while protecting public health.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;
&lt;/media:description&gt;
&lt;media:thumbnail url="http://gallery.usgs.gov/images/05_24_2013/gkb4Erq11X_05_24_2013/thumbs/CoastalEco_KPrzybyla_kelly18.JPG"/&gt;
&lt;media:content type="" url="http://gallery.usgs.gov/images/05_24_2013/gkb4Erq11X_05_24_2013/large/CoastalEco_KPrzybyla_kelly18.JPG"/&gt;
&lt;/item&gt;
</code></pre>

<h2>Step 2. Opt to Show as a GovBox, in the Sidebar, or Both</h2>

<p>Allow searchers to see inline results for the three most recent, relevant RSS results <em>across all of your RSS feeds</em> by turning on the option to show as a GovBox on the <a href="/sites/manual/display-overview.html">Display Overview</a> page. You can also edit the default title, News, on the Display Overview page.</p>

<p>Allow searchers to see narrow results to a specific feed in the left-hand column of the results page by turning on the option to show in the Sidebar on the <a href="/sites/manual/display-overview.html">Display Overview</a> page. To ensure searchers don't encounter too many dead ends, we recommend showing only feeds with a significant amount of content as a sidebar option.</p>

<h2>Step 3. Check Your Search Results Page</h2>

<p><strong>GovBox.</strong> If you opted to show your RSS feed(s) as a GovBox, searchers will see a News GovBox. This GovBox will highlight the three most recent, relevant results across all of your RSS feeds.</p>

<p><strong>Sidebar.</strong> If you opted to show your RSS feed(s) in the sidebar, searchers can narrow their results to see your RSS-based results only.</p>

<p>Within the RSS-based results, searchers can opt to limit results to the last hour, day, week, month, or year, or they can set a custom date range. They also can sort results in descending order by relevance (best match first) or date (most recent first).</p>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Troubleshooting tip:</em></strong> We support RSS 2.0 and Atom feeds. Learn more and validate your feeds at:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://validator.w3.org/feed">W3C Feed Validation Service</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> (Atom &amp; RSS)</li>
<li>RSS 2.0 <a href="http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification">specification</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> and <a href="http://www.rssboard.org/rss-validator">validator</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /></li>
<li><a href="http://www.atomenabled.org/developers/syndication">Atom syndication format</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /></li>
</ul>


<p><strong><em>Troubleshooting tip:</em></strong> We index the content on your RSS feeds from the time you input them in the <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a>. To backfill historical content, temporarily modify your RSS feeds to return more results. Leave this larger feed in place for one hour. You can do this during off-hours and you don't need to coordinate with us.</p>

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> You can click on the 'Preview' option to see the content we have indexed for each of your RSS feeds.</p>

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> When you <a href="/sites/manual/youtube.html">provide us with your YouTube channel</a>, we'll automatically index the RSS feed for your YouTube channel.</p>

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> For any feeds that you've extended with a contributor, publisher, or subject <a href="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-terms">Dublin Core</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> property, searchers may narrow results by these facets in the <a href="/sites/manual/display-overview.html">sidebar</a> on the results page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create Collections Within Our Index]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/collections.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/collections.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Collections</p>

<p>Would you like searchers to be able to narrow results to a specific subset of content within your site or on another site? You can create a collection across any set of domains, subdomains, or subfolders.</p>

<h2>Step 1. Create a Collection</h2>

<p>Enter a name for the collection (e.g., FAQs).</p>

<p>Enter the URLs that make up this collection. Start each URL prefix with http:// and end it in a trailing slash () to avoid unintended matches (e.g., http://publications.agency.gov/docs/ and http://answers.agency.gov).</p>

<!-- START UPDATE -->


<h2>Step 2. Opt to Show in Sidebar</h2>

<p>Click on the <a href="/sites/manual/display-overview.html">Display Overview</a> page. Check the option, Show in Sidebar, to allow searchers to see navigation options in the left-hand column of the results page.</p>

<!-- END UPDATE -->


<h2>Step 3. Check Your Search Results Page</h2>

<p>Searchers will see an option to narrow their search results to pages in this collection in the left-hand navigation on the results page.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/manual-collection-2.png" alt="Collection on the search results page" /></p>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> You can click on the 'Preview' option to see the content we have indexed for each of your collections.</p>

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> You can set up a search box on your website that limits results to your collection.</p>

<p>Start with the standard form snippet on the <a href="/sites/manual/activate.html">Activate Search</a> page. Change the form action to <code>action="http://search.usa.gov/search/docs</code> and add the following line to limit the results to your collection.</p>

<p><code>&lt;input type="hidden" name="dc" value="###"&gt;</code></p>

<p>The value is the number for your collection ID, which is visible in the URL when you edit your collection in the Admin Center.</p>

<p>See the sample search box below that is limited to news releases in <a href="http://www.ftc.gov/opa/index.shtml">FTC.gov's Newroom</a> for a search on <em>privacy</em>.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/manual-collection-3.png" alt="FTC.gov Newsroom search box" /><br/>
<em>Newsroom page with a search box that is limited to news</em></p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/manual-collection-4.png" alt="FTC.gov search results page" /><br/>
<em>Search results page that returns news results only</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to View a Snapshot of What's Happening on Your Site Today]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/site-overview.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/site-overview.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Dashboard > Site Overview</p>

<p>The Site Overview page in the <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> provides a snapshot of what has been happening on your site in the past day or so.</p>

<h2>Top Queries</h2>

<p>Reports on the top 10 searches done by searchers on your site. If you don't have any searches, you'll see a message that there aren't enough query data available. These typically don't require any action as they don't change much from day-to-day.</p>

<p>Note that the data are processed to present "real" searches by humans (that is, the data are de-duped by IP address to remove bot traffic and other noise).</p>

<h2>Top Clicked URLs</h2>

<p>Reports on the top 10 pages that were clicked thru by searchers on your search results page. If you don't have any clicks, you'll see a message that there aren't enough click data available. These typically don't require any action as they don't change much from day-to-day.</p>

<h2>Trending URLs</h2>

<p>If there are any pages that are trending, they'll appear here. Reports on up to the top 10 changing URLs that were <em>visited by users on your website</em>.</p>

<p>Use this report to identify newly popular pages on your website. Investigate why pages are trending, if the reason is not immediately apparent.</p>

<p>Note that you'll only see this list of trending URLs if you have our <a href="/sites/manual/code.html">Javascript snippet</a> on your web pages. Data are updated every few minutes so this is near real-time information and you may see URLs come and go quickly.</p>

<h2>Trending Queries</h2>

<p>If there are any queries that are trending, they'll appear here. Reports on up to the top 10 changing search terms with the greatest <em>gain</em> between yesterday and today.</p>

<p>Use this report to identify newly popular terms. Create new content or update existing content to ensure it's current, accurate, and complete.</p>

<h2>Queries with No Results</h2>

<p>If there are any terms that returned no results, they'll appear here. Reports on up to the top 10 queries with no results.</p>

<p>For example, on one agency's website in October 2012, a dozen searches for <em>frostline</em> returned no results. The frost line&mdash;also known as depth of frost or freezing&mdash;is the depth to which the groundwater in soil is expected to freeze. The agency's pages on the topic referred to this concept as <em>depth of freezing</em>.</p>

<p>Use this alert about results data to help searchers find your content by adding a <a href="/sites/manual/best-bets-text.html">Best Bet</a>, updating your existing web pages, or both.</p>

<h2>Top Queries with Low Click Thrus</h2>

<p>If there are any frequently searched terms that returned results but didn't result in a click at least 20% of the time, they'll appear here. Reports on up to the top 10 searches with low click thru rates.</p>

<p>Use this alert about low click thrus to identify issues with coverage. You may opt to create a <a href="/sites/manual/best-bets-text.html">Best Bet</a>, add pages that may be missing from the results, or do both to improve recall. Or, you may opt to incorporate language from these popular search terms into your titles and descriptions to improve the relevance of results.</p>

<h2>This Month's Totals to Date</h2>

<p>Reports on the total number of queries and clicks for the present month-to-date. A click  is recorded each time a searcher clicks on a results link.</p>

<p>A graph of your site's total search queries over time is also presented to provide an overview of how your traffic has trended from the time your agency started using USASearch (but no further back than 2010). Hover over the trend line to see the total number of queries in previous months.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Highlight Text Best Bets]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/best-bets-text.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/best-bets-text.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Manage Content > Best Bets: Text</p>

<p>Do you want to promote a specific web page? Create a Text Best Bet.</p>

<p>A Best Bet appears above the standard web results when a searcher's query matches the text of its title, description, or keywords.</p>

<p>Text Best Bets have the same look as standard web results. Up to three relevant best bets are listed under a heading, Recommended by YourSite.</p>

<p>See the sample results page below that shows best bets displayed on TSA.gov for a search on <em><a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?query=razors&amp;affiliate=tsa.gov">razors</a></em>.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/best-bets-text.png" alt="Text best bets for 'razors' on TSA.gov" /></p>

<p>Text Best Bets may be added individually or via bulk upload.</p>

<h2>Add an Individual Best Bet</h2>

<p><strong><em>URL.</em></strong> Add the URL of the web page that you want to promote.</p>

<p><strong><em>Title and Description.</em></strong> Add the title and description of the web page that you want to promote. Each field can have up to 255 characters. Titles and descriptions are visible to searchers.</p>

<p><strong><em>Publish Dates.</em></strong> The default start date is the day in which you input data and create a Best Bet. The default end date is null, so it will stay up forever until you decide to take it down. You can opt to set a start and end date to control to specify other start and end dates.</p>

<p><strong><em>Keywords.</em></strong> Keywords are optional. Add specific words or phrases that are <em>not</em> already included in the visible title or description. Common keywords include synonyms, acronyms, compound words, misspellings, or other variants. Each field can have up to 255 characters. Keywords are <em>not</em> visible to searchers.</p>

<h3>Bulk Upload</h3>

<p>Create a comma-separated file with the following fields.</p>

<p>URL, Title,  Description, StartDate, EndDate, Keywords</p>

<p>URL, title, and description are required. Start date, end date, and keywords are optional. Save the file with .csv, .txt, or .xml extension and upload it.</p>

<!--START UPDATE-->


<p>Bulk upload appends new entries to your existing entries.</p>

<!--END UPDATE-->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Add Your Tweets to Our Index]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/twitter.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/twitter.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Manage Content > Twitter</p>

<p>Provide us with the @handle for your Twitter account(s). Your @handle is your agency's username used within Twitter. When you're logged into Twitter, you can see your username at <a href="https://twitter.com/settings/account">https://twitter.com/settings/account</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" />.</p>

<p>For example, the Twitter username for the USDA's Food Safety and Inspection Service is <a href="https://twitter.com/USDAFoodSafety">@USDAFoodSafety</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" />.</p>

<p>When you add your Twitter @handle, we'll automatically index and display <em>your</em> tweets. Select the option, Show tweets from my lists, to index the tweets for all members of your lists.</p>

<p>If you don't want to display your tweets, simply delete your Twitter handle.</p>

<p>See the sample results page below that shows a recent tweet displayed on SNAP-Ed Connection for a search on <em><a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=snap-edconnection&amp;query=nutrition">nutrition</a></em>.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/social-media-tweets.png" alt="Search result with a tweet on SNAP-Ed Connection" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Add Your Flickr Images to Our Index]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/flickr.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/flickr.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Manage Content > Flickr</p>

<h2>Tell Us About Your Flickr Photostream</h2>

<p>Provide us with the <em>full URL</em> for your Flickr photostream. Most photostreams are in the photos folder (e.g., <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/hudopa">http://www.flickr.com/photos/hudopa</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> for HUD). Some photostreams are in the groups folder (e.g., <a href="http://www.flickr.com/groups/usagov">http://www.flickr.com/groups/usagov</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> for USA.gov).</p>

<p>The URL must be for your overall photostream. You cannot specify individual photos, sets, favorites, or maps.</p>

<!-- START UPDATE -->


<h2>Opt to Display Your Flickr Images</h2>

<p>When you add the URL for your Flickr photostream, we'll automatically index all of the images in your photostream.</p>

<p>On the image results page, we'll automatically backfill the standard image results from your website with the images from your Flickr photostream.</p>

<p>You can also opt to display images GovBox on your main web results page by turning on the option to show as a GovBox on the <a href="/sites/manual/display-overview.html">Display Overview</a> page.</p>

<!-- END UPDATE -->


<p>See the sample results page below that shows photo results displayed on the National Ocean Service for a search on <em><a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?query=humpback+whales&amp;affiliate=oceanservice.noaa.gov">humpback whales</a></em>.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/govbox-photos.png" alt="Results page with photos shown as a GovBox" /></p>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> Do you have a multimedia gallery on your website for your agency's photos, images, videos, podcasts, or other multimedia content? Do you use a content management system, database, or media RSS (MRSS) feed to power this gallery? You can index <a href="/sites/manual/rss.html">MRSS feeds</a> so that your multimedia content is automatically included in your search results.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Manage Your Site's Users]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/users.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/users.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Dashboard > Manage Users</p>

<p>After you've <a href="/sites/manual/add-site.html">signed in and added a site</a> with your official government email, you can add your coworkers to your site.</p>

<p>You can add anyone you'd like to your site&mdash;with or without a .gov or .mil email address.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/user.png" alt="Add a user" /></p>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> We recommend adding a generic email account (such as webteam@agency.gov) as a user to ensure ongoing access to your USASearch account as individuals come and go.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Edit Your Settings]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/settings.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/settings.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Dashboard > Settings</p>

<h2>Display Name (Required)</h2>

<p>Tell us the name of your website. Searchers see your site name on the results page, such as in your page title or best bets. We recommend using the plain language name for your agency or site, such as National Institutes of Health.</p>

<h2>Site Handle (Required)</h2>

<p>We use your site handle in the HTTP request to specify displaying your customized settings. We recommend making this handle short and unique, such as nih.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/settings.png" alt="Site name and handle on NIH.gov's search results page" /></p>

<h2>Site ID (System Generated)</h2>

<p>We assign a unique numeric ID to your site. We use this ID for some back-end code. You also see this ID in the URL for your site in the <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a>.</p>

<h2>Site Language (Required)</h2>

<p>Choose a language for your site, English or Spanish. We will only index and provide results for pages in your selected language. All display text on the results page will also be in your selected language.</p>

<h2>Delete</h2>

<p>After you've set up a site, you may want to delete it. <strong>Use caution.</strong> This action permanently deletes your site and its associated analytics and indexes. We cannot restore deleted sites.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Troubleshooting Tip:</em></strong> If you later need to edit your site handle or language, e-mail us at <a href="&#109;&#97;&#x69;&#x6c;&#116;&#111;&#x3a;&#85;&#x53;&#x41;&#x53;&#101;&#x61;&#114;&#99;&#104;&#64;&#x67;&#115;&#97;&#46;&#x67;&#x6f;&#118;">&#85;&#83;&#x41;&#83;&#101;&#97;&#x72;&#99;&#x68;&#64;&#x67;&#x73;&#97;&#46;&#x67;&#x6f;&#118;</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Preview Your Search Results]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/preview.html"/>
    <updated>2013-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/preview.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> > YourSite > Preview</p>

<p>As you update your site's display settings, you can preview your search results page before pushing the changes to your live website.</p>

<p>Visit our <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a>, select your site, and click on the Preview option (the eye icon) in the left-hand menu.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/preview-nav.png" alt="Select the preview option" /></p>

<p>A preview of your search results page will appear as an overlay in the current window.</p>

<p><strong>View Staged.</strong> This option will allow you to view the staged search results page before you publish it to your live site. You'll see this option if you have staged changes.</p>

<p><strong>View Current.</strong> This option will allow you to view the current, live search results page on your site. This is the only option you'll see if you don't have any staged changes.</p>

<p>You'll also see corresponding options for <strong>View Staged Mobile</strong> and <strong>View Current Mobile</strong> to view your mobile search results page.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/preview-overlay.png" alt="Preview overlay" /></p>

<p>Close the preview overlay by selecting the 'x' option in the upper right-hand corner. You'll return to whichever page you had originally been on in the Admin Center.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Did you know?</em></strong> You can also preview (and share) your search results page by typing http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=<strong>YourSiteHandle</strong> into the address bar in any browser. (Your site handle is listed on the <a href="/sites/manual/settings.html">Settings</a> page in the Admin Center, if you don't know it.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recalls API]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/developer/recalls.html"/>
    <updated>2013-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/developer/recalls.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="/developer/index.html">APIs for Developers</a> > Recalls API</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT"><img style="position: absolute; top: 41px; right: 0; border: 0;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/github/ribbons/forkme_right_orange_ff7600.png" alt="Fork me on GitHub"></a></p>

<p>Helping alert the public to unsafe, hazardous, or defective products.</p>

<ul>
  <li class="overview current"><a href="#overview">Overview</a></li>
  <li class="api"><a href="#using-the-api">Using the API</a></li>
  <li class="parameters"><a href="#parameters">Parameters</a></li>
  <li class="sources"><a href="#data-sources">Data Sources</a></li>
  <li class="returns"><a href="#what-it-returns">What it Returns</a></li>
</ul>


<p><a name="overview"></a></p>

<h2>Overview</h2>

<p>When you're buying and using products, safety comes first.</p>

<p>Six federal regulatory agencies issue recalls on <a href="http://www.recalls.gov">Recalls.gov</a>.</p>

<p>This Recalls API allows you to tap into a list of (1) drug and food safety recalls from the <a href="http://www.fda.gov">Food and Drug Administration</a> (FDA), <a href="http://www.fsis.usda.gov">U.S. Department of Agriculture's Food Safety and Inspection Service</a> (UDSA FSIS), and <a href="http://www.FoodSafety.gov">FoodSafety.gov</a>; (2) car safety recalls from the <a href="http://www.nhtsa.gov">National Highway Traffic Safety Administration</a> (NHTSA); and (3) product safety recalls from the <a href="http://www.cpsc.gov">Consumer Product Safety Commission</a> (CPSC).</p>

<p>This API is great for consumer safety websites or applications, news organizations, and websites or magazines targeted to specific audiences, such as parents.</p>

<p><a name="using-the-api"></a></p>

<h2>Using the API</h2>

<p>This Recalls API accepts a GET request.</p>

<p>Recalls are searchable by keyword, issuing agency, date, UPC code, vehicle-specific attributes, or any combination of these.</p>

<p>The base URL is http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?<strong>parameters</strong></p>

<p>Sample API requests follow.</p>

<p>All recalls<br/>
<a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?</a></p>

<p>All cribs<br/>
<a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?query=cribs">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?query=cribs</a></p>

<p>All cribs that pose a choking hazard<br/>
<a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?query=cribs+choking">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?query=cribs+choking</a></p>

<p>All cribs that pose a choking hazard sorted by date<br/>
<a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?query=cribs+choking&amp;sort=date">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?query=cribs+choking&amp;sort=date</a></p>

<p><a name="parameters"></a></p>

<h2>Parameters</h2>

<p>Seven generic parameters are accepted.</p>

<ol>
<li>query</li>
<li>organization</li>
<li>start_date</li>
<li>end_date</li>
<li>page</li>
<li>per_page</li>
<li>sort</li>
</ol>


<p>There are additional parameters that are specific to food, product, and car safety recalls. None are required.</p>

<h3>query</h3>

<p>Attempts to extract as much "signal" as possible from the input text. Handles word variants, so a search on "choke" will find a recall categorized as a "choking" hazard.</p>

<h3>organization</h3>

<p>Specifies which agency issued the recall. Possible values are <code>CPSC</code>, <code>FDA</code>, <code>NHTSA</code>, or <code>USDA</code>.</p>

<p>Example (one agency): <a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?organization=nhtsa">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?organization=nhtsa</a></p>

<p>Example (multiple agencies): <a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?organization=fda+usda">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?organization=fda+usda</a></p>

<h3>start_date</h3>

<p>Specifies the start date of the recall.</p>

<p>Example: <a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?start_date=2012-01-01">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?start_date=2012-01-01</a></p>

<h3>end_date</h3>

<p>Specifies the end date of the recall.</p>

<p>Example: <a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?end_date=2012-12-31">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?end_date=2012-12-31</a></p>

<h3>page</h3>

<p>Specifies the pagination of search results. Possible values are <code>1</code> to <code>20</code>.</p>

<p>Example: <a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?page=3">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?page=3</a></p>

<h3>per_page</h3>

<p>Specifies the number of search results for each page. Possible values are <code>1</code> to <code>50</code>.</p>

<p>Example: <a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?per_page=10">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?per_page=10</a></p>

<h3>sort</h3>

<p>Results are sorted by relevance by default. Possible values are <code>rel</code> or <code>date</code>. Use 'sort=date' to sort results by date with the most recent listed first.</p>

<p>Example: <a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?sort=date">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?sort=date</a></p>

<h3>food_type</h3>

<p>Only for drug and food safety recalls. Possible values are <code>food</code> or <code>drug</code>.</p>

<p>Example: <a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?food_type=drug">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?food_type=drug</a></p>

<h3>upc</h3>

<p>Only for CPSC recalls. Specifies the UPC code when available. Not all products have UPC codes.</p>

<p>Example: <a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?upc=042666601627">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search.json?upc=042666601627</a></p>

<h3>make, model, year, and code (only for NHTSA recalls)</h3>

<ul>
<li><code>make</code> specifies the make of the vehicle or equipment. Example: <a href="http://localhost:3000/search?make=winnebago">http://localhost:3000/search?make=winnebago</a></li>
<li><code>model</code> specifies the model of the vehicle or equipment. Example: <a href="http://localhost:3000/search?model=ellipse">http://localhost:3000/search?model=ellipse</a></li>
<li><code>year</code> specifies the year of the vehicle or equipment. Example: <a href="http://localhost:3000/search?year=2010">http://localhost:3000/search?year=2010</a></li>
<li><code>code</code> specifies the NHTSA code. Possible values are <code>E</code>, <code>V</code> [for vehicles], <code>I</code>, <code>T</code>, <code>C</code>, or <code>X</code>. Example: <a href="http://localhost:3000/search?code=v">http://localhost:3000/search?code=v</a></li>
</ul>


<p><a name="data-sources"></a></p>

<h2>Data Sources</h2>

<p>We've tailored this Recalls API for our use in the <a href="http://apps.usa.gov/usagov.shtml">USA.gov iPhone app</a> and <a href="http://apps.usa.gov/product-recalls-2.shtml">Product Recalls Android app</a>.</p>

<p>Data are normalized across (1) drug and food safety recalls from the <a href="http://www.fda.gov">FDA</a>, <a href="http://www.fsis.usda.gov">UDSA FSIS</a>, and <a href="http://www.FoodSafety.gov">FoodSafety.gov</a>; (2) car safety recalls from the <a href="http://www.nhtsa.gov">NHTSA</a>; and (3) product safety recalls from the <a href="http://www.cpsc.gov">CPSC</a>.</p>

<p>So, we encourage you to use the five original data sources directly or via <a href="http://www.recalls.gov">Recalls.gov</a>.</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://www.fda.gov/Safety/Recalls/default.htm">FDA recalls, market withdrawals, and safety alerts</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.fsis.usda.gov/wps/portal/fsis/topics/recalls-and-public-health-alerts">USDA FSIS recalls and public health alerts</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.foodsafety.gov/recalls">FoodSafety.gov recalls and alerts</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.nhtsa.gov/Vehicle+Safety/Recalls+&amp;+Defects">NHTSA recalls and defects</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.cpsc.gov/Recalls">CPSC recalls</a></li>
</ol>


<p><a name="what-it-returns"></a></p>

<h2>What it Returns</h2>

<p>Below are three sample JSON responses for food, product, and car safety recalls.</p>

<h3>Food Recalls</h3>

<pre><code>{
    success: {
        total: 82,
        results: [
            {
                organization: "USDA",
                recall_number: "1df0a5440b",
                recall_date: "2011-05-14",
                recall_url: "http://www.fsis.usda.gov/News_&amp;_Events/Recall_037_2011_Release/index.asp",
                description: "Rose &amp; Shore Meat Co., a Vernon, Calif., establishment, is recalling approximately 15,900 pounds of ready-to-eat deli meat products that may be contaminated with Listeria monocytogenes.",
                summary: "California Firm Recalls Deli Meat Products for Possible Listeria Contamination"
            },
            {
                organization: "FDA",
                recall_number: "51d9096a25",
                recall_date: "2010-06-21",
                recall_url: "http://www.fda.gov/Safety/Recalls/ucm216371.htm",
                description: "Portland Shellfish Company, Inc. is expanding this voluntarily recall to include the Meat Without Feet private label food service (2 Lb bags), pack of ready to eat frozen lobster claw and knuckle meat. Lot 13310, as recent tests show the product has the potential to be contaminated with Listeria monocytogenes, an organism which can cause serious and sometimes fatal infections in young children, frail or elderly people, and others with weakened immune systems",
                summary: "Portland Shellfish Company Expands Recall to Include Meat Without Feet Label, Lobster Claw and Knuckle Meat, because of Possible Health Risk"
            }
        ]
}}
</code></pre>

<h3>Product Recalls</h3>

<pre><code>{"success":{
    "total":2,
    "results":[
        {
            "organization":"CPSC",
            "recall_number":"12080",
            "recall_date":"2012-01-05",
            "recall_url":"http://www.cpsc.gov/cpscpub/prerel/prhtml12/12080.html",
            "manufacturers":["Target"],
            "product_types":["Lights &amp; Accessories"],
            "descriptions":["Target 6-pc. LED Flashlight Sets"],
            "upcs":["490021010049"],
            "hazards":["Fire &amp; Fire-Related Burn"],
            "countries":["China"]
        },
        {
            "organization":"CPSC",
            "recall_number":"12710",
            "recall_date":"2012-01-05",
            "recall_url":"http://www.cpsc.gov/cpscpub/prerel/prhtml12/12710.html",
            "manufacturers":["Sterno"],
            "product_types":["Candles &amp; Candle Holders"],
            "descriptions":["Sterno Bulk Pack 5 Hour Tea Lights"],
            "upcs":null,
            "hazards":["Fire &amp; Fire-Related Burn"],
            "countries":["Thailand"]
        }
    ]
}}
</code></pre>

<h3>Car Recalls</h3>

<pre><code>{"success":{
    "total":2,
    "results":[
        {
            "organization":"NHTSA",
            "recall_number":"12V579000",
            "recall_date":"2012-12-18",
            "recall_url":"http://www-odi.nhtsa.dot.gov/recalls/recallresults.cfm?start=1&amp;SearchType=QuickSearch&amp;rcl_ID=12V579000&amp;summary=true&amp;PrintVersion=YES",
            "records":[
                {
                    "component_description":"VISIBILITY/WIPER",
                    "make":"SPARTAN",
                    "manufacturer":"Spartan Chassis, Inc.",
                    "manufacturing_begin_date":"2012-10-01",
                    "manufacturing_end_date":"2012-10-31",
                    "model":"GLADIATOR",
                    "recalled_component_id":"000051813001317776000001349",
                    "year":2012
                },
                {
                    "component_description":"VISIBILITY/WIPER",
                    "make":"SPARTAN",
                    "manufacturer":"Spartan Chassis, Inc.",
                    "manufacturing_begin_date":"2012-10-01",
                    "manufacturing_end_date":"2012-10-31",
                    "model":"METROSTAR",
                    "recalled_component_id":"000051813001317777000001349",
                    "year":2012
                }
            ],
            "manufacturer_campaign_number":"12016",
            "component_description":"VISIBILITY/WIPER",
            "manufacturer":"Spartan Chassis, Inc.",
            "code":"V",
            "potential_units_affected":"36",
            "initiator":"MFR",
            "report_date":"20121210",
            "defect_summary":"Spartan Motors Chassis is recalling certain model year 2012-2013 Gladiator, Metro Star, Metro Star-X, and Force emergency rescue chassis cabs built between October 1, 2012, through October 31, 2012.  The wiper motor shaft and the wiper arm shaft have diff",
            "consequence_summary":"If the windshield wipers become inoperative, the driver could have reduced visibility, which may increase the risk of a crash.  ",
            "corrective_summary":"The remedy for this recall campaign is still under development.  The manufacturer has not yet provided a notification schedule.  Owners may contact Spartan at 1-800-543-5008.",
            "notes":"Spartan's recall campaign number is 12016.Owners may also contact the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration Vehicle Safety Hotline at 1-888-327-4236 (TTY 1-800-424-9153), or go to www.safercar.gov.",
            "recall_subject":"Windshield Wipers may become Inoperative"
        },
        {
            "organization":"NHTSA",
            "recall_number":"12V571000",
            "recall_date":"2012-12-18",
            "recall_url":"http://www-odi.nhtsa.dot.gov/recalls/recallresults.cfm?start=1&amp;SearchType=QuickSearch&amp;rcl_ID=12V571000&amp;summary=true&amp;PrintVersion=YES",
            "records":[
                {
                    "component_description":"FUEL SYSTEM, GASOLINE:DELIVERY:FUEL PUMP",
                    "make":"JAGUAR",
                    "manufacturer":"JAGUAR CARS LTD",
                    "manufacturing_begin_date":"2012-10-03",
                    "manufacturing_end_date":"2012-10-12",
                    "model":"XF",
                    "recalled_component_id":"000051654001723816000000152",
                    "year":2013
                },
                {
                    "component_description":"ELECTRICAL SYSTEM",
                    "make":"JAGUAR",
                    "manufacturer":"JAGUAR CARS LTD",
                    "manufacturing_begin_date":"2012-10-03",
                    "manufacturing_end_date":"2012-10-12",
                    "model":"XF",
                    "recalled_component_id":"000051654001723816000000200",
                    "year":2013
                }
            ],
            "manufacturer_campaign_number":"J028",
            "component_description":"ELECTRICAL SYSTEM",
            "manufacturer":"Jaguar Land Rover North America, LLC",
            "code":"V",
            "potential_units_affected":"13",
            "initiator":"MFR",
            "report_date":"20121207",
            "defect_summary":"Jaguar Land Rover is recalling certain model year 2013 XF vehicles manufactured October 3, 2012, through October 12, 2012 and equipped with a gasoline engine.",
            "consequence_summary":"An engine stall without warning while driving may lead to a loss of motive power, a loss of power-assisted braking and a loss of power-assisted steering.",
            "corrective_summary":"Jaguar Land Rover will notify owners, and dealers will install an additional wiring harness to the in-tank fuel pump, free of charge.",
            "notes":"Jaguar's campaign recall number is J028.Owners may also contact the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration Vehicle Safety Hotline at 1-888-327-4236 (TTY 1-800-424-9153), or go to www.safercar.gov.",
            "recall_subject":"Fuel Starvation may cause Vehicle Stall"
        }
    ]
}}
</code></pre>

<h2>Open Source Code</h2>

<p>The server code that runs this API is on Github. If you're a Rails developer, fork our <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/recalls_api">Recalls Server API</a> repo to add features (such as additional datasets) or fix bugs.</p>

<p>Better yet, send us a <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/recalls_api/pulls">pull request</a> to contribute your changes to our project and improve this API for everyone who is using it.</p>

<h2>Feedback</h2>

<p>E-mail us at <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#105;&#108;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#85;&#x53;&#65;&#83;&#x65;&#x61;&#x72;&#x63;&#x68;&#64;&#103;&#x73;&#97;&#46;&#x67;&#x6f;&#x76;">&#85;&#x53;&#x41;&#83;&#101;&#97;&#x72;&#x63;&#104;&#x40;&#x67;&#x73;&#x61;&#x2e;&#103;&#x6f;&#x76;</a> with any suggestions about what you'd like to see in the next version of API.</p>

<h2>Terms of Use</h2>

<p>By accessing the Recalls API, you agree to <a href="http://www.usa.gov/About/developer-resources/terms-of-service.shtml">USA.gov's Terms of Service for Developer Resources</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jobs API]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/developer/jobs.html"/>
    <updated>2013-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/developer/jobs.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > <a href="/developer/index.html">APIs for Developers</a> > Jobs API</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT"><img style="position: absolute; top: 41px; right: 0; border: 0;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/github/ribbons/forkme_right_orange_ff7600.png" alt="Fork me on GitHub"></a></p>

<p>Helping job seekers land a job with the government.</p>

<ul>
  <li class="overview current"><a href="#overview">Overview</a></li>
  <li class="api"><a href="#using-the-api">Using the API</a></li>
  <li class="parameters"><a href="#parameters">Parameters</a></li>
  <li class="sources"><a href="#data-sources">Data Sources</a></li>
  <li class="returns"><a href="#what-it-returns">What it Returns</a></li>
  <li class="samples"><a href="#code-samples">Code Samples</a></li>
</ul>


<p><a name="overview"></a></p>

<h2>Overview</h2>

<p>The unemployment rate has hovered around 8 percent since early 2012. So, not surprisingly, many people are hitting the web to search for jobs.</p>

<p>Federal, state, and local government agencies are hiring and have thousands of job openings across the country.</p>

<p>This Jobs API allows you to tap into a list of current jobs openings with the government. Jobs are searchable by keyword, location, agency, schedule, or any combination of these.</p>

<p>This API is great for job websites or applications, job banks, and career counseling and placement applications.</p>

<p><a name="using-the-api"></a></p>

<h2>Using the API</h2>

<p>This Jobs API accepts a GET request.</p>

<p>Jobs are searchable by keyword, location, agency, schedule, or any combination of these.</p>

<p>The base URL is http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?<strong>parameters</strong></p>

<p>Sample API requests follow.</p>

<p>All nursing jobs<br/>
<a href="http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=nursing+jobs">http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=nursing+jobs</a></p>

<p>Nursing jobs in NY<br/>
<a href="http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=nursing+jobs+in+ny">http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=nursing+jobs+in+ny</a></p>

<p>Nursing jobs with a state government agency<br/>
<a href="http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=nursing+jobs&amp;tags=state">http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=nursing+jobs&amp;tags=state</a></p>

<p>Nursing jobs with a federal government agency<br/>
<a href="http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=nursing+jobs&amp;tags=federal">http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=nursing+jobs&amp;tags=federal</a></p>

<p>Nursing jobs with Veterans Affairs in NY<br/>
<a href="http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=nursing+jobs+with+veterans+affairs+in+ny">http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=nursing+jobs+with+veterans+affairs+in+ny</a></p>

<p>Part-time nursing jobs with Veterans Affairs in NY<br/>
<a href="http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=parttime+nursing+jobs+with+veterans+affairs+in+ny">http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=parttime+nursing+jobs+with+veterans+affairs+in+ny</a></p>

<p><a name="parameters"></a></p>

<h2>Parameters</h2>

<p>Seven parameters are accepted.</p>

<ol>
<li>query</li>
<li>organization_id</li>
<li>hl (for highlighting)</li>
<li>size</li>
<li>from</li>
<li>tags</li>
<li>lat_lon</li>
</ol>


<h3>Query</h3>

<p>Attempts to extract as much "signal" as possible from the input text. Handles word variants, so a search on "nursing jobs" will find a job titled "nurse practitioner" and "RN." When parts of the query parameter are used to search against the position title, the results are ordered by relevance. When no query parameter is specified, they are ordered by date with the most recent listed first.  For generic jobs searches (e.g., 'jobs', 'internships') where the <strong>lat_lon</strong> parameter is passed in, the results will be sorted by distance to the searcher's geographic location.</p>

<p>Sample query formats follow.</p>

<h4>All jobs (by date or by proximity)</h4>

<ul>
<li>jobs</li>
<li>positions</li>
<li>vacancies</li>
<li>opportunities</li>
<li>postings</li>
</ul>


<h4>Location-based (by date)</h4>

<ul>
<li>jobs in fulton</li>
<li>jobs in fulton, md</li>
<li>jobs in fulton, maryland</li>
<li>jobs in md</li>
<li>pentagon jobs</li>
<li>jobs fayetteville</li>
<li>fayetteville nc jobs</li>
<li>jobs atlanta georgia</li>
</ul>


<h4>Agency-based (by date)</h4>

<ul>
<li>job opportunities at the cia</li>
<li>jobs at the treasury dept</li>
<li>tsa job openings</li>
<li>va jobs # will match jobs in Virginia</li>
</ul>


<h4>Keyword-based (by relevance)</h4>

<ul>
<li>nursing jobs</li>
<li>summer internship position</li>
</ul>


<h4>Schedule-based (by date)</h4>

<ul>
<li>part-time jobs</li>
<li>full-time positions</li>
</ul>


<h4>Combinations (by relevance)</h4>

<ul>
<li>part-time security guard job openings at the tsa in los angeles, ca</li>
</ul>


<h3>Organization_id</h3>

<p>Specifies which federal, state, or local agency to use as a filter.</p>

<p>For federal agencies, the ID is based on <a href="https://schemas.usajobs.gov/Enumerations/AgencySubElement.xml">USAJobs' agency schema</a>. Two letter codes are used to span entire departments, while four letter codes are generally used for independent agencies or agencies within a department.</p>

<p>For state and local agencies, a sample of the format follows.</p>

<p><em>State of Virginia</em><br/>
US-VA</p>

<p><em>State of Virginia Department of Taxation</em><br/>
US-VA:DEPT-TAX</p>

<p><em>Fairfax County, VA</em><br/>
US-VA:COUNTY-FAIRFAX</p>

<p><em>Fairfax County Sheriff</em><br/>
US-VA:COUNTY-FAIRFAX:SHERIFF</p>

<p><em>City of Fairfax, VA</em><br/>
US-VA:COUNTY-FAIRFAX:CITY-FAIRFAX</p>

<p>If you specify an <code>organization_id</code> in your API call but the searcher types in another agency, the searchers' agency overrides the <code>organization_id</code> parameter. For example, VA jobs are returned when you specify Air Force jobs, but the searcher looks for jobs at the VA (<a href="http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=jobs+at+the+va&amp;organization_id=AF">http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=jobs+at+the+va&amp;organization_id=AF</a>).</p>

<h3>Hl [highlighting]</h3>

<p>No highlighting is included by default. Use 'hl=1' to highlight terms in the position title that match terms in the user's search. Highlighted terms are surrounded with <code>&lt;em&gt;</code> tags.</p>

<h3>Size</h3>

<p>Specifies how many results are returned (up to 100 at a time).</p>

<h3>From</h3>

<p>Specifies the starting record.</p>

<h3>Tags</h3>

<p>Specifies the level of government. Current tags are <code>federal</code>, <code>state</code>, <code>county</code>, and <code>city</code>.</p>

<h3>Lat_lon</h3>

<p>Comma-separated pair denoting the position of the searcher looking for a job. For example, 'lat_lon=37.783333,-122.416667' is the value for San Francisco, CA. For generic job searches (e.g., 'jobs', 'internships') where this parameter is passed in, the Jobs API server will sort jobs results and return those that are closest to the searcher's location. For jobs that have multiple locations associated with the position, the distance to the closest location is used to determine the overall geo-distance for the job. Note that for keyword-based job searches (e.g., 'jobs in NY', 'nursing jobs'), this parameter has no effect and is ignored.</p>

<p><a name="data-sources"></a></p>

<h2>Data Sources</h2>

<p>We've tailored this Jobs API for our use in our search results. Data are normalized across government job listings and we don't include all jobs from all data sources. So, we encourage you to use the original data sources directly.</p>

<p>Federal government jobs are from <a href="https://www.usajobs.gov">USAJobs</a>. The USAJobs API for job opportunity announcements is at <a href="https://data.usajobs.gov/Rest">https://data.usajobs.gov/Rest</a>.</p>

<p>State and local government jobs are from cities, counties, and state agencies that use <a href="http://www.neogov.com">NeoGov</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" />, such <a href="https://bouldercolorado.gov/jobs-and-volunteer">jobs with the the city of Boulder, Colorado</a>.</p>

<p><strong><em>Are we missing your jobs data?</em></strong> E-mail us at <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#x69;&#x6c;&#116;&#111;&#x3a;&#85;&#x53;&#65;&#x53;&#x65;&#97;&#x72;&#99;&#104;&#x40;&#x67;&#115;&#97;&#46;&#103;&#111;&#x76;">&#85;&#x53;&#65;&#83;&#x65;&#97;&#114;&#99;&#x68;&#x40;&#103;&#115;&#97;&#x2e;&#103;&#x6f;&#x76;</a> to let us know where you publish the jobs data for your federal, state, or local government agency. We'll accept your jobs data via FTP or any machine-readable format (such as an RSS feed or API).</p>

<p><a name="what-it-returns"></a></p>

<h2>What it Returns</h2>

<p>Below is a sample JSON response for <a href="http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=nursing+jobs+with+veterans+affairs+in+albany+ny">http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?query=nursing+jobs+with+veterans+affairs+in+albany+ny</a>.</p>

<pre><code>[
  {
    id: "usajobs:340537800",
    position_title: "Nursing Assistant Float Pool",
    organization_name: "Veterans Affairs, Veterans Health Administration",
    rate_interval_code: "PA",
    minimum: 31315,
    maximum: 40706,
    start_date: "2013-03-27",
    end_date: "2013-05-31",
    locations: [
        "Albany, NY"
    ],
    url: "https://www.usajobs.gov/GetJob/ViewDetails/340537800"
  },
  {
    id: "usajobs:342782900",
    position_title: "Registered Nurse - Endoscopy",
    organization_name: "Veterans Affairs, Veterans Health Administration",
    rate_interval_code: "PA",
    minimum: 0,
    maximum: 0,
    start_date: "2013-05-02",
    end_date: "2013-05-13",
    locations: [
        "Albany, NY"
    ],
    url: "https://www.usajobs.gov/GetJob/ViewDetails/342782900"
  }
]
</code></pre>

<p><a name="code-samples"></a></p>

<h2>Code Samples</h2>

<p>We "eat our own dog food" and use this Jobs API to display the job openings on the government websites that use USASearch.</p>

<p>See the sample results page below that shows current jobs openings across the Department of Homeland Security for a search on
<em><a href="http://search.dhs.gov/search?query=security+jobs&amp;affiliate=dhs">security jobs</a></em> on DHS.gov.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/dhs-jobs.png" alt="Jobs GovBox on DHS.gov" /></p>

<h2>Open Source Code</h2>

<p>The server code that runs this API is on Github. If you're a Rails developer, fork our
<a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/jobs_api">Jobs Server API</a> repo to add features (such
as additional datasets) or fix bugs.</p>

<p>Better yet, send us a <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/jobs_api/pulls">pull request</a>
to contribute your changes to our project and improve this API for everyone who is using it.</p>

<h2>Feedback</h2>

<p>E-mail us at <a href="&#109;&#97;&#x69;&#x6c;&#116;&#x6f;&#58;&#x55;&#x53;&#x41;&#83;&#x65;&#x61;&#x72;&#x63;&#104;&#x40;&#x67;&#x73;&#97;&#x2e;&#103;&#x6f;&#x76;">&#85;&#x53;&#x41;&#x53;&#101;&#97;&#114;&#99;&#x68;&#x40;&#x67;&#x73;&#97;&#46;&#x67;&#x6f;&#x76;</a> with any suggestions about what you'd like to see in the next version of API.</p>

<h2>Terms of Use</h2>

<p>By accessing the Jobs API, you agree to <a href="http://www.usa.gov/About/developer-resources/terms-of-service.shtml">USA.gov's Terms of Service for Developer Resources</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Customers]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers.html"/>
    <updated>2013-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We have a proven track record of delivering fast, relevant search results. Over 1,500 government websites currently use USASearch to power their search box and improve their visitors' search experience.</p>

<table align="center" width="100%">
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="center" width="25%"><a href="http://usdasearch.usda.gov/search?affiliate=usda&query=jobs"><img alt="Agriculture" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-usda.png" width="100" height="100"></a><br><strong>Agriculture</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center" width="25%"><a href="http://search.commerce.gov/search?affiliate=commerce.gov&query=jobs"><img alt="Commerce" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-commerce.png" width="100" height="100"></a><br><strong>Commerce</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center" width="25%"><a href="http://search.defense.gov/search?affiliate=defense_gov&query=jobs"><img alt="Defense" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-defense.png" width="100" height="100"></a><br><strong>Defense</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center" width="25%"><a href="http://search.dhs.gov/search?affiliate=dhs&query=jobs"><img alt="Homeland Security" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-dhs.png" width="100" height="100"></a><br><strong>Homeland Security</strong></td>
</tr>
</table>




<table align="center" width="100%">
<tr>
<tr><td>&nbsp;</td></tr>
<td valign="top" align="center" width="25%"><a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=housingandurbandevelopment&query=jobs"><img alt="HUD" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-hud.png" width="100" height="100"></a><br><strong>HUD</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center" width="25%"><a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=doi.gov&query=jobs"><img alt="Interior" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-interior.png" width="100" height="100"></a><br><strong>Interior</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center" width="25%"><a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=u.s.departmentoflabor&query=jobs"><img alt="Labor" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-labor.png" width="100" height="100"></a><br><strong>Labor</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center" width="25%"><a href="http://search.treasury.gov/search?affiliate=treasury&query=jobs"><img alt="Treasury" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-treasury.png" width="100" height="100"></a><br><strong>Treasury</strong></td>
</tr>
</table>




<table align="center" width="100%">
<tr><td>&nbsp;</td></tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="center"><a href="http://portal.ehawaii.gov/page/search/?q=jobs"><img alt="Hawaii" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-hawaii.png"></a><br><strong>Hawaii</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center"><a href="http://www.kansas.gov/search/?affiliate=kansas.gov&query=jobs"><img alt="Kansas" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-kansas.png"></a><br><strong>Kansas</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center"><a href="http://kentucky.gov/Pages/search.aspx?terms=jobs&affiliateId=GENERAL"><img alt="Kentucky" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-kentucky.png"></a><br><strong>Kentucky</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center"><a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=www.louisiana.gov&query=jobs"><img alt="Louisiana" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-louisiana.png"></a><br><strong>Louisiana</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center"><a href="http://www.maine.gov/searchme/search?searchquery=jobs"><img alt="Maine" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-maine.png"></a><br><strong>Maine</strong></td>
</tr>
</table>




<table align="center" width="100%">
<tr><td>&nbsp;</td></tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="center"><a href="http://search.michigan.gov/search?affiliate=mi-som&query=jobs"><img alt="Michigan" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-michigan.png"></a><br><strong>Michigan</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center"><a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=nc.gov&query=jobs"><img alt="North Carolina" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-nc.png"></a><br><strong>North Carolina</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center"><a href="http://www.ri.gov/search/?q=jobs"><img alt="Rhode Island" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-ri.png"></a><br><strong>Rhode Island</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center"><a href="http://www.sc.gov/Pages/Search.aspx?q=jobs"><img alt="South Carolina" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-sc.png" height="70"></a><br><strong>South Carolina</strong></td>
<td valign="top" align="center"><a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=accesswashington&query=jobs"><img alt="Washington" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-washington.png" height="70"></a><br><strong>Washington</strong></td>
</tr>
</table>


<h2>Testimonials</h2>

<blockquote><p>We encourage the use of shared services across government agencies and we want to make <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov">WhiteHouse.gov</a> an example for others to follow. It would not be possible to match the value of GSA's free search service by procuring or building a custom solution. Previously, we needed to dedicate significant resources to configuring and tuning our internal solution, whereas with USASearch, we can now deploy these resources to enhance the features of and technology supporting the White House website.</p>

<p><em>&mdash;The White House</em></p></blockquote>

<p>Read more <a href="/tagged/testimonial">testimonials</a> and <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">join them</a> today.</p>

<h2>Our History</h2>

<p>USASearch got its start when Internet entrepreneur Eric Brewer, whose early research was funded by the Department of Defense, offered to donate a powerful search engine to government. That gift helped accelerate the government's earlier work to create a government-wide portal.</p>

<p>In June 2000, President Clinton announced the gift from the Federal Search Foundation, a nonprofit organization established by Brewer, and instructed that an official U.S. web portal be launched within 90 days. USA.gov went online on September 22, 2000 under the name FirstGov.gov with a <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20001109105200/http://www.firstgov.gov">prominent search box</a> to allow the public to search across government websites.</p>

<p>Visit USA.gov to learn more <a href="http://www.usa.gov/About.shtml">about its mission and history</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[With the USASearch tool, we are able to deliver a modernized and customer-centric search experience...]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/usda.html"/>
    <updated>2013-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/usda.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the USASearch tool, we are able to deliver a modernized and customer-centric search experience on <a href="http://www.usda.gov">USDA.gov</a>. The service has provided significant improvements to our site search technology and the ability to leverage open source technology and seamlessly integrate with other existing platforms and USDA social and multi-media channels across the web.</p>

<p>We are able to fully manage the tool and reduce the amount of resources needed to maintain an enterprise-wide search solution across the Department. Our employees and customers expressed immediate satisfaction. We now have the ability to work with our agencies to further the enhancements provided by this technology and to build upon our total web presence.</p>

<p>Bernetta Reese, Web and Project Manager, <a href="http://www.usda.gov">U.S. Department of Agriculture</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spring Cleaning: Notes for the Week Ending June 21, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-06-21.html"/>
    <updated>2013-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-06-21.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We've spent the past few weeks doing some spring cleaning to improve our backend infrastructure and to lay the groundwork for a major update to our Admin Center. Stay tuned!</p>

<h2>Chores</h2>

<ul>
<li>We started using the Rails <a href="http://guides.rubyonrails.org/asset_pipeline.html">asset pipeline</a>. As a result of using the pipeline and some of the other chores below, we decreased the page load time by 25 percent.</li>
<li>We upgraded to <a href="http://www.elasticsearch.org/blog/0-90-1-released/">Elasticsearch 0.90.1</a>.</li>
<li>We upgraded to <a href="http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/news/2013/05/14/ruby-2-0-0-p195-is-released">Ruby 2.0.0</a>.</li>
<li>We updated the way we monitor <a href="http://blog.phusion.nl/category/passenger/phusion-passenger-4">Phusion Passenger</a>.</li>
<li>We removed some unused tables and columns from our MySQL database.</li>
<li>We removed the legacy recalls code from our codebase now that we've released it as a standalone open source <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/recalls_api">Recalls API Server</a>.</li>
<li>We no longer require a valid API key to include API queries in your <a href="/tagged/analytics">site analytics</a>.</li>
<li>We updated our list of synonyms to include fracking and hyrdofracturing as equivalent terms.</li>
<li>The hyperlinks in the Admin Center system alerts are now clickable.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Fixes</h2>

<ul>
<li>We fixed a regression bug with <a href="https://github.com/haml">Haml</a> and Ruby 2.0.0 that made the background color of the search results the same color as the page background.</li>
<li>We fixed the CSS for the magnifying glass on the search box so that it appears properly in IE7.</li>
<li>We now only show unique descriptions for <a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search?organization=cpsc&amp;sort=date">CPSC recalls</a>.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Your Multimedia Galleries: Notes for the Week Ending May 31, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-05-31.html"/>
    <updated>2013-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-05-31.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Highlight: Search Your Multimedia Galleries</h2>

<p>Do you have a multimedia gallery on your website for your agency's photos, images, videos, podcasts, or other multimedia content? Do you use a content management system, database, or media RSS (MRSS) feed to power this gallery?</p>

<p>You can now opt to <a href="/sites/manual/rss.html">index MRSS feeds</a> so that your multimedia content is automatically included in your search results.</p>

<p>MRSS is the standard <a href="http://www.rssboard.org/media-rss">media RSS specification</a> for syndicating multimedia content. So, even if you don't have an MRSS feed now, it should be easy to generate one as long as your content is in a content management system or other database. MRSS is also the standard specification used by hosted multimedia services such as Flickr, Instagram, Vimeo, and YouTube.</p>

<p>Email us at <a href="&#109;&#97;&#x69;&#108;&#x74;&#x6f;&#58;&#x55;&#83;&#x41;&#83;&#101;&#97;&#114;&#x63;&#x68;&#x40;&#103;&#x73;&#x61;&#x2e;&#x67;&#111;&#118;">&#x55;&#83;&#x41;&#x53;&#101;&#x61;&#x72;&#99;&#x68;&#x40;&#103;&#x73;&#97;&#46;&#103;&#111;&#x76;</a> if you have any questions about how to set up an MRSS feed to index your multimedia content.</p>

<p>(Thanks, <a href="http://www.usgs.gov">USGS.gov</a> team, for suggesting this new feature!)</p>

<h2>Other Features</h2>

<ul>
<li>For each result, searchers now see the URL directly under the title. The order is now title-URL-description. It had previously been title-description-URL.</li>
<li>Searchers using screen readers now hear plain language labels for the search box&mdash;Enter your search term (English) and Ingrese su bsqueda (Spanish).</li>
<li>When searchers opt to allow us to use their location, they now see <a href="/sites/manual/govbox-jobs.html">jobs</a> that are geographically closest them.</li>
<li>Mobile searchers now see your site's display name as the alt tag for your mobile logo.</li>
<li>You can now access jobs data in our <a href="/sites/manual/api.html">search API</a> so that, if you use our API, you can display jobs in your search results.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Chores</h2>

<ul>
<li>We updated how we index and store <a href="/sites/manual/rss.html">RSS feeds</a>, including YouTube feeds, so that we index each feed only one time.</li>
<li>We now return a Bad Request message for <a href="/developer/recalls.html">recalls API</a> searches that specify a page greater than 20, which is <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/recalls_api/commit/0539ce559cae7c4f9360f56dba91932bc48ebb4c">outside of the allowed range</a>.</li>
<li>When available, we now <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/recalls_api/commit/74ff28198b2e09418d9d0826fffdcb99bd7fd22f">pull CPSC's URLs</a> for their recalls from their 301 or 302 response headers.</li>
<li>We now filter out federal jobs with more than 20 locations.</li>
<li>We removed the code for our forms feature on <a href="http://www.usa.gov">USA.gov</a> and federal forms API. Follow <a href="https://twitter.com/ProjectMyUSA">@ProjectMyUSA</a> to see how the MyUSA team is working to improve the public's experience with federal forms.</li>
<li>We removed the code that created a separate mobile version of USA.gov. Visit  <a href="http://www.USA.gov">http://www.USA.gov</a> to see its new, responsive design.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Fixes</h2>

<ul>
<li>We fixed the pagination in our <a href="/sites/manual/api.html">search API</a> so that the API now consistently returns 10 results (1-10, 11-20, 21-30, etc).</li>
<li>We tweaked the Spanish translations for the <a href="/sites/manual/govbox-jobs.html">jobs GovBox</a>.</li>
<li>We fixed the link for the advanced search operators on the <a href="http://search.usa.gov/search/advanced?affiliate=gobiernousa">Spanish-language advanced search page</a> to point to the corresponding Spanish-language help.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Your Twitter Lists: Notes for the Week Ending May 10, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-05-10.html"/>
    <updated>2013-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-05-10.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Highlight: Search Your Twitter Lists</h2>

<p>Does your agency have dozens of Twitter accounts? Do you have a public Twitter list for these accounts? You can now opt to <a href="/sites/manual/twitter.html">index tweets</a> from your lists. You can either:</p>

<ul>
<li>Show tweets from your Twitter account only (for example, index and show tweets from <a href="https://twitter.com/USDA">@USDA</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> only)</li>
<li>Show tweets from your account's public lists (for example, index and show tweets from the all members of @USDA's list, <a href="https://twitter.com/USDA/lists/usda-twitter-accounts">USDA Twitter accounts</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" />).</li>
</ul>


<p>(Thanks, <a href="http://www.nih.gov">NIH.gov</a> team, for suggesting this new feature!)</p>

<h2>Other Features</h2>

<ul>
<li>Searchers on Spanish-language websites now see the <a href="/sites/manual/govbox-jobs.html">Jobs GovBox</a> when they search on jobs-related terms. For example, a Jobs GovBox appears on GobiernoUSA.gov for a search on <a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=gobiernousa&amp;query=trabajos"><em>trabajos</em></a>.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Chores</h2>

<ul>
<li>We updated the cron script for our monthly analytics emails.</li>
<li>We updated our stemming file.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Fixes</h2>

<ul>
<li>We now correctly identify the Food and Drug Administration or Food Safety and Inspection Service as the data sources in our <a href="/developer/recalls.html">Recalls API</a>.</li>
<li>We fixed how we handle registered trademarks in the <a href="/developer/recalls.html">Recalls API</a> so that searchers can now find items such as Zicam&reg;.</li>
<li>We now provide a better response when an API call specifies the 'doc' index but doesn't include the required, complementary 'dc' parameter.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Find State and Local Jobs: Search Notes for the Week Ending May 3, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-05-03.html"/>
    <updated>2013-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-05-03.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Highlight: Find State and Local Jobs</h2>

<p>Searchers on many state and local websites can now see current job openings. We're automatically indexing and displaying job openings for all of your websites that use <a href="http://www.neogov.com">NeoGov</a>.</p>

<p>See the sample results page below that shows current job openings displayed on the City of Bloomington, MN, for a search on <a href="http://search.ci.bloomington.mn.us/search?affiliate=cityofbloomingtonmnsearchresults&amp;query=jobs">jobs</a>.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/jobs-bloomington.png" alt="Search results for jobs on ci.bloomington.mn.us" /></p>

<p>(Thanks, City of Bloomington, for helping us pilot test this new feature!)</p>

<h2>Other Features</h2>

<ul>
<li>Searchers now see search results for <a href="/sites/manual/collections.html">collections</a> that are in deeply nested folders on your site.</li>
<li>Searchers no longer see deep site links for the first-listed search result.</li>
<li>Developers can now access <a href="http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?tags=state">state</a> and <a href="http://api.usa.gov/jobs/search.json?tags=city+county">local</a> jobs data via our <a href="/developer/jobs.html">Jobs API</a> for government agencies that use both USASearch and NeoGov.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Chores</h2>

<ul>
<li>We updated our <a href="/tos.html">terms of service</a>.</li>
<li>We updated the links in the header of our Admin Center and search results page to match our new website.</li>
<li>We removed the option to exclude specific domains from the Admin Center. Read our tip on <a href="/sites/manual/domains.html">how to exclude content</a> or email us at <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#x6c;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#85;&#83;&#65;&#83;&#101;&#x61;&#114;&#x63;&#104;&#64;&#103;&#115;&#97;&#x2e;&#103;&#x6f;&#118;">&#x55;&#x53;&#x41;&#83;&#101;&#x61;&#x72;&#99;&#x68;&#x40;&#x67;&#115;&#x61;&#46;&#103;&#111;&#118;</a> with any questions.</li>
<li>We removed outdated, unused code that allowed you to embed the search results page within an iFrame.</li>
<li>We removed code that allowed you to set keywords to limit the scope of the search results (which had previously been a workaround to allow searchers to see your deeply nested content).</li>
<li>We removed the trending searches feature and widget.</li>
<li>We updated our <a href="http://jenkins-ci.org">Jenkins</a> build to fix to failing <a href="http://cukes.info">Cucumber</a> specs.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Fixes</h2>

<ul>
<li>We're now tracking impressions on <a href="/sites/manual/best-bets-graphics.html">graphics Best Bets</a>.</li>
<li>We now accept Flickr and RSS feeds even if there are invalid items without a description, date, or other required field.</li>
<li>The advanced search link no longer propagates unnecessary parameters in the URL.</li>
<li>We removed trailing spaces from Twitter handles to prevent broken links in the <a href="/sites/manual/twitter.html">Twitter GovBox</a>.</li>
<li>We now accept Flickr handles with an '@' sign in them.</li>
<li>Searchers now see better results when they do a search from the <a href="http://search.usa.gov/search/advanced?affiliate=usagov">advanced search page</a> with multiple terms in the 'Any of these words' and 'None of these words' fields.</li>
<li>Searchers now see results for terms like full-time and part-time. The hyphens had previously been treated as the NOT Boolean operator.</li>
<li>Searchers no longer see the <a href="/sites/manual/govbox-jobs.html">Jobs GovBox</a> for advanced searches when it isn't relevant.</li>
<li>We fixed a bug so that, if a site parameter is specified, it overrides the scopeid parameter.</li>
<li>We added some additional logic to the code that redirects visitors from search.usa.gov to USA.gov's homepage.</li>
<li>We fixed a few regression bugs for related searches and the naming of the 'unescapedUrl' and 'publishedAt' fields in our <a href="/sites/manual/api.html">Search API</a>.</li>
<li>We now display search results only for pages that specify a URL.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Help Searchers Find Jobs]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/govbox-jobs.html"/>
    <updated>2013-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/govbox-jobs.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the most common search tasks is to look for current job openings. To help searchers quickly find relevant jobs we've created the Jobs GovBox.</p>

<p>When you <a href="/sites/manual/display-overview.html">turn on the Jobs GovBox</a>, searchers looking for jobs on your site will see up to three relevant jobs listings on your results page.</p>

<h2>Federal Government</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Federal Cross-Agency Portals.</strong> If your website is a federal cross-agency portal (e.g., USA.gov), the Jobs GovBox will return relevant, location- and keyword-matched job openings <em>across all federal agencies</em>.</li>
<li><strong>Federal Department Websites.</strong> If your website is affiliated with a specific federal department (e.g., Department of Commerce), the Jobs GovBox will return relevant, location- and keyword-matched job openings <em>across all agencies within your department</em>.</li>
<li><strong>Federal Agency or Office Websites.</strong> If your website is affiliated with a specific federal agency (e.g., NOAA) or office (e.g, National Ocean Service), the Jobs GovBox will return relevant, location-and keyword-matched job openings <em>at your agency</em>.</li>
</ul>


<p>Searchers will also see a direct link to <a href="https://www.usajobs.gov">USAJobs.gov</a> for all current job openings (specific to your department or agency, if applicable), as shown in the sample below for a search on <a href="http://usdasearch.usda.gov/search?affiliate=usda&amp;query=jobs" title=""><em>jobs</em></a> on the USDA.gov.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/govbox-jobs.png" alt="Search results for jobs on USDA.gov" /></p>

<h2>State and Local Government</h2>

<p>If your website is a state or local government site that uses both USASearch and NeoGov (e.g., Michigan.gov), the Jobs GovBox will return relevant, location- and keyword-matched job openings <em>across your agency</em>.</p>

<p>Searchers will also see a direct link to your NeoGov page for all current job openings specific to your agency, as shown in the sample below for a search on <em><a href="http://search.ci.bloomington.mn.us/search?affiliate=cityofbloomingtonmnsearchresults&amp;query=jobs">jobs</a></em> on the City of Bloomington, MN.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/jobs-bloomington.png" alt="Search results for jobs on ci.bloomington.mn.us" /></p>

<p>Otherwise, the Jobs GovBox will return relevant, location- and keyword-matched job openings <em>across all federal, state, and local agencies</em>.</p>

<hr />

<p> <strong>Did you know?</strong> Are you a federal agency that doesn't post your jobs on USAJobs? Or a local or state government that doesn't use NeoGov? We want your jobs data. E-mail us at <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#105;&#108;&#x74;&#111;&#x3a;&#x55;&#x53;&#x41;&#x53;&#x65;&#x61;&#114;&#x63;&#104;&#x40;&#x67;&#115;&#97;&#46;&#x67;&#111;&#118;">&#x55;&#x53;&#65;&#83;&#101;&#97;&#x72;&#99;&#104;&#x40;&#103;&#115;&#x61;&#x2e;&#x67;&#111;&#118;</a> to let us know where you publish your job openings so that we can include them in the Jobs GovBox.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Checklist for a Successful Website Redesign]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/redesign.html"/>
    <updated>2013-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/redesign.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We often receive questions when an affiliate undergoes a major website upgrade, changes content management systems, or both. We created this checklist to share with you four steps to take to ensure your redesign is successful.</p>

<ol>
<li>Keep the file name and directly structure the same, if possible. If it isn't possible, use 301 redirects to send visitors to the appropriate new pages. For more on 301 redirects, read tips from <a href="http://www.bing.com/blogs/site_blogs/b/webmaster/archive/2011/10/06/managing-redirects-301s-302s-and-canonicals.aspx">Bing</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> and <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/93633">Google</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" />. Notify other websites that link to you of the changes.</li>
<li>Register for the commercial search engines' webmaster tools.

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.bing.com/toolbox/webmaster">Bing Webmaster Tools</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /></li>
<li><a href="https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/">Google Webmaster Tools</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Update the <a href="http://www.sitemaps.org">XML sitemap</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" /> on your website and notify the search engines via the webmaster tools.</li>
<li>Notify the search engines of the content that has been removed via the webmaster tools. Specifically, in Bing, use the <a href="http://www.bing.com/blogs/site_blogs/b/webmaster/archive/2013/03/15/bing-wmt-launches-site-move-tool.aspx">Site Move tool</a> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" />.</li>
</ol>


<p>If you've undergone a redesign, followed these four steps, and you still don't see your content updated in your site search results, please notify us at <a href="&#109;&#97;&#x69;&#108;&#116;&#111;&#x3a;&#x55;&#x53;&#x41;&#83;&#x65;&#x61;&#x72;&#x63;&#104;&#64;&#x67;&#x73;&#97;&#46;&#x67;&#111;&#x76;">&#85;&#x53;&#x41;&#x53;&#x65;&#97;&#x72;&#x63;&#104;&#64;&#103;&#115;&#97;&#x2e;&#x67;&#x6f;&#118;</a>.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong><em>Additional Resource</em></strong></p>

<ul>
<li><em><a href="http://googlewebmastercentral.blogspot.com/2012/04/how-to-move-your-content-to-new.html">How to move your content to a new location</a></em> <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/external_link.gif" alt="External link" />, Google Webmaster Central Blog</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Help Searchers Find Information for Federal Agencies]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/govbox-agencies.html"/>
    <updated>2013-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/govbox-agencies.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Searches for government agencies are very common. So we created the Agency GovBox to help you provide searchers with easy-to-find, authoritative contact information for federal agencies.</p>

<p>The federal Agency GovBox includes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Phone numbers;</li>
<li>Links to social media accounts; and</li>
<li>A box to search the agency's website.</li>
</ul>


<p>If you <a href="/sites/manual/display-overview.html">opt to show the Agency GovBox</a>, searchers looking for federal agencies on your site can readily find high-quality information, as shown in the sample below for a search on <a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=doi.gov&amp;query=nps"><em>nps</em></a> on <a href="http://www.doi.gov">DOI.gov</a>.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/govbox-agency.png" alt="Agency GovBox for IRS on USA.gov's search results page" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Terms of Service]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/tos.html"/>
    <updated>2013-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/tos.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following terms of service ("Terms") govern the General Services Administration's (GSA) USASearch Program website and services, including the content, documentation, code and related materials, are offered subject to your acceptance of the Terms as well as any relevant sections of the HowTo.gov <a href="http://www.howto.gov/site-policies">Site Policies</a> (collectively, the "Agreement"). Access to or use of USASearch services or its content constitutes acceptance to this Agreement.</p>

<h2>Data Collection and Use</h2>

<h3>Data Collection</h3>

<ul>
<li>We don't collect any personally-identifiable information nor use persistent cookies.</li>
<li>When you use USASearch, we store information about searches on your site, including: the web page from which searchers accessed your search results, the date and time, the words searched for, items clicked on a page, and the browser and operating system used. We periodically delete our search logs.</li>
<li>We use this information to measure the usage of our website and services and to identify system performance or problem areas. We also use this information to help us develop the service, analyze patterns of usage, and to make the service more useful. This information is not used for associating search terms or patterns of site navigation with individual users. We may anonymize and provide this information to third-party entities for the purposes of analyzing search traffic.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Secondary Use</h3>

<ul>
<li>Customers using our Search Data API cannot cache results.</li>
<li>Data accessed through our website and services does not, and should not, include controls over its end use.</li>
<li>Once the data has been downloaded from USASearch, we can't vouch for the quality or timeliness of any analyses conducted with data retrieved.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Citing Data</h2>

<p>Customers using the Search Data API must display the <a href="http://download.microsoft.com/download/0/4/E/04E076D4-60B2-4D31-BCC7-C4805B558DBB/Bing%20product%20guidelines.pdf">Web Results by Bing</a> [PDF] logo on 'web' and 'image' search results pages for attribution of web results. Customers using any of the other three indexes ('docs', 'news', and 'videonews') must display the USASearch logo for attribution instead of the Bing logo.</p>

<h2>Source Code</h2>

<h3>Use of Open Source Software</h3>

<p>USASearch uses open-source software and free or low cost, commercial application programming interfaces when it best meets the needs and mission of GSA.</p>

<h3>Redistribution of Code</h3>

<ol>
<li>Software source code written entirely by GSA staff, and by contractors who are developing software on behalf of GSA, is by default a public domain work.</li>
<li>Software source code previously released under an open source license and then modified by GSA staff is considered a "joint work." It is partially copyrighted, partially public domain, and as a whole is protected by the copyrights of the non-government authors and must be released according to the terms of the original open-source license.</li>
<li><p>All source code as defined above may be shared with the general public via a highly visible, easily accessible online source code community (such as Github) that facilitates the code's reuse. Source code won't be released if any of the following conditions are met:</p></li>
<li><p>The author of the code determines that the code is too crude to merit distribution or provide value to the broader community.</p></li>
<li>The Government doesn't have the rights to reproduce and release the item. The Government has public release rights when the software is developed by Government personnel, when the Government receives "unlimited rights" in software developed by a contractor at Government expense, or when pre-existing OSS is modified by or for the Government.</li>
<li>The public release of the item is restricted by other law or regulation, such as the Export Administration Regulations or the International Traffic in Arms Regulation.</li>
<li>GSA cybersecurity staff determine that the public release of such code would pose an unacceptable risk to GSA's operational security.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Modification or False Representation of Content</h2>

<p>You may not modify or falsely represent content accessed through USASearch yet still claim the source is USASearch.</p>

<h2>Right to Limit</h2>

<p>Users of the website and services must have a valid government email address from a federal, state, local, tribal, or territorial government agency. If GSA reasonably believes that you are not a government employee, or a contractor acting within the scope of its government contract, GSA may temporarily or permanently block your use of the website and services.</p>

<p>Use of the APIs may be subject to certain limitations on access, calls, or use as set forth within this Agreement or otherwise provided by GSA. If GSA reasonably believes that you have attempted to exceed or circumvent these limits, your ability to use the API may be permanently or temporarily blocked.</p>

<p>GSA may monitor your use of its services to improve the service or to insure compliance with this Agreement.</p>

<h2>Service Termination</h2>

<p>If you wish to terminate this Agreement, you may do so by refraining from further use of the website and services. GSA reserves the right (though not the obligation) to (1) refuse to provide the services to you if it is GSA's opinion that use violates any GSA policy, or (2) terminate or deny you access to and use of all or part of the services at any time for any other reason in its sole discretion. Any hosted applications may also be shut down or removed. All provisions of this Agreement which by their nature should survive termination shall survive termination including, without limitation, warranty disclaimers, indemnity, and limitations of liability.</p>

<h2>Changes</h2>

<p>GSA reserves the right, at its sole discretion, to modify or replace this Agreement, in whole or in part. Your continued use of or access to the USASearch services following posting of any changes to this Agreement constitutes acceptance of those modified terms. GSA may, in the future, offer new services and/or features. Such new features and/or services shall be subject to the terms and conditions of this Agreement.</p>

<h2>Disclaimer of Warranties</h2>

<p>USASearch services are provided "as is" and on an "as-available" basis. GSA hereby disclaims all warranties of any kind, express or implied, including without limitation the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, and non-infringement. GSA makes no warranty that the services will be error free or that access thereto will be continuous or uninterrupted.</p>

<h2>Limitations on Liability</h2>

<p>In no event will GSA be liable with respect to any subject matter of this Agreement under any contract, negligence, strict liability or other legal or equitable theory for: (1) any special, incidental, or consequential damages; (2) the cost of procurement of substitute products or services; or (3) for interruption of use or loss or corruption of data.</p>

<h2>General Representations</h2>

<p>You hereby warrant that (1) your use of the website and services will be in strict accordance with the Agreement and all applicable laws and regulations, and (2) your use of the website and services will not infringe or misappropriate the intellectual property rights of any third party.</p>

<h2>Miscellaneous</h2>

<p>This Agreement constitutes the entire Agreement between GSA and you concerning the use of the website and services, and may only be modified by the posting of a revised version on this page by GSA.</p>

<h2>Disputes</h2>

<p>Any disputes arising out of this Agreement and access to or use of the services shall be governed by federal law.</p>

<h2>No Waiver of Rights</h2>

<p>GSA's failure to exercise or enforce any right or provision of this Agreement shall not constitute waiver of such right or provision.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Open Source Strategy]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/open-source.html"/>
    <updated>2013-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/open-source.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We keep an eye on on our what our government counterparts are up to, both in the U.S. and other countries. We recently came across <a href="https://www.gov.uk">Gov.UK's</a> philosophy on and approach to <a href="http://digital.cabinetoffice.gov.uk/2012/10/12/coding-in-the-open">coding in the open</a>. It caught our attention and we realized we should also articulate our open source strategy.</p>

<h2>Use and Contribute to Open Source Projects</h2>

<p>Since 2010, we've embraced and leveraged open source software to build our site search service for federal, state, and local government websites. This use of open source has allowed us to experience enormous growth over the past few years. In March 2013 alone, over 24 million searchers received results from our service&mdash;a four-fold increase since March 2010.</p>

<p>Our search service is now a complex system made up of many moving parts, including providing type-ahead search suggestions, serving search results, fetching, indexing, and caching content, and providing analytics.</p>

<p>Each of these parts is compiled into our USASearch codebase and, as we use open source components for our system, we contribute back to the projects.</p>

<h2>Code in the Open</h2>

<p>We recently began to unravel our monolithic codebase so that we can share individual pieces of our code. To borrow the phrase from Gov.UK, we're now <strong><em>coding in the open</em></strong>.</p>

<p>We recently released the code for our <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/jobs_api">Jobs</a> and <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/recalls_api">Recalls</a> API servers. They're our first foray into coding in the open. The source code for these API servers is in <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT">our GitHub repo</a> and is available for anyone to see and contribute to.</p>

<p>The data products for this code are also open and available for anyone to consume on our <a href="/developer/index.html">USASearch.HowTo.gov/Developer</a> hub.</p>

<p>These two servers and their underlying data now operate outside of our core search codebase.</p>

<p>Following this same model, moving forward, we plan to:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Share first&mdash;For every new feature, we'll write the code so that <em>anyone</em> can make use of the code, not just us. If the public community contributes to the codebase, we'll be able to improve this feature without taxing our developers.</p></li>
<li><p>Expose APIs&mdash;We'll expose our data products as APIs so that <em>anyone</em> can make use of the data, not just searchers on a government websites.</p></li>
<li><p>Be our own customer&mdash;We'll use our own public code and data just like everyone else. We'll call our own API servers to integrate the data within our search results pages.</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Make Things Open to Make Things Better</h2>

<p>We agree with Gov.UK that "to make things open makes things better."</p>

<p>We have finite resources and we don't want to lose our focus on serving our agency customers and improving visitors' search experience on government websites. So, we won't be spending a lot of time to build or support a vibrant community around our code.</p>

<p>That said, we hope that exposing the pieces of our system will be useful to someone somewhere. We'll continue to provide the "ingredients" of our search service so that others will be able to make use of the code and data in ways that we could never imagine.</p>

<h2>And, We're Not Alone</h2>

<p>We're not alone. Other federal agencies have embraced the approach of coding in the open and have <a href="http://gsa.github.io/federal-open-source-repos">GitHub repos</a>. Below are a just a few of our many favorites.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The Consumer Finance Protection Bureau has embraced open source, including serving their public data sets through <a href="https://github.com/cfpb/qu">qu</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>USA.gov recently released the code for their <a href="https://github.com/usagov/usagov-ios-app">iPhone app</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>The White House was in the forefront of using open source software in the federal government with their use of Drupal. They're continuing to lead by example by opening up the code for their <a href="https://github.com/WhiteHouse/petitions">We the People petitions</a> and <a href="https://github.com/WhiteHouse/wh-app-ios">iOS</a> and <a href="https://github.com/WhiteHouse/wh-app-android">Android</a> mobile apps.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show Your Footer: Search Notes for the Week Ending April 5, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-04-05.html"/>
    <updated>2013-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-04-05.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Highlight: Show Your Footer</h2>

<p>Do you have information in the footer of your results page that searchers need to see? Searchers can now view or hide the footer while on your search results page.</p>

<p>After clicking on the Show Footer icon located at the bottom right-hand corner of the search results page, searchers will see the footer.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/footer-1.png" alt="Show/hide footer icon" /></p>

<p>They'll still be able to scroll infinitely through the search results while the footer is visible. To hide the footer, they can click on the icon again.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/footer-2.png" alt="Results page with a visible footer icon" /></p>

<h2>Chores</h2>

<ul>
<li>We automated the syncing of our geolocation data.</li>
<li>We published instructions for the <a href="/developer/jobs.html">Jobs API</a>.</li>
<li>We migrated our website platform from Tumblr to <a href="http://pages.github.com">GitHub Pages</a>.</li>
<li>We set up a cron job to regenerate tagged pages after commits for our website.</li>
<li>We published an RSS feed for our website.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Fixes</h2>

<ul>
<li>Searchers see a tool tip for the icon that toggles the display of the header and footer.</li>
<li>Searchers no longer see an unescaped HTML tags.</li>
<li>We <a href="https://github.com/rails/rails/pull/4911">reduced the file name maximum size</a> in our ActiveSupport FileStore cache.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[USASearch]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/index.html"/>
    <updated>2013-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/index.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="banner">
  <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">
    <img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/get-started.jpg" class="img-polaroid" alt="Get started with USASearch" />
  </a>
</div>




<div class="row">
<div class="span6">
  <h2><i class="icon-flag"></i>&nbsp;Recent Release Notes</h2>


<ul>
<li><a href="/releases/2013-06-21.html">Spring Cleaning: Notes for the Week Ending June 21, 2013</a></li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="/releases/2013-05-31.html">Search Your Multimedia Galleries: Notes for the Week Ending May 31, 2013</a></li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="/releases/2013-05-10.html">Search Your Twitter Lists: Notes for the Week Ending May 10, 2013</a></li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="/releases/2013-05-03.html">Find State and Local Jobs: Search Notes for the Week Ending May 3, 2013</a></li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><a href="/releases/2013-04-05.html">Show Your Footer: Search Notes for the Week Ending April 5, 2013</a></li>
</ul>


<strong><a href="/tagged/releases/">All release notes</a> ></strong>
</div>
  <div class="span6">
  <h2><i class="icon-question-sign"></i>&nbsp;How Do I...</h2>
    <ul>
     <li><a href="/sites/manual/account.html">Sign up for an account?</a></li>
     <li><a href="/blog/go-live.html">Go live with USASearch?</a></li>
     <li><a href="/blog/redesign.html">Prepare for a redesign, move to a new CMS, or both?</a></li>
    </ul>
    <strong><a href="/tagged/how-to/">All how to tips</a> ></strong>
  </div>
  
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[APIs for Developers]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/developer/index.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/developer/index.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a> > APIs for Developers</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT"><img style="position: absolute; top: 41px; right: 0; border: 0;" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/github/ribbons/forkme_right_orange_ff7600.png" alt="Fork me on GitHub"></a></p>

<p>Data underpins everything we do to provide a great search experience on government websites.
In line with the White House's
<a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/omb/egov/digital-government/digital-government.html">Digital Government Strategy</a>, we're making our data open through APIs.</p>

<p>USASearch.HowTo.gov/Developer connects you&mdash;software developers, researchers, and our
government customers&mdash;with the tools you need to unlock the government data that
underpins our hosted search service.</p>

<h2>For the Public</h2>

<p><strong><a href="jobs.html">Jobs</a></strong>&mdash;This API returns job openings across federal, state, and local government agencies.</p>

<p><strong><a href="recalls.html">Recalls</a></strong>&mdash;This API returns food, car, and product safety data and recalls.</p>

<p>Visit <a href="http://www.usa.gov/About/developer-resources/developers.shtml">USA.gov/Developer</a> for a full list of USA.gov's APIs and data feeds available to the public.</p>

<h2>For Government Customers</h2>

<p><strong><a href="/sites/manual/api.html">Search Results</a></strong>&mdash;Provides USASearch customers their search results in XML, JSON, or
JSON-P. This API is only available for use on official government websites.
<a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Sign in</a> is required.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending March 8, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-03-08.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-03-08.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Highlighted Feature: Limiting Results to a Subset of Your Content</h2>

<p>Do you want to set up a search box (or even hundreds of search boxes) over a subset of your content?</p>

<p>You can set up a <a href="/sites/manual/collections.html">Collection</a>. Or, you can now pass in a 'sitelimit' parameter to filter the results to specific folders or domains.</p>

<h3>Option 1. Set Up a Collection</h3>

<p>See the sample results page on <a href="http://www.nih.gov">NIH.gov</a> that shows results for a search on <a href="http://search.nih.gov/search/docs?affiliate=nih&amp;dc=565&amp;query=cancer"><em>cancer</em></a> in NIH.gov's New Releases.</p>

<p>Note that the searcher sees that results are filtered to News in the left-hand menu.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/nih-collection.png" alt="Collection-based search results for cancer in NIH.gov news releases" /></p>

<h3>Option 2. Use the Sitelimit Parameter</h3>

<p>Compare the collection-based results above with the results for <a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=nih&amp;query=cancer&amp;sitelimit=nih.gov/news">the same search using the sitelimit parameter</a>.</p>

<p>Note that the searcher sees that results are filtered to nih.gov/news in a message under the search box, among other differences.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/nih-sitelimit.png" alt="Sitelimit-based search results for cancer in NIH.gov news releases" /></p>

<h2>Other Feature</h2>

<ul>
<li>Searchers' see job openings in their state <em>before</em> the listings for jobs in other states.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Chores</h2>

<ul>
<li>We added sequester/sequestration as an entry in our synonym file so that searchers looking for information on the topic find all relevant results.</li>
<li>We throttled the YouTube RSSFeedFetcher to avoid HTTP 403 errors.</li>
<li>We added some compound indexes to speed up queries.</li>
<li>We added JSONP support for the <a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/developer/jobs.html">Jobs API</a> and <a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/developer/recalls.html">Recalls API</a>.</li>
<li>We investigated additional sources for jobs openings, such as the Department of Labor's <a href="http://developer.dol.gov/DOL-SUMMERJOBS-SERVICE.htm">Summer Jobs</a> and the National Resource Directory's <a href="https://www.nrd.gov/home/api/veterans_job_search">Veterans Jobs Bank</a>.</li>
<li>We moved the publishing platform for <a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch.HowTo.gov</a> from Tumblr to <a href="http://pages.github.com">Github pages</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Fixes</h2>

<ul>
<li>Visitors to eForms.gov, FedForms.gov, and Forms.gov are now automatically redirected to the USA.gov's list of <a href="http://www.usa.gov/Topics/Reference-Shelf/forms.shtml">government forms by agency</a>.</li>
<li>We tuned the redirect on search.usa.gov/images so that all needed images show up on results pages.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending February 22, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-02-22.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-02-22.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Features</h2>

<ul>
<li>Searchers now see the most current titles and descriptions available for <a href="/sites/manual/youtube.html">YouTube videos</a> and they won't see any deleted videos.</li>
<li>Visitors to the pages search.usa.gov and buscador.usa.gov are now automatically redirected to <a href="http://www.usa.gov">USA.gov</a> and <a href="http://www.usa.gov/gobiernousa">GobiernoUSA.gov</a>, respectively, so they see the most recent content on these homepages.</li>
<li>Spanish searchers now see <a href="http://www.plainlanguage.gov">plain language</a> helper text.</li>
<li>Searchers no longer see two search boxes on the search results page, which will create a more visually appealing and usable page.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Chores</h2>

<ul>
<li>We rewrote some query routing rules for job searches to present more precise results in the <a href="/sites/manual/govbox-jobs.html">Jobs GovBox</a>.</li>
<li>We configured <a href="https://travis-ci.org">Travis-CI</a> to enable continuous integration for the <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/recalls_api">Recalls Server API</a> and <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/jobs_api">Jobs Server API</a>.</li>
<li>We shortened the Jobs API base URL to <a href="http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search">http://api.usa.gov/recalls/search</a>.</li>
<li>We reconfigured our RSS feed fetching to update more efficiently.</li>
<li>We upgraded to <a href="http://weblog.rubyonrails.org/2013/2/11/SEC-ANN-Rails-3-2-12-3-1-11-and-2-3-17-have-been-released">Rails 3.2.12</a> and <a href="http://rubygems.org/gems/rack">Rack</a> 1.4.5.</li>
<li>We upgraded our <a href="http://www.cloudera.com/content/cloudera/en/products/cdh.html">Cloudera Distribution for Hadoop</a> (CDH) cluster.</li>
<li>We removed the outdated yellow call out boxes from the <a href="https://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Fixes</h2>

<ul>
<li>You'll no longer see an error message if you delete a site that has a YouTube profile or when adding a site that has no managed RSS feed.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending February 8, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-02-08.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-02-08.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Highlighted Feature</h2>


<p>You can now access your raw HTTP logs. These logs contain valuable data on searches, clicks and USASearch tag page loads.</p>


<p>Read<a href="/sites/manual/raw-logs.html">How to Access Your Raw Logs</a> for more details about how to request secure FTP access to your logs.</p>


<h2>Other Features</h2>


<ul><li>We open sourced all of the code that powers our <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/recalls_api">Recalls Server API</a> in Github.</li>
<li>Searchers are now able to search and see results from collections that are not visible in the left-hand navigation on your "main" web results. You can use this option to provide a search box on a small subset of content (such as a policy manual or meeting minutes) while not cluttering up the left-hand navigation on your main results page. (It also helps reduce the likelihood that searchers experience a "dead end" on your main results page.)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Chores</h2>


<ul><li><span>We upgraded to <a href="http://www.centos.org/">CentOS</a> 6.3.</span></li>
<li>We optimized the routing of search queries so that they're served by the geographically closest datacenter.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending February 1, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-02-01.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-02-01.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Highlighted Feature</h2>

<p>The display of search results pages is constantly evolving. Some changes are subtle. Others are more noticeable.</p>

<p>In line with industry best practices and commercial search engines, we've moved the tools for filtering and sorting results to the top of results list (rather than on the left side). We've also added an option to clear all filters.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/search-tools.png" alt="Tools for filtering and sorting" /></p>

<h2>Chores</h2>

<ul>
<li>We upgraded to <a href="%22http://weblog.rubyonrails.org/2013/1/8/Rails-3-2-11-3-1-10-3-0-19-and-2-3-15-have-been-released">Rails 3.2.11</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Fixes</h2>

<ul>
<li>Searchers no longer see Did You Mean suggestions for your excluded domains.</li>
<li>We fixed a cross browser compatibility issue on the Query Logs page in the Admin Center so that the number of clicks' column is now visible.</li>
<li>We labeled the Safe Search radio options on our <a href="http://search.usa.gov/search/advanced?affiliate=govbenefits">advanced search page</a> as a fieldset to improve accessibility for screen readers.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending January 25, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-01-25.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-01-25.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Highlighted Feature</h2>


<p>This week we buckled down and analyzed data on jobs-related searches to ensure that the newfederal<a href="/sites/manual/govbox-jobs.html">Jobs GovBox</a>lists the<span>most relevant</span><span>job openings.</span></p>


<p>Searchers can now effectively search for jobs by keyword, agency, state, or work schedule (part-or full-time).</p>


<p>We also focused on not showing the Jobs GovBox when it isn't relevant (for example, it is no longer shown when searchers look for job safety posters or employment verification forms).</p>


<h2>Chores</h2>


<ul><li><span>We added our posting channel ID to all USAJobs links.</span></li>
<li><span>We set up a cron job to fetch and process job files from USAJobs.</span></li>
<li><span>We added impression and click tracking for the Jobs GovBox module.</span></li>
<li><span>We resolved performance discrepancy between our<a href="/releases/2012-10-19.html">two datacenters</a>.</span></li>
<li><span>We no longer use XML sitemaps to add documents to the USASearch web index.</span></li>
</ul>


<h2>Fixes</h2>


<ul><li><span>You can now delete keywords from text best bets.</span></li>
<li><span>Newly added misspellings are now being applied to type-ahead suggestions.</span></li>
<li><span><span>Searchers can now find jobs in non-standard state locations (for example someone searching for jobs in Washington, DC, will find postings the the location ofWashington DC Metro Area, District of Columbia)</span><span>.</span></span></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending January 11, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-01-11.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-01-11.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Highlighted Feature: The Jobs GovBox</h2>

<p>We're excited to announce that searchers looking for jobs on your site can now see all of your agency's current job openings.</p>

<p>Our new <a href="/sites/manual/govbox-jobs.html">Jobs Govbox</a> displays up to three location- and keyword-matched job openings on your results page. For more information on how to turn on this GovBox, see <a href="/sites/manual/display-overview.html">How To Select The Modules That Appear On Your Results Page</a>.</p>

<p>We've also open sourced all of the code that powers our <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/jobs_api">Jobs Server API</a> in Github.</p>

<h2>Fixes</h2>

<p>And, we've already pushed two bug fixes for the Jobs GovBox to production. Searchers no longer see yet-to-be-opened or already closed jobs.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for the Week Ending January 4, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-01-04.html"/>
    <updated>2013-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2013-01-04.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Highlighted Feature</h2>


<p>Are you curious about the most searched for terms on your site in the past year? They'll arrive in your inbox in our new,<span>annual</span><span></span><span>Year-in-Review email.</span></p>


<p>We'll send you an email every December 15 (along with cheer and goodwill) with a list of the top 1,000 terms searched for on your site over the past year and how many times each term was searched.</p>


<h2>Other Features</h2>


<ul><li><span>Developers using our <a href="https://github.com/GSA-OCSIT/jobs_api">jobs API</a>can find agency-specific jobs by searching for an agency's name, abbreviation, or other variant.</span></li>
</ul>


<h2>Chores</h2>


<ul><li>We upgraded to <a href="http://weblog.rubyonrails.org/2013/1/2/Rails-3-2-10--3-1-9--and-3-0-18-have-been-released/">Rails 3.2.10</a>.</li>
<li>We sped up our interaction with the <a href="http://www.bing.com/developers/">Bing Search API</a>.</li>
<li>We set up an automatic download of current jobs opening from <a href="https://schemas.usajobs.gov/">USAJobs' jobs export</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Fixes</h2>


<ul><li><span>Searchers and API users are now able to maintain a HTTP connection for multiple requests resulting in shorter response times.</span></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending December 14, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-12-14.html"/>
    <updated>2012-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-12-14.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Highlighted Feature</h2>


<p>Did you know that mobile search traffic increases during the holidays?</p>


<p>You can now customize the header on your mobile search results page to create a more seamless experience for visitors to your mobile website.Our new feature allows you to upload your mobile logo and specify a mobile homepage URL.</p>


<p>USASearch &gt; Admin Center &gt; YourSite &gt; Header and Footer</p>


<h2>Other Features</h2>


<ul><li>Searchers see Bing image results followed by results from your <a href="/sites/manual/flickr.html">Flickr</a> photostream. (Example: search for images about <em>hurricane sandy</em>on<a href="http://search.usa.gov/search/images?affiliate=u.s.departmentoflabor&amp;m=false&amp;query=hurricane+sandy">DOL.gov</a>.)</li>
<li>Searchers can now sort RSS-based results (such as press releases, blogs, etc.) by date or relevance.</li>
<li>Searchers now only see tweets from up to three months ago.</li>
<li>Searchers now only see articles from up to one year ago in the News GovBox.</li>
<li>You can now exclude specific subdomains or folders from your search results on the Excluded Domains page in the Admin Center.</li>
<li>You can now segment the keywords for your text <a href="/sites/manual/best-bets-text.html">Best Bets</a>.</li>
<li>You now see your domains listed in A-Z order on the <a href="/sites/manual/domains.html">Domains</a> page in the Admin Center.</li>
<li>You now see your requested <a href="/sites/manual/third-party.html">3rd Party Tracking</a> scripts in the Admin Center.</li>
<li>You can now access collection results via our <a href="/sites/manual/api.html">API</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Chores</h2>


<ul><li>We refined the rules of our fetcher to index only HTML pages with the <a href="/sites/manual/code.html">USASearch Javascript tag</a> and any PDF or Microsoft Office documents linked from the tagged HTML page.</li>
<li>We automatically remove the repetitive @ if you include it as part of your <a href="/sites/manual/twitter.html">Twitter handle</a>.</li>
<li>We automatically resize your mobile header image if it is too big.</li>
<li>We updated our Linux <a href="http://www.kernel.org/">kernels</a>, <a href="http://jenkins-ci.org/">Jenkins</a>, <a href="http://newrelic.com/">New Relic</a>, and lots of <a href="http://rubygems.org/">RubyGems</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Fixes</h2>


<ul><li>Searchers can now set a custom date range even if type-ahead search is disabled on your results page.</li>
<li>Searchers no longer see inactive best bets as recommended pages in the type-ahead search.</li>
<li>Images no longer overlap on image search results pages.</li>
<li>We now show both queries and clicks in the analytics reports for customers with really long site handles.</li>
<li>We fixed a bug with how we recorded clicks for searches with apostrophes.</li>
<li>We show you an error message when you try to upload an improperly encoded URL via the URLs &amp; Sitemaps page in the Admin Center.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending November 16, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-11-16.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-11-16.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Highlighted Feature</h2>


<p>Searchers often know the exact page they're looking for. We've added a feature to help them find that page even more quickly.</p>


<p>As searchers type in their query, relevant text<a href="/sites/manual/best-bets-text.html">Best Bets</a>are shown as Recommended Pages, as shown in the sample below for a search on <em>fa&#8230;</em> on<a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?query=jobs&amp;affiliate=u.s.departmentoflabor">DOL.gov</a>.</p>


<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_mdljlrljT71qid15q.png"/></p>


<h2>Other Features</h2>


<ul><li>Searchers can narrow RSS news results by custom date ranges.</li>
<li>Searchers now see more images above the fold on image results pages.</li>
<li>Searchers see integrated image results across both the images on your website and in your Flickr photostream.</li>
<li>You can now add the<a href="http://www.howto.gov/web-content/digital-metrics/digital-analytics-program">Digtital Analytics Program</a>'s government-wide analytics tag to your search results pages. Email the Digital Analytics Program at <a href="mailto:DAP@gsa.gov">DAP@gsa.gov</a> for more information on setting up the government-wide analytics tag.</li>
<li>When you <a href="/sites/manual/twitter.html">add your Twitter handle</a> in the Admin Center, we now show the Twitter GovBox by default.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Chores</h2>


<ul><li>We upgraded the <a href="https://rubygems.org/gems/tweetstream">tweetstream</a> and <a href="https://rubygems.org/gems/twitter">twitter</a> gems.</li>
<li>We upgraded <a href="http://jenkins-ci.org/">Jenkins</a>.</li>
<li>We upgraded to <a href="http://blog.cloudera.com/blog/2012/10/cdh4-1-now-released/">Cloudera 4.1</a> and installed <a href="https://ccp.cloudera.com/display/IMPALA10BETADOC/Cloudera+Impala+1.0+Beta+Documentation">Impala</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Fixes</h2>


<ul><li>We fixed the URLs within your tweets so that searchers can now click on the links.</li>
<li>We fixed a bug so that infinite scroll now works on news and image results pages.</li>
<li>We now index your<span>ISO-8859-1 encoded pages.</span></li>
<li>We now always show your no results section on the Query Logs page in the Admin Center.</li>
<li><span>We fixed some bugs with how the ends of the day and month were calculated so that the data displayed in our reports is consistent.</span></li>
<li>We fixed a bug so that the query timeline chart now displays in all browsers.</li>
<li>Wesyncedthe Query Logs and Click Stats reports so that you now see today's data for both.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending November 2, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-11-02.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-11-02.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Highlighted Feature: Common Search Metrics for the Digital Strategy</em></p>


<p>Do you ever feel like you're drowning in data? Do you feel like finding meaningful insights from the data is like searching for a needle in a haystack?</p>


<p>To standardize and streamline how agencies collect and report this data, the <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/omb/egov/digital-government/digital-government.html">Digital Government Strategy</a> requires federal executive branch agencies to implement common performance and customer satisfaction metrics.<a href="http://www.howto.gov">HowTo.gov</a> has published <a href="http://www.howto.gov/web-content/digital-metrics">guidance on common metrics</a>, including describing what you should measure, what to do with the data, and common tools to help you collect and analyze your metrics.</p>


<p>To support you in collecting and reporting your site <a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/tagged/analytics">search metrics</a> for the Digital Government Strategy, we've added four new reports to the [Admin Center](https://search.usa.gov/sites).</p>


<h2>1. Top "no results" queries</h2>


<p>The most popular, valid searches that don't return any results on your site's search results page (e.g., because you don't have the content on your site, or the content isn't findable by the person's search term).<span class="Apple-tab-span"> </span>Review your content to see if you need to add new content, or update existing content to include the words your readers search for.</p>


<h2>2. Top searches with low click through rates</h2>


<p>The most popular search terms that people generally don't act (click) on. Consider incorporating language from these popular search terms into page titles or descriptions, to encourage searchers to click on your relevant page.</p>


<h2>3. Top changing search terms (movement up/down)</h2>


<p>Shows trending topics, what's hot or not. Use this report to investigate why people might be losing interest in once-popular content and consider archiving if it's no longer needed. For newly popular terms, create new content or update existing content to ensure it's current, accurate, and complete. </p>


<h2>4. Top clicked URLs for specific queries</h2>


<p>The most common results that searchers found most relevant or appealing, for specific search terms.Review these popular pages and other customer top tasks to make sure they are current, accurate, complete and compelling.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending October 19, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-10-19.html"/>
    <updated>2012-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-10-19.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Good news! We completed a major upgrade of our search infrastructure.You likely didn't notice as we completed the upgrade without any downtime for searchers on your site.</p>


<p>Our system is now even more secure, stable, and redundant than it was before. Plus, it is faster, too.Highlights of the upgrade follow.</p>


<p><em><strong>Multihoming</strong></em></p>


<p>We've always had adisasterrecovery, backup datacenter, but it often sat idle. We wanted to make better use of all of our servers so we're now leveraging a content delivery network to send traffic to whichever datacenter is geographically closest to the searcher. This allows us to use both datacenters equally and serve our results quickly.</p>


<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_mcd7tbK8RD1qid15q.png"/></p>


<p><em><strong>New Hardware</strong></em></p>


<p>We increased our RAM and CPU resources by five times. We have room to grow and to roll out more features.</p>


<p><em><strong>Upgraded Software</strong></em></p>


<p>We're now on Red Hat 6 and Cloudera 4.</p>


<p><em><strong>Speed, Speed, Speed</strong></em></p>


<p>We're always working to improve the speed of our search results. We changed some of our caching rules. We also started to leverage<a href="http://wiki.nginx.org/Main">Nginx</a>(a free, open-source, high-performance HTTP server).</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending October 12, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-10-12.html"/>
    <updated>2012-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-10-12.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<ul><li><span>We added alerts to the Admin Center to communicatemaintenancewindows or other timely content with you.</span></li>
<li>Searchers can see keyword-scoped results for collections. If you have a collectionbelow three folder levels deep, <a href="mailto:usasearch@gsa.gov">email us</a> and we'll help you set up a keyword for your collection.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Chores</strong></p>


<ul><li>We removed the Hosted Sitemap feature.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>We nowshow dates for RSS news items on each customer's search results page only.</li>
<li>We fixed a bug which caused highlighted terms on results pages to omit trailing spaces.</li>
<li>We fixed a bug on how "site:" operators retrieve results.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending September 28, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-09-28.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-09-28.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>Highlighted Feature: Infinite Scrolling</strong></em></p>


<p>Searchers now have the benefit of infinite scrolling on your results pages. What isinfinite scrolling?You've probably used it on many commercial websites, such as<a href="http://www.bing.com/images/search?q=yosemite">Bing Images</a>, <a href="http://duckduckgo.com/?q=yosemite">Duck Duck Go</a>, <a href="http://pinterest.com/search/boards/?q=yosemite">Pinterest</a>, and <a href="https://twitter.com/i/#!/search/yosemite">Twitter</a>. It automatically allows searchers to see more results when they get to the bottom of the page, without clicking on the link for the next page of results.</p>


<p>Try it out on your site's search results page, or on <a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=usagov&amp;query=yosemite">USA.gov</a>.</p>


<p><a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=usagov&amp;query=yosemite"><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_mb2awk8xwU1qid15q.png"/></a></p>


<p>Infinite scrolling has many advantages, including:</p>


<ol><li><em><em>Speed.</em><span></span></em>The next set of new results loads quicker than a totally new page.</li>
<li><em>Streamlining the user interface.</em> Studies show most searchers don't use the next page buttons. Proactively loading results allowssearchers to see more results on one page and to compare them.</li>
<li><em>Simplifying the indexes.</em> When and how we display results from our various web indexes is easier for us, you, and end users.</li>
</ol>


<p><em><strong>Other Features</strong></em></p>


<p>We completely revamped how<a href="/sites/manual/collections.html">collections</a>work to provide you with more flexibility. We encourage you to check out this feature if you're interested in offering navigation options in the left-handsidebaron your results page. You can now create a collection:</p>


<ul><li>Covering tens of thousands (or even millions) of web pages.</li>
<li>Coveringdomains that aren't part of your primary <a href="/sites/manual/domains.html">domain</a> (i.e., that aren't shown on the mainweb resultspage).</li>
<li>Without needing to add our Javascript<a href="/sites/manual/code.html">code snippet</a>.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending September 21, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-09-21.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-09-21.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Helping searchers find forms</em></p>


<p>Similar to our existing<a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?query=census+bureau&amp;affiliate=usagov">agency</a> and <a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=usagov&amp;query=diabetes">health</a>GovBoxes, we created a <a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?affiliate=usagov&amp;query=i9+form">forms</a> GovBox to help searchers find federal government forms. So far, we've included forms from the Department of Defense, General Services Administration, Social Security Administration, U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, and Department of Veterans Affairs.</p>


<p>We've also published the forms data as a <a href="http://www.usa.gov/About/developer-resources/forms.shtml">Federal Forms API</a> for third-party developers.</p>


<p><strong>Chores</strong></p>


<ul><li>We upgraded our robots.txt parser to account for comments and varying cases.</li>
<li>We eliminated support for six <a href="/blog/legacy-domains.html">legacy domains</a> as part of the .gov web reform project.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>We fixed broken URLs for Best Bets image files.</li>
<li>We fixed a bug with our browser user agent so that Internet Explorer users no longer sometimes see a blank results page.</li>
<li>We fixed a CSS validation bug so you don't see an error message when editing your header or footer.</li>
<li>We updated a broken link for Explore Topics on m.USA.gov.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Six legacy domains are expiring]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/legacy-domains.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/legacy-domains.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of the federal <a href="http://www.usa.gov/WebReform.shtml">.gov web reform</a> project, we're eliminating six of our legacy domains. Going forward, our only supported domain is search.usa.gov (or search.yoursite.gov, if you've requested <a href="/sites/manual/cname.html">DNS masking</a>).
What do you need to do? If your URL starts with any of the following six legacy domains, you must update your HTML form code.</p>

<ol>
<li>firstgovsearch.gov</li>
<li>searchusa.gov</li>
<li>usasearch.gov</li>
<li>(Spanish) buscador.gov</li>
<li>(Spanish) buscadorusa.gov</li>
<li>(Spanish) usabuscador.gov</li>
</ol>


<p>Specifically, you have to update the action of your <a href="/sites/manual/code.html">form code</a> to call search.usa.gov (or search.yoursite.gov).</p>

<p><code>&lt;form method="get" action="http://search.usa.gov/search"&gt;</code></p>

<p>Note that, if you don't update your form code, your search results page will no longer work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending August 17, 2012 ]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-08-22.html"/>
    <updated>2012-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-08-22.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="post_title"><strong>Features</strong></div>


<p><em>Coming soon! Forms GovBox</em></p>


<p>Similar to our existing <a href="/sites/manual/govbox-agencies.html">agency</a> and <a href="/sites/manual/govbox-health.html">health</a> GovBoxes, we're currently working on rolling out a forms GovBox to help searchers find federal government forms.</p>


<p>If you have forms metadata in a structured format, and want to have your visitors see them in search results, please send us an email at <a href="mailto:usasearch@gsa.gov" title="usasearch@gsa.gov">usasearch@gsa.gov</a>.</p>


<p><strong>Chores</strong></p>


<ul><li>We upgraded to <a href="http://weblog.rubyonrails.org/2012/8/9/ann-rails-3-2-8-has-been-released/">Rails 3.2.8</a>.</li>
<li>We upgraded to Ruby 1.9.3.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>We fixed broken URLs for YouTube thumbnails.</li>
<li>We fixed an invalid byte sequence in UTF-8.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending August 10, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-08-10.html"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-08-10.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Highlight: More Faceted Navigation Options</em></p>


<p><span>Searchers can now narrow their results by up to three additional facets</span>contributor, publisher, or subject. To start using this feature, simply update any of your <a href="/sites/manual/rss.html">RSS feeds</a> to include these Dublin Core properties.</p>


<p><em>Other features</em></p>


<ul><li><span>Searchers are able to show and hide options (e.g., the time filter) from the sidebar on the results page.</span></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Chores</strong></p>


<ul><li>We investigated additionaltools to monitor our application and the speed of our results.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>We fixed the z-index so that type-ahead suggestions always appear on top of other page elements. We also updated the CSS for our type-ahead to ensure it doesn't conflict with your CSS.</li>
<li>We fixed our recalls API to return the expected response and to handle null values for recalled_on.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending August 3, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-08-03.html"/>
    <updated>2012-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-08-03.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Highlight: Drupal 7 module now available</em></p>


<p>If you're using Drupal, be sure to check out our updated <a href="https://drupal.org/project/USASearch">Drupal module</a>. It includes a new development branch for version 6 and and a release for version 7. Thanks, <a href="http://drupal.org/user/457434">Tim Wood</a>at the Department of Commerce!</p>


<p><em>Other features</em></p>


<ul><li>You can now add only one <a href="/sites/manual/code.html">Javascript snippet</a> to your web pages (versus two separate snippets).</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Chores</strong></p>


<ul><li>We updated the <a href="/sites/manual/govbox-health.html">health GovBox</a> to account for changes in the MedlinePlus <a href="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/xml.html">XML files</a>.</li>
<li>We investigated features and functionality of <a href="https://developers.google.com/bigquery/">Google BigQuery</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>We fixed the alt text on our Results by &#8230; images.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Weeks of Chores: Search Notes for the Week Ending July 27, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-07-27.html"/>
    <updated>2012-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-07-27.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal"><span>It's hard to believe August is already here. Over the past three weeks, we finished a long list of summer chores and we're happy to have a clear deck to offer you more features in the coming months.</span></p>


<p class="MsoNormal"><span></span>We upgraded our environment to <a href="http://weblog.rubyonrails.org/2012/1/20/rails-3-2-0-faster-dev-mode-routing-explain-queries-tagged-logger-store/">Rails 3.2</a>. This upgrade ensures continued stability and allows us to maintain our record of exceeding our service level agreements.</p>


<p class="MsoNormal">We also changed our back-end logic for indexing your content. We now index secure (https) content. We also now allow you to give instructions to the 'usasearch' user agent in your <a href="http://www.robotstxt.org/robotstxt.html">robots.txt</a> file.</p>


<p>Don't forget to check out your July search statsin your email inbox or via the [Admin Center](https://search.usa.gov/sites).</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[USASearch improved the quality of NC.gov's search...]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/nc.html"/>
    <updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/nc.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>USASearch improved the quality of NC.gov's search results 1000-fold. Results are relevant, helpful, and reliable. Setting up the site search is easy, and the instructions for including the search box on a website are clear and easyincluding search that must cross many domains. Customer service is superb. I would recommend USASearch to any government agency.</p>

<p>Lois Nilsen, Web Content Manager, <a href="http://www.nc.gov">NC.gov</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search Notes for the Week Ending July 6, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-07-06.html"/>
    <updated>2012-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-07-06.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We hope you had a good Fourth of July!</p>


<p>One of your most frequently asked questions is, "What's your roadmap?" We decided to use the halfway point of the year to expand our release notes to include notes on our upcoming features.</p>


<p><strong>Last Week's New Features</strong></p>


<p>We're now displaying Twitter results inthe third rail. Searchers like Twitter results because they often contain your latest information. The third rail increases the visibility of your tweets and it allows searchers to see both Twitter and YouTube results above the fold in the browser.</p>


<p>See the sample results page below that shows social media results on Commerce.gov for a search on<em><a href="http://search.commerce.gov/search?query=innovation&amp;affiliate=commerce.gov">innovation</a></em>.</p>


<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_m71vk4FInR1qid15q.jpg"/></p>


<p><strong>Other Features</strong></p>


<ul><li>You may now enter multiple handles if you have more than one social media account for Flickr, Twitter, or YouTube.</li>
<li>Mobile searchers can see image results.</li>
<li>You may now see whether we've indexed your Twitter or Flickr content.</li>
<li>We now index Microsoft Office documents (Excel, Word, and PowerPoint).</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>We now label Office documents.</li>
<li>We fixed an issue with Flickr indexing.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Coming Up in July</strong></p>


<p>We "celebrated" during the Fourth of July holiday by focusing on some general housekeeping to ensure stability for the rest of the year. We'll release new features to index secure (https) content. We'll also update our USASearch Tag to power both type-ahead and fetching (eliminating the need for you to have put two sets of USASearch javascript on your web pages).</p>


<p><strong>Coming Up Next Quarter</strong></p>


<p>We divide our roadmap into four categories, and we complete one major feature in each category per quarter.</p>


<p><em>1. Customer Services.</em>We plan to improve and facilitate our signup process. We're going to automatically populate more content when you add a site so it is easier for you to take advantage of new features. We also plan to create a dashboard to allow you to see what has changed within your search configuration.</p>


<p><em>2. Content Sources.</em>You've requested more control to divide search results into content sources, topics, etc. We plan to offer more flexibility to allow you to divide your content as it makes sense for your searchers.</p>


<p><em>3. Core Search.</em>One good (or bad) aspect about search is that there is always more work to do in terms of relevancy, speed, scaling, etc. We plan to focus on tuning these aspects,especiallyfor our newer content sources.</p>


<p><em>4. Search Analytics.</em>We have a growing amount of data, and we want to expose more of it to you. In parallel with providing you just a dashboard in the Admin Center, we plan to proactively notify you of any potential issues.</p>


<p>We hope that this glimpse into our recently released features and our short- and long-term roadmap helps you understand what we're working on and what's coming down the road.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for the Week Ending June 29, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-06-29.html"/>
    <updated>2012-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-06-29.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Highlight: searchers see recent tweets when they search on your website</em></p>


<p>If you have a Twitter account, tell us the name of your profile and searchers will be able to find relevant, recent tweets when they search on your website.</p>


<ol><li>Log in to the [Admin Center](https://search.usa.gov/sites). Select your site.</li>
<li>Click on the Social Media option. Enter the name of your Twitter account and click save.</li>
<li>Click on the Results Modules option and opt to show your tweets in a GovBox.</li>
</ol>


<p>Wait until you post your next tweet. Then, go to your website and do a search for a word or phrase in the tweet. You'll see it as a GovBox intermingled with your web results.</p>


<p><em>Other features</em></p>


<ul><li>Customers with lots of documents will have them indexed more quickly.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>Address memory bloat.</li>
<li>Searchers can no longer see multiple sidebar items selected.</li>
<li>Launch jumpstart index for newly added sites with a single site domain.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for the Week Ending June 22, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-06-22.html"/>
    <updated>2012-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-06-22.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><div><strong>Feature</strong><em><br/><br/>Highlight: Flickr image search</em><br/><br/>We've found that those of you who have a Flickr photostream have higher quality image results from your photostream than from your web pages. So, if you've told us about your Flickr account, it now powers the default image search on your results page. We also now index the tags for your photostream to improve retrieval and relevance of your images.<strong><br/><br/>Chore</strong></div>
<ul><li><span>Limit PDF file size to 50&#160;MB.</span></li>
</ul></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for the Week Ending June 15, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-06-15.html"/>
    <updated>2012-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-06-15.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Highlight: improved PDF parser</em></p>


<p>We have good news for those of you with lots of PDF files. We've upgraded our PDF parser to <a href="http://tika.apache.org/">Apache Tika</a> to improve our ability to index complex, non-standard PDFs.</p>


<p><em>Other features<br/></em></p>


<ul><li>Customers may input third party tracking (e.g., Google Analytics, WebTrends, Omniture, etc.) via a request form.</li>
<li>Customers may upload up to 10,000 URLs via the bulk upload option on the URLs and Sitemaps page.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>Fixed memory bloat associated with log file processing.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for the Week Ending June 8, 2012  ]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-06-08.html"/>
    <updated>2012-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-06-08.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Highlight: Flickr integration</em></p>


<p>Do you have a Flickr photostream? Tell us the name of your photostream. Within minutes, searchers will be able to find relevant images from your Flickr photostream when they search on your website.</p>


<ul><li>Searchers see shorter snippets for RSS-based web snippets.</li>
<li>Searchers see a more concise statement regarding the number of results found.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>Support relative paths for favicons when adding a new site.</li>
<li>Set "{query} - {site} resultados de la bsqueda" as the default page title for Spanish-language sites.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for the Week Ending June 1, 2012  ]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-06-01.html"/>
    <updated>2012-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-06-01.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Highlight: Customers Receive a Monthly Analytics Report</em></p>


<p>Now it is easier than ever for you to glean insight from your search logs on what visitors are searching for&#8212;in their own words&#8212;on your site. On the first of each month, we'll now email you an analytics report. Hopefully, you already received one on June 1.</p>


<p><em>Other Features</em></p>


<ul><li>Searchers see improved titles and descriptions for web results that match RSS news items.</li>
<li>Searchers have faster load times on results pages with large CSS in their header or footer.</li>
<li>Customers see a new error message when there is malformed HTML in their header or footer.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for the Week Ending May 25, 2012  ]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-05-25.html"/>
    <updated>2012-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-05-25.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Highlight: Autopopulate content sources</em></p>


<p>When you add a new site, we'll proactively index contentthat we find on your home page, including RSS feeds, favicons, andsocial media handles. This will streamline the process of adding a site and make it easier than ever to leverage our features.</p>


<ul><li>Searchers see a magnifying glass icon for the search button.</li>
<li>Searchers don't see "Everything" in the sidebar when it is the only option.</li>
<li>Searchers don't see redundant information in the description snippets.</li>
<li>Searchers see only recently discovered URLs in the new URLs GovBox.</li>
<li>Customers can opt to display the new URLs GovBox on the Results Modules page in the Admin Center.</li>
<li>Customers see their site ID on the Site Information page.</li>
<li>Customers can see what content is indexed for their feeds from the RSS page.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>Searchers see up to 20 videos per page when searching for more videos from the GovBox.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for the Week Ending May 18, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-05-18.html"/>
    <updated>2012-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-05-18.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Highlight: Monthly Analytics Email</em></p>


<p>Beginning on June 1, you won't have to log in to see your search analytics.We'll deliver a report directly to your inbox each month. Plus, it will be easier to share the data with your colleagues.</p>


<ul><li>Searchers see video results from YouTube playlists.</li>
<li>Searchers see a recent tweet when it matches their query.</li>
<li>Mobile visitors to m.USA.gov see unique page titles in browser.</li>
<li>When customers add or modify a <a href="/sites/manual/domains.html">domain</a>, their pages are automatically discovered.</li>
<li>Customers have a free form text box (versus a drop-down menu) to enter related sites on the Results Modules page.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>Searchers can tab to a link to skip to the main content. (Thanks, USCIS, for pointing this out.)</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for the Week Ending May 11, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-05-11.html"/>
    <updated>2012-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-05-11.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Highlight: Additional Sidebar Flexibility</em></p>


<p>You can now change the order of the sidebar options that appear on your results page, regardless of source.</p>


<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_m42l7i8Z251qid15q.png"/></p>


<ul><li>Customers may leverage the USASearch discovery tag over https.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>Fix layout of deep links.</li>
<li>Fetch RSS feed entries without guid.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[April 2012 Release Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-04-30.html"/>
    <updated>2012-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-04-30.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In April, we released several important underlying infrastructure changes. These changes will allow us to deliver more features for our agency customers and searchers in the months ahead. For example, we upgraded all of our customers to a new template-based system, which will provide us with the flexibility to roll out new video, image, and social media features seamlessly.</p>


<p>Below are the release details for April and, as a reminder, we divide our work into three categories.</p>


<ol><li>FeaturesThings you actually notice.</li>
<li>ChoresBack-end improvements that you don't notice.</li>
<li>FixesFixes to any code issues that may arise.</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>For Agency Customers</em></p>


<ul><li>Customers can input multiple social media handles or URLs on the Social Media page.</li>
<li>Customers can input multiple RSS feeds for each title on the RSS page.</li>
<li>Customers can upload a page background image on the Look and Feel page. They can also select a repeat option for the image.</li>
<li>Customers can toggle display of deep links on the Results Module page.</li>
<li>Customers can toggle related sites, including Spanish, on the Results Module page.</li>
<li>Customers can input their WebTrends or Google Analytics IDs on the 3rd Party Tracking page.</li>
<li>Customers can download weekly reports from Monthly Reports page.</li>
<li>API customers can access new features through the API.</li>
<li>USASearch admins can bulk upload an unlimited number of URLs on behalf of customers.</li>
<li>USASearch admins can specify "catalog" URLs on behalf of customers.</li>
</ul>


<p><em>For Searchers</em></p>


<ul><li>Searchers see all elements aligned horizontally under search bar.</li>
<li>Searchers see the published at date for web search results when the URL is part of an RSS feed.</li>
<li>Searchers see up to 20 video results per page with a paging option to see more results.</li>
<li>Mobile searchers see mobile friendly results pages for RSS- and collection-based results.</li>
<li>Searchers see magnifying glass favicon on hosted results pages when no custom favicon is specified.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Chores</strong></p>


<ul><li>Regularly update all specified URLs, including those discovered via sitemaps.</li>
<li>Remove the locale parameter from the URL.</li>
<li>Collapse duplicate leading slashes in URLs in the USASearch index.</li>
<li>Discover and create nested PDFs daily. Fetch and index them with the weekly refresh.</li>
<li>Update USASearch program URL to <a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">usasearch.howto.gov</a>.</li>
<li>Redirect searchers from search.usa.gov/forms to USA.gov's <a href="http://www.usa.gov/Topics/Reference-Shelf/forms.shtml">forms page</a>.</li>
<li>Developers can no longer sign up for a USASearch account. Redirect developers to the recalls API on USA.gov's <a href="http://www.usa.gov/About/developer-resources/developers.shtml">developer resources</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>Customers using ad block extensions see the left nav in the Admin Center.</li>
<li>Customers are no longer allowed to toggle OneSERP on the Look and Feel page if their header or footer contains script, style, or link elements.</li>
<li>Customers are no longer allowed to enter HTML or body elements in the header and footer.</li>
<li>IE-specific comments do not break the page layout.</li>
<li>Searchers no longer see a border around the header image when it has a link.</li>
<li>Take the useragent into account when parsing robots.txt files.</li>
<li>Center managed headers in IE8.</li>
<li>Fix RSS search to allow page parameters.</li>
<li>Fix display problem with ampersands.</li>
<li>Fix date sort in the recalls API.</li>
<li>Fix export URLs to export all records.</li>
<li>Fix the URLs and Sitemaps page to load quickly.</li>
<li>Fix missing help links in the Admin Center.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release Notes for the Week Ending May 4, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-05-04.html"/>
    <updated>2012-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-05-04.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Highlight: Twitter integration</strong></p>


<p>Starting in May, we're posting our release notes at the end of each week (versus each month). We've heard, and we agree, that the monthly list is too much to absorb in one sitting. We also want to let you know about our new features more promptly.</p>


<p>Below are the release details for the first week of May.</p>


<p><strong>Features (things you actually notice)</strong></p>


<p><em>For agency customers</em></p>


<ul><li>Customers who have input their Twitter handle(s) have their tweets indexed.</li>
<li>Customers receive periodic emails about unused features.</li>
</ul>


<p><em>For searchers</em></p>


<ul><li>Searchers see an improved user interface for faceted navigation in sidebar.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Fixes (fixes to any bugs that may arise)</strong></p>


<ul><li>RSS feed parser now looks for atomUpdated.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Chores (back-end improvements that you don't notice)</strong></p>


<ul><li>USASearch admin can generate system reports based on selected features.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[After our migration of Commerce.gov to Drupal, we...]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/commerce.html"/>
    <updated>2012-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/commerce.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After our migration of Commerce.gov to Drupal, we used the native search tool. However, after looking at the internal site search analytics, it was obvious visitors were not finding what they were looking for. USASearch integrated easily into our system and provided several new features. I appreciate the auto-fill and sort by source features and so do our visitors. Our analytics logs report a much higher percentage of searches resulting in what the visitor was looking for.</p>

<p>Mike Kruger, Director of Digital Strategy, <a href="http://www.commerce.gov">U.S. Department of Commerce</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ The primary mission of the Defense Media Activity...]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/dod.html"/>
    <updated>2012-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/dod.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The primary mission of the Defense Media Activity (DMA) is to provide a broad range of high quality multimedia products and services to inform, educate, and entertain Department of Defense audiences around the world. DMA Public Web delivers information to a worldwide audience via 500+ official Department of Defense websites such as the official websites for Department of Defense, Joint Chiefs of Staff, Air Force, Marines, Navy, and Army Corps of Engineers.</p>

<p>Our goal is to do that using the latest technologies available in the most cost effective manner possible. Partnering with USASearch has enabled us to further enhance our capabilities while saving upwards of $214,000 per year from our previous enterprise search system.</p>

<p>USASearch has empowered us with more control over search results to more effectively help our customers quickly and easily find the information they are looking for. Their flexible system allows us to make adjustments with ease and quickly deploy search for new sites, two elements that are crucial to the success of our operations.</p>

<p>Beyond that, we feel that USASearch values their stakeholders and we appreciate their flexibility, attention to detail, and migration assistance. They have been in constant contact with our team, and have adjusted their code numerous times to meet our core mission requirements with nothing less than superlative and reliable results. This program is a terrific example of how government agencies are finding new and creative ways to save money while still providing a much needed service.</p>

<p>Public Web, <a href="http://www.dma.mil">Defense Media Activity</a>, <a href="http://www.defense.gov">U.S. Department of Defense</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[March 2012 Release Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-03-31.html"/>
    <updated>2012-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-03-31.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>We've moved! Our homepage is now <a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov"><a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">http://usasearch.howto.gov</a></a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.howto.gov">HowTo.gov</a> is a website to help government workers deliver a better customer experience to citizens. HowTo.gov is managed by <a href="http://www.gsa.gov/portal/category/25729">GSA's Office of Citizen Services and Innovative Technologies</a> and the <a href="http://www.howto.gov/communities/federal-web-managers-council">Federal Web Managers Council</a>, and is supported by other communities of practice. Search is an important aspect of customer experience so we're happy be part of HowTo.gov.</p>
<p>Below are the release details for March and, as a reminder, we divide our work into three categories.</p>
<ol><li>FeaturesThings you actually notice.</li>
<li>ChoresBack-end improvements that you don't notice.</li>
<li>FixesFixes to any code issues that may arise.</li>
</ol><p><strong>Features</strong></p>
<p><em>For Agency Customers</em></p>
<ul><li>Customers can add an optional header for the sidebar options on the results page.</li>
<li>Customers can add header and footer navigation on the results page by entering label and URL pairs.</li>
<li>Customer can toggle display of RSS feeds as a GovBox.</li>
<li>Customers who enter a <a href="/sites/manual/youtube.html">YouTube</a> handle automatically have a RSS feed created for their videos.</li>
<li>Customers see new Sidebar and Results Modules pages in the Admin Center.</li>
<li>Customers see Page Views page in the Admin Center to provide usage data on results page.</li>
<li>Customers are redirected from old URLs to new usasearch.howto.gov URLs.</li>
<li>Customers can access feature-specific help via the Admin Center.</li>
</ul><p><em>For Searchers</em></p>
<ul><li>Searchers see results from RSS feeds in a GovBox.</li>
<li>Searchers see logical links for image results.</li>
<li>Searchers see a GovBox for videos with a multimedia-friendly UI.</li>
<li>Searchers who don't enter a query term on RSS-based results pages see results in reverse chronological order.</li>
<li>Searchers see results from all time when they click on RSS GovBox titles.</li>
<li>Searchers who modify their query (but don't execute it) see results for their new query term when they click on a sidebar option.</li>
<li>Searchers see plain language text on the Spanish-language no results found page.</li>
</ul><p><strong>Chores</strong></p>
<ul><li>Revised the on-page Admin Center help text.</li>
<li>Increased speed of returning search results, especially for RSS feeds.</li>
<li>Implemented Spanish stop words.</li>
</ul><p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>
<ul><li>No error page seen when searching across RSS feeds.</li>
<li>No error page seen when accessing RSS- or collection-based results pages from a mobile device.</li>
<li>Increased font size for title of RSS GovBox.</li>
<li>Fixed link so that clicking on Images on the results page stays within that site.</li>
<li>Improved handling of fetching HTML content for slower customer websites.</li>
<li>Removed ability to enter enter CSS or JavaScript tags in the managed header or footer fields.</li>
<li>Fixed Push Changes to trigger an email with header and footer changes.</li>
</ul></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Department of Labor Launches Improved Site and Uses USASearch]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/labor.html"/>
    <updated>2012-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/labor.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last year the Department of Labor (DOL) participated in the <a href="http://www.howto.gov/web-content/usability/first-fridays">First Fridays</a> Product Testing Program, a discount usability testing session designed to find and fix usability problems on <a href="http://www.dol.gov">DOL.gov</a>.</p>

<p>The experience led the DOL web team to <a href="http://social.dol.gov/blog/improving-our-website">improve DOL.gov</a>, including changing their search engine.</p>

<p>So it was satisfying to learn that they decided to use USASearch to power the search on DOL.gov. The basis of their decision to select USASearch is exactly what we hope motivates each agency to use USASearch.</p>

<blockquote><p>The 'out of the box' search results are much more relevant than our prior search results because it harnesses the power of a world-class search engine and the program offers us a great amount of control for suggesting the best links for certain search results and ensuring that new content or breaking news is included in the search results.</p></blockquote>

<p>Thank you, DOL!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gartner Case Study Commends USASearch]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/gartner.html"/>
    <updated>2012-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/gartner.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Gartner recently published a very positive case study on USASearch (<em><a href="http://www.gartner.com/DisplayDocument?id=1909916">Create Better, Faster Enterprise Search With a Customized Open-Source Option</a></em>, January 2012). In the report, Gartner notes that USASearch addresses the key aspects of designing a search system.</p>

<blockquote><p>Gartner identifies key stages of action in "Your Enterprise Search Project: The Outward Spiral." USASearch addressed them all:</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Staffing</em> the project with experts who had domain knowledge.</li>
<li><em>Scoping</em> the project using those personnel to satisfy search requirements for federal websites.</li>
<li><em>Selecting</em> the right technology.</li>
<li><em>Implementing</em> it effectively with workers who have the right skill sets.</li>
<li><em>Measuring</em> results as effectively as possible.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[February 2012 Release Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-02-29.html"/>
    <updated>2012-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-02-29.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>February was an exciting month for the USASearch team. We rolled out a brand new look to emphasize our focus on helping you create a great search experience on your websites.</p>
<p>Our blog will now serve as our home page. It also will answer your questions about how our features work so be sure to browse through our <a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/tagged/how-to">How To Manual</a> for tips on how to configure your search settings.</p>
Below are the release details for February and, as a reminder, we divide our work into three categories.<ol><li>FeaturesThings you actually notice.</li>
<li>ChoresBack-end improvements that you don't notice.</li>
<li>FixesFixes to any code issues that may arise.</li>
</ol><p><strong>Features</strong></p>
<p><em>For Searchers</em></p>
<ul><li>Searchers don't see narrow by date on Everything or Images pages (i.e., on Bing-based results pages).</li>
<li>Searchers see a longer search box on the results page.</li>
<li>Searchers see near-real-time <a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/tagged/type-ahead">type-ahead</a> suggestions.</li>
<li>Searchers see a custom header image on results pages.</li>
<li>Searchers may narrow results by <a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/tagged/collections">collections</a> in left nav.</li>
<li>Searchers see a Results by USASearch logo.</li>
<li>Mobile visitors can find more <a href="http://www.usa.gov/gobiernousa">GobiernoUSA.gov</a> pages.</li>
</ul><p><em>For Agency Customers</em></p>
<ul><li>Customers see new Add New Site wizard.</li>
<li>Customers see raw and processed query analytics in downloaded CSV files.</li>
<li>Customers with legacy results pages can preview template-based results pages.</li>
<li>Customers have an Export to CSV option for indexed URLs.</li>
<li>Customers see updated Look &amp; Feel and Header &amp; Footer pages.</li>
</ul><p><strong>Chores</strong></p>
<ul><li>Fix Sunspot library to remove orphans.</li>
<li>Adjust default CSS for theme-based templates.</li>
<li>Move customers with legacy templates and without header/footer to theme-based templates.</li>
<li>Allow assignment of priorities to background (Resque) jobs.</li>
<li>Set default index to Bing + USASearch.</li>
</ul><p><strong>Fixes</strong></p>
<ul><li>Fix occasional errors highlighting phrases.</li>
<li>Fix layout on theme-based templates.</li>
<li>Fix URL prefixes with trailing spaces to not append slash.</li>
<li>Update error message when customers upload a .txt file.</li>
<li>Fix images to have same results page title as other verticals.</li>
<li>Automatically down case terms in site handle field.</li>
<li>Fix bug where the header image filename was getting longer and longer when saving.</li>
<li>Fix Agency GovBox to point to new USA.gov results page.</li>
</ul></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[January 2012 Release Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-01-31.html"/>
    <updated>2012-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2012-01-31.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span>As we start 2012, we </span><span>want to highlight two major, new features. </span></p>


<ol><li><span>Discovery Tag</span>O<span>ur on-demand indexing engine allows you to automatically add content to your search index. You may make use of our on-demand indexing by placing our Discovery Tag (available on the Get Code page in the admin center) on your web pages.<br/></span></li>
<li><span>Themes for results pages</span>Our n<span>ew and improved theme-based results pages help you create a customized look and feel "out of the box." You may view the themes by adding a new site in our admin center. We're also in the process of migrating all customers into this new user interface.</span></li>
</ol>


<p>Below are the details for January and, as a reminder, we divide our work into three categories.</p>


<ol><li>FeaturesThings you actually notice.</li>
<li>ChoresBack-end improvements that you don't notice.</li>
<li>FixesFixes to any code issues that may arise.</li>
</ol>


<p><strong><em>Features</em></strong></p>


<p><em>For Searchers</em></p>


<ul><li>Searchers get better PDF result coverage in results.</li>
<li>Searchers only see indexed documents that belong to the site's domain collection.</li>
<li>Searchers see MedlinePlus (health topics) and Enhanced Agency GovBoxes, when customers opt to display them via the admin center.</li>
<li>Searchers see nicer paging.</li>
<li>Searchers don't see Indexed Document GovBox.</li>
<li>Searchers can see all Indexed Document results.</li>
<li>Searchers on template-based results pages see a nice, matching shaded header with rounded corners.</li>
<li>Mobile searchers see colors from selected theme.</li>
<li>Searchers see square fade on related searches and other modules.</li>
</ul>


<p><em>For Agency Customers</em></p>


<ul><li>Customers see new Domains page.</li>
<li>Customers have an easy way to pass multiple parameters.</li>
<li>By default, customers have a useful header on results pages during signup.</li>
<li>Customers may point at a dynamic sitemap generator for hosted sitemaps.</li>
<li>Customers may set up sites with keyword filtered results.</li>
<li>Customers see an updated left nav in the admin center.</li>
</ul>


<p><em><strong>Chores</strong></em></p>


<ul><li>Migrated USA.gov's  "enhanced results" Agency and MedlinePlus to GovBoxes.</li>
<li>Refactored search classes.</li>
<li>Removed website URL from the Add New Site wizard.</li>
<li>Shortened unique index for type-ahead suggestions.</li>
<li>Upgraded Solr from 1.4 to 3.5.</li>
<li>Changed timestamp indexing for Solr to use a trie on NewsItem model.</li>
<li>Modified stopword analysis to include Solr CommonGrams filtering.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Bug Fixes</strong></p>


<ul><li>Fixed Spanish translations for indexed documents.</li>
<li>Fixed display error when search results contain Bing matches and indexed documents.</li>
<li>Fixed error received by customers when migrating to themes. </li>
<li>Fixed RSS feed readers to handle 503 errors more gracefully.</li>
<li>Disabled ActiveRecord observers during database migrations.</li>
<li>Removed rule to allow customers to add top level domains (e.g., .gov and .mil) as site domains.</li>
<li>Fixed parsing of PDF files.</li>
<li>Fixed tests around Bing result counts.</li>
<li>Preserved newlines on virtual header/footer/css fields when updated via admin center.</li>
<li>Fixed doctype for nested PDF documents.</li>
<li>Fixed various problems around discovery of embedded PDFs.</li>
<li>Created error page for searchers when the search per-page query parameter is set to blank.</li>
<li>Fixed issue where hosted sitemaps still existed for domains with no indexed documents.</li>
<li>Weeded out indexed documents for anything that doesn't work with URI.parse() method.</li>
<li>Handled race condition where duplicate id/content hash pair gets past Rails but is caught in MySQL.</li>
<li>Handled race condition where an IndexedDocument can't be updated because another one was created.</li>
<li>Removed assumption that pages are PDF because the URL ends in ".pdf."</li>
<li>Selected "Everything" on results page by default.</li>
<li>Removed body field from the CSV download of IndexedDocument URLs</li>
<li>Fixed infinite loop in PDF discovery and indexing.</li>
<li>Verified IndexedDocument URL length is &lt;= 2000 rather than accepting it and silently truncating it.</li>
<li>Used document body for documents with a blank meta description tag.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[December 2011 Release Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-12-31.html"/>
    <updated>2011-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-12-31.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We divide our work into three categories.</p>


<ol><li>FeaturesThings you actually notice.</li>
<li>ChoresBack-end improvements that you don't notice.</li>
<li>BugsFixes to any code issues that may arise.</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Features for Searchers</em></p>


<ul><li>Searchers don't see duplicate results from Add URLs.</li>
<li>Spanish searchers see stemmed equivalents.</li>
<li>Searchers on USA.gov see FAQ GovBox higher in results.</li>
</ul>


<p><em>Features for Agency Customers</em></p>


<ul><li>Customers can choose from predefined themes.</li>
<li>Customers see a a Sitemap box on the Sitemaps page.</li>
<li>Customers have a Discovery Tag for USASearch to proactively discover and index content from their websites.</li>
<li>Customers can edit Header and Footer CSS.</li>
<li>Customers can set their locale to Spanish during sign up.</li>
<li>Customers see an updated left nav.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Chores</strong></p>


<ul><li>Remove "locale" parameter from all models, analytics, etc.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Bugs<br/></strong></p>


<ul><li>Add Spanish translations for Popular Links, no RSS results, and document results.</li>
<li>Remove extra whitespace when displaying snippets.</li>
<li>Fix buggy bold highlighting in type-ahead searches in API.</li>
<li>Remove 0-100 scale from sparklines in search module stats and let it autoscale.</li>
<li>Increase length of URL and title field on indexed documents.</li>
<li>Ignore invalid IndexedDocument URL's before they get queued for fetching/indexing</li>
<li>Ignore HTTPS URLS for on-demand index.</li>
<li>Fix duplicate results due to domain and protocol variations.</li>
<li>Handle 503 errors from RSS feeds more gracefully.</li>
<li>Fix error logging around duplicate indexed docs pages.</li>
<li>Fix deduping regression to still match exact URLs.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Didn't Try to Grow a Bigger Ox: How I Found Hadoop]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/hadoop-bigger-ox.html"/>
    <updated>2011-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/hadoop-bigger-ox.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A year ago I rolled my first Hadoop system into production. Since then, I've spoken to quite a few people who are eager to try Hadoop themselves in order to solve their own big data problems. Despite having similar backgrounds and data problems, few of these people have sunk their teeth into Hadoop. When I go to Hadoop Meetups in San Francisco, I often meet new people who are evaluating Hadoop and have yet to launch a cluster. Based on my own background and experience, I have some ideas on why this is the case.</p>


<p>I studied computer science in school and have worked on a wide variety of computer systems in my career, with a lot of focus on server-side Java. I learned a bit about building distributed systems and working with large amounts of data when I built a pay-per-click (PPC) ad network in 2004. The system is still in operation and at one point was handling several thousand searches per second. As the sole technical resource on the system, I had to educate myself very quickly about how to scale up.</p>


<p>As I contemplated how doomed I would be should traffic levels increase much more, I remember wondering to myself, "How does Google deal with all that data?" The answer came to me in the form of the Google File System (GFS) paper and later the MapReduce paper, both from Google. It dawned on me that because Google was forced to solve a much larger problem, they had come up with an elegant solution for a whole range of more modest data problems running on commodity hardware. But it wouldn't be until 2010 that I would get to work with this technology firsthand.</p>


<p>As I wrote in an <a href="/blog/adopting-hadoop.html" target="_blank">earlier article</a>, I started re-architecting <a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch</a>, the U.S. government's search system, in 2009 based on a solution stack of free, open source software including Ruby on Rails, Solr, and MySQL. A wave of dja vu hit me as I started worrying about what to do with the growing mountain of data piling up in MySQL and our increasing need to analyze it in different ways. I had heard that a new company called Cloudera, founded by some big data people from Yahoo!, Google, and Facebook, was making Hadoop available for the masses in a reliable distribution, much in the same way that RedHat did for Linux. Curiosity got the best of me and I bought the newly minted <em>Hadoop: The Definitive Guide</em> from O'Reilly. The most insightful part of the book to me was the very first sentence. It's a quote from Grace Hopper: "In pioneer days, they used oxen for heavy pulling, and when one ox couldn't budge a log, they didn't try to grow a bigger ox." I didn't want to grow a bigger server; I wanted to harness a bunch of small servers together to work in unison. The more I learned the more curious I got, so I started reading more. And that's when I hit my first roadblock.</p>


<p>I think people who have been working with Hadoop technologies for years and years sometimes forget just how rich and diverse the big data software ecosystem has become, and how daunting it can be to folks approaching it for the first time. When people at the Meetups say they are evaluating solutions to their data scaling problem, the answers they hear sound something like this: "Just use Hadoop Hive Pig Mahout Avro HBase Cassandra Oozie Sqoop Flume ZooKeeper Cascading NoSQL RCFile. Oh, almost forgotcloud."</p>


<p>The thought of wading through all of that just to learn about what I needed to learn about was a bit too overwhelming for me, so I put the whole matter aside for a few months. Over time, I started to dive into each of these projects to understand the primary use case, how active the developer community was and which organizations were using it in production. I converged on the idea of using Hive as a warehouse for our data. I opted for Cloudera's distribution since I wanted to reduce the risk of running into compatibility issues between all the various subsystems. Having tracked down anomalies in a highly multi-threaded and contentious distributed Java system before, I liked the idea of someone else taking on that problem for me.</p>


<p>At some point, I had read everything I could read and grew impatient to get my hands dirty, so I decided to just download CDH3 on my laptop and give it a try. The tutorial instructions for the standalone version worked, and I successfully computed more digits of pi than I ever thought I'd need. After creating some sample data in Hive and running a few queries, I felt pretty confident that Hive would be the right tool for the job. I just needed to find somewhere to install and run HDFS (namenode, secondary namenode, and data nodes), Hadoop (jobtracker and tasktracker nodes), Hive, and Hue for a nice front end to it all.</p>


<p>I knew from my past experience how to stretch the limits of CPU, disk, IO, and memory on commodity servers, and I identified a few potential servers at our primary datacenter with resources I figured I could leverage. Once again I followed the tutorial instructions, this time for the fully distributed version of CDH3, and once again I started to compute pi. And that's when I hit my second roadblock. It took me a few days to figure out that I had a problem with DNS. Each machine needs to be able to resolve every other machine's name and IP in the cluster. Whether you do that via /etc/hosts or a local DNS server is up to you, but it needs to happen or the whole thing gets wedged. Once I got that sorted out, everything just started falling into place and I had Hive working in production within a few days. A week later, I started pulling out the MySQL jobs and deleting big tables, and that's been the trend ever since.</p>


<p>Over time, I've gone on to learn about using custom Ruby mappers in Hive, moving data back and forth between MySQL and Hive with Sqoop, and getting the data into HDFS in real-time with Flume. All of these components from the Cloudera distribution are working nicely in our production environment now, and I sleep well at night knowing I have such a solid, deliberate plan for growth. My initial investment in learning about the Hadoop ecosystem is really paying dividends, but when I think about all those people at the Meetups stuck in evaluation mode, I feel their pain. Does it have to be such a struggle?</p>


<p>The big challenge in my opinion is not that any one piece of the puzzle is too difficult. Any reasonably smart (or in my case stubborn) engineer can set themselves on the task of learning about a new technology once they know that it needs to be learned. The challenge with the Hadoop ecosystem is that it presents the newbie with the meta-problem of figuring out which of these tools are appropriate for their use case at all, and whether or not to even consider the problem today versus deferring it until later. In a way Facebook has it easy, because when you are adding 15TB of data per day, that decision is pretty much made for you.</p>


<p>For all the companies sitting in the twilight between the gigabyte and the petabyte who don't have Hadoop expertise in-house, there is a collection of free information to help guide people to the right solution space (Hadoop Tutorial, White Papers). These days, when I talk to people who are evaluating solutions to their big data problems, my advice to them is to break down their problems into a few discrete use cases and then work on ferreting out the technologies that are designed for that use case. Get a proof of concept to demonstrate that the technology can address your use case and convince yourself and others that you're on the right track. Work toward putting something simple into production. Lather, rinse, and repeat. I am still in that cycle myself, as these days I'm exploring HBase and OpenTSDB to give me low-latency access to time series data and Mahout to do frequent item set mining, but that's another article for another day.</p>


<p><em>By Loren</em></p>


<p><em><strong>This post is cross-posted from <a href="http://www.cloudera.com/blog/2011/12/how-i-found-hadoop/">Cloudera</a>.</strong></em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[November 2011 Release Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-11-30.html"/>
    <updated>2011-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-11-30.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Happy Holidays from the USASearch Team!</p>


<p>We're happy to let you know more about our on-demand indexing features. You can now let us know where your new content lives (by submitting your new URLs, RSS feeds, or sitemaps), and we'll immediately display it on your results pages. You've been asking for on-demand indexing, so we're happy to officially announce this capability. Please check it out and let us know what you think.</p>


<p>As a reminder, we divide our work into three categories.</p>


<ol><li>FeaturesThings you actually notice.</li>
<li>ChoresBack-end improvements that you don't notice.</li>
<li>BugsFixes to any code issues that may arise.</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Features for Searchers</em></p>


<ul><li>Searchers see site-specific favicon.</li>
<li>Searchers may narrow results to see images only.</li>
<li>Searchers may use SSL.</li>
<li>Searchers see related searches based on type-ahead suggestions at the bottom of results pages.</li>
<li>Spanish searchers retrieve tokenized variants.</li>
<li>USA.gov visitors can consume recalls as an <a href="http://www.usa.gov/rss/index.shtml">RSS feed</a>.</li>
<li>Mobile tablet visitors to m.USA.gov see the classic view for results pages.</li>
</ul>


<p><em>Features for Affiliate Center Users<br/></em></p>


<ul><li>Affiliate Center users can populate and display top or trending searches.</li>
<li>Affiliate Center users may submit sitemaps for on-demand indexing.</li>
<li>URLs added by Affiliate Center users are refreshed periodically.</li>
<li>Affiliate Center users may emergency delete a URL.</li>
<li>Affiliate Center users may bulk delete type-ahead suggestions.</li>
<li>Affiliate Center users receive an audit-trail email when their header or footer changes.</li>
<li>Affiliate Center users may delete URLs they've added as content sources.</li>
<li>Affiliate Center users may customize font colors and families on their results pages via themes. </li>
<li>Affiliate may enable Images tab on Affiliate SERP.</li>
<li>Affiliates may submit social media handles. </li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Chores</strong></p>


<ul><li>Added 'a' as a stopword.</li>
<li>Updated search analytics in Affiliate Center to search on today's data. </li>
<li>Changed label in Affiliate Center from HTTP Parameter Site Name to Site Handle.</li>
<li>Investigated document fetching and indexing errors.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Bugs</strong><br/><ul><li>Added Spanish translations for Everything, Images, and time filters on results pages.</li>
<li>Removed garbage characters for indexed PDF files.</li>
<li>Added support to parse password-protected PDF files.</li>
<li>Truncated descriptions for indexed PDF files at 250 characters.</li>
<li>Added support to allow sitemaps can reference other sitemaps.</li>
</ul></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ The USASearch tool is awesome. It makes finding...]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/bia.html"/>
    <updated>2011-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/bia.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The USASearch tool is awesome. It makes finding things on our website easier than ever. The results that come back are both quick and relevant. My favorite feature has to be Query Logs. What our users are looking for is now crystal clear, which makes my life way easier. It provides insight into what users want that is sometimes very hard to find. It also allows us to promote the correct content.</p>

<p>For instance, for several months our most search terms were employment and jobs, so we created a Jobs page and put it right on our homepage. After that the search for those terms dropped dramatically, which means users no longer had to poke and search for Jobs/Employment information because it was right where it needed to be.</p>

<p>I almost couldn't believe that this amazing service is free. It's easy to implement and full of useful features, which would normally cost us quite a lot and in this economy it's these types of services that help us save money.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.bia.gov">Indian Affairs</a>, U.S. Department of the Interior</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We encourage the use of shared services across...]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/White-House.html"/>
    <updated>2011-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/White-House.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We encourage the use of shared services across government agencies and we want to make WhiteHouse.gov an example for others to follow. It would not be possible to match the value of GSA's free search service by procuring or building a custom solution. Previously, we needed to dedicate significant resources to configuring and tuning our internal solution, whereas with USASearch, we can now deploy these resources to enhance the features of and technology supporting the White House website.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov">The White House</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[USASearch Wins Government Big Data Solutions Award]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/award-big-data.html"/>
    <updated>2011-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/award-big-data.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>USASearch is the <a href="http://ctolabs.com/gsa-usasearch-wins-2011-government-big-data-solutions-award">winner of the 2011 Government Big Data Solutions Award</a>, announced at <a href="http://www.hadoopworld.com">Hadoop World</a> in New York City on November 8, 2011.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://ctolabs.com/big-data-award">Big Data Award</a> was established to highlight innovative solutions and to facilitate the exchange of best practices, lessons learned, and creative ideas for addressing Big Data challenges. The Award judges saw the USASearch Program as a great example of solving Big Data problems to improve government agility and to provide better service for less.</p>

<p>In line with the GSA's cost-saving "build once, use many times" paradigm, USASearch provides hosted search services for <a href="http://www.usa.gov">USA.gov</a> and hundreds of other government websites. This is done in a cost-effective way, especially for the agencies involved, which receive these services at no cost.</p>

<p>From the Award presentation:</p>

<blockquote><p>The GSA is to be congratulated for their mission-focused, citizen-centered, open approach to a big data challenge and a resulting solution that improves the experience of a broad swath of users of federal services. On behalf of our judges and the many citizens who use this capability on a daily basis we say thank you, and congratulations on this well deserved recognition.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hadoop for Rubyists]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/hadoop-rubyists.html"/>
    <updated>2011-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/hadoop-rubyists.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Is your MySQL groaning under too much data? Tired of waiting hours for analytics rake tasks?</p>

<p><a href="http://pivotallabs.com/talks/150-hadoop-for-rubyists"><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_luckbhCakH1qid15q.png" alt="Hadoop for Rubyists video" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://pivotallabs.com/talks/150-hadoop-for-rubyists">Listen to Loren</a>, USASearch's senior technical architect, as he discusses how USASearch leveraged our existing Ruby codebase by building Hadoop Map/Reduce jobs using Hive and plugging in our own Ruby mappers/reducers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[October 2011 Release Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-10-31.html"/>
    <updated>2011-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-10-31.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span></span>October wasn't scary for the USASearch team. We enhanced your ability to immediately add content to your search results. You can now tell us about a URL or RSS feed in the <a href="http://search.usa.gov/sites">Admin Center</a> and we will immediately index the content and display it on your results page.</p>


<p>Additionally, we now offer real-time reporting for your search queries in the Affiliate Center, allowing you to see your website's search activity throughout the day.</p>


<p><span>As a reminder, we divide our work into three categories:</span><span> </span></p>


<p>1) FeaturesThings that you actually notice;<br/>2) ChoresBack-end improvements that you don't notice; and<span><br/>3) BugsFixes to any code issues that may arise.</span></p>


<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Features for Searchers</em></p>


<ul><li>Searchers see polished look and feel for results pages with RSS elements.</li>
<li>Searchers see option to filter results by last 24 hours, last week, and last month on results pages with RSS elements.</li>
<li>Searchers see option to remove all filters when no results are found for RSS results. </li>
<li>Searchers see indexed documents/pages from the USASearch index on results pages.</li>
<li>>m.USA.gov visitors see new homepage options.</li>
<li>m.USA.gov visitors may click anywhere on row to select a homepage option.</li>
</ul>


<p><em>Features for Affiliate Center Users<br/></em></p>


<ul><li>Affiliate Center users may input RSS feeds.</li>
<li>Affiliate Center users see crawl information for USASearch crawler.</li>
<li>URLs added by Affiliate Center users and fetched by USASearch go into Add to Bing feed transparently.</li>
<li>Affiliate Center users may add URLs not in their domain list.</li>
<li>Affiliate Center users may bulk upload Best Bets in CSV format.</li>
<li>Affiliate Center users may view today's analytics data.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Chores</strong></p>


<ul><li>Report RSS feed processing errors.</li>
<li>Precede Bing logo with "Results by." </li>
<li>Searchers see attribution to USASearch Program in HTML code.</li>
<li>Ignore case when RSS feeds are busy or unavailable.</li>
<li>Update Affiliate Center navigation and text.</li>
<li>Implement near zero-downtime deployments.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Bugs</strong></p>


<ul><li>Add flag to determine whether older items from an RSS feed are ignored or processed.</li>
<li>Affiliate Center users using IE9 may cancel a delete request.</li>
<li>Publications does not stem to public(s).</li>
<li>Affiliate Center users may upload Atom RSS feeds.</li>
<li>Searchers don't see "!!!sep" after an Affiliate Center user deletes a row in a Best Bet.</li>
<li>RSS searches don't cause an error when the affiliate name is invalid.</li>
<li>Indexed document results highlight keywords.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your service is phenomenal. I cannot believe I...]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/nij.html"/>
    <updated>2011-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/nij.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Your service is phenomenal. I cannot believe I waited this long to switch to USASearch for NIJ.gov.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.nij.gov">National Institute of Justice</a>, U.S. Department of Justice</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[September 2011 Release Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-09-30.html"/>
    <updated>2011-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-09-30.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In September, we were busy laying the groundwork for an exciting fall.</p>


<p>Due to popular demand, all of your search results pages are now mobile-friendly.</p>


<p>We also rolled out a feature to index PDF files, the first of our on demand indexing features. Stay tuned as we will have more in-depth posts about how you can use USASearch to make your various content sources immediately appear within your search results.</p>


<p><span> </span></p>


<p>As a reminder, we divide our work into three categories:</p>


<p>1) FeaturesThings that you actually notice;<br/>2) BugsFixes to any code issues that may arise; and<br/>3) ChoresBack-end improvements that you don't notice.</p>


<p><strong>Features</strong></p>


<p><em>Features for Affiliate Center Users</em></p>


<ul><li>Ability to specify a PDF file to be fetched and indexed</li>
<li>Ability to add a featured site</li>
<li>Ability to access the Search API via XML</li>
<li>Ability to reference your external CSS</li>
</ul>


<p><em>Features for Searchers</em></p>


<ul><li>Searchers see indexed PDFs after the last Bing result, and can click to see a subsequent page consisting of only locally indexed PDF files</li>
<li>Searchers see more results from Boosted Content layer if there are no Bing results</li>
<li>Mobile visitors to your websites see mobile-friendly results pages</li>
<li>Searchers see 508-friendly colors on the grey template</li>
<li>Searchers see agencies' popular URLs based on their language (i.e., locale)</li>
<li>Searchers on [USA.gov](http://www.usa.gov) and <a href="http://www.usa.gov/gobiernousa">GobiernoUSA.gov</a> see Featured Collections</li>
<li>Mobile visitors to m.USA.gov see both Featured Content and Top Questions FAQs</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Bugs</strong></p>


<ul><li>Visitors on m.USA.gov who have chosen Classic mode remain on the classic results page after clicking on a search trends link</li>
<li>Searchers see only the one, most relevant featured collection</li>
<li>Searchers see both featured sites and collections</li>
<li>Searchers see newspaper-style lists in featured collections</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Chores</strong></p>


<ul><li>Upgrade Rails for security fixes</li>
<li>Remove PPT from certain query strings</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Help Searchers Find Health Information]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/govbox-health.html"/>
    <updated>2011-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/sites/manual/govbox-health.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Searches for health-related information are very common. So we created the Health GovBox to help you provide searchers with high-quality, authoritative health information.</p>

<p>This GovBox offers direct access to <a href="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/healthtopics.html">MedlinePlus Health Topics</a> and to open studies on <a href="http://clinicaltrials.gov">ClinicalTrials.gov</a>. To ensure we provide timely information across all health topics, we've done this automatically using the <a href="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/xml.html">MedlinePlus XML files</a>, which cover both the English and Spanish health topics.</p>

<p>If you <a href="/sites/manual/display-overview.html">opt to show the MedlinePlus GovBox</a>, searchers looking for health topics on your site can readily find high-quality health information, as shown in the sample below for a search on <em><a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?query=ovarian+cancer">ovarian cancer</a></em> on <a href="http://www.nc.gov">NC.gov</a>.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/govbox-health.png" alt="Health GovBox on NC.gov" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[August 2011 Release Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-09-15.html"/>
    <updated>2011-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-09-15.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span></span></p>


<p><span>While the dogs days of summer are almost over, we didn't let the weather stop us from rolling out some hot new features.</span></p>


<p><span>We we are currently beta testing two new rendering options: iFrame and a <a href="https://drupal.org/project/USASearch">Drupal module</a> which will allow you to host the search results on your web site and gain additional control of the look and feel. If you are an affiliate and interested in beta testing, please let us know.</span></p>


<p><span></span>As a reminder, we divide our work into three categories:</p>


<p>1) FeaturesThings that you actually notice</p>


<p>2) BugsFixes to any code issues that may arise</p>


<p>3) ChoresBack-end improvements that users don't notice</p>


<p><span></span></p>


<p><strong>Features:</strong></p>


<ul><li>Users can view Featured Collections in Affiliate SERPs</li>
<li>Mobile users see boosted sites</li>
<li>Affiliates have option to embed iFrame that renders search results</li>
<li>Improve monthly reporting process</li>
<li>Update Popular Pages for Affiliates</li>
<li>Affiliates may assign published start and end date to a Featured Collection</li>
<li>User sees Popular Pages in Agency Govbox</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Bugs:</strong></p>


<ul><li><span>Fix accessibility issues</span></li>
<li><span>User see error page when the request contains unrecognized extension</span></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Chores:</strong></p>


<ul><li><span>Improve monthly reporting process</span></li>
<li><span>Affiliate admin can assign published start and end date to a Featured Collection</span></li>
<li><span>Click table housekeeping</span></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[USASearch Wins InformationWeek Award]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/award-informationweek.html"/>
    <updated>2011-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/award-informationweek.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>InformationWeek</em> yesterday <a href="http://www.informationweek.com/news/galleries/government/leadership/231600939">recognized 15 government agencies</a> for taking on ambitious IT initiatives in an effort to provide better services at a lower cost.</p>

<p>Former federal CIO Vivek Kundra talked often about the technology gap that separates government workers from private-sector employees. Federal, state, and local government agencies have many initiatives under way in an effort to close that gap.</p>

<p>They're employing cloud computing, software as a service, the Web, mobile technologies, and more to give government workers the tools they need to be more productive and to deliver public services more efficiently.</p>

<p>GSA's USASearch was one of those honored by <em>InformationWeek</em> for making government services in English and in Spanish more accessible online with a revamped version of USASearch and its set of advanced search technologies for <a href="http://www.usa.gov">USA.gov</a>. Noted was our use of Microsoft's Bing Index, open source technologies such MySQL, Hadoop, and OpenCalais, and employing agile development to deliver new features quickly.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_lrjk43Q2sP1qid15q.png" alt="Web results for a search on white house on USA.gov" /></p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_lrjk5nzgYz1qid15q.png" alt="Image results for a search on white house on USA.gov" /></p>

<p>The award also cited our affiliate program which now includes hundreds of government websites that share our services and data through the platform. This affiliate program offers free search services to any federal, state, local, tribal, or territorial government agency. Affiliates can create a customized search experience that best fits their clients' needs through a simple, online administrative console.</p>

<p>Read about USASearch and the other 14&#160;InformationWeek award recipients at <a href="http://www.informationweek.com/news/galleries/government/leadership/231600939">http://www.informationweek.com/news/galleries/government/leadership/231600939</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NY State Dept of Environmental Conservation Rolls Out New Site Search]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/nysdec.html"/>
    <updated>2011-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/nysdec.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The New York State <a href="http://www.dec.ny.gov">Department of Environmental Conservation</a> (DEC) was created on July 1,1970 to combine in a single agency all state programs designed to protect and enhance the environment. Its mission is to conserve, improve and protect New York's natural resources and environment and to prevent, abate and control water, land and air pollution, in order to enhance the health, safety and welfare of the people of the state and their overall economic and social well-being.</p>

<p>DEC recently rolled out a new site search functionality using USASearch. Be sure to visit <a href="http://www.dec.ny.gov">http://www.dec.ny.gov</a> and take a look for yourself.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/testimonial-nysdec.png" alt="Search results on the Department of Environmental Conservation's website" /></p>

<p>Regarding their experience, the DEC web team shares:</p>

<blockquote><p>We rolled out the search on our public website last week. So far, all of the feedback has been extremely positive. Everyone here loves the new search so thank you for providing this service to us!</p></blockquote>

<p>We're glad to hear that we were able to help improve their customers' search experience.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July Release Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-08-11.html"/>
    <updated>2011-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-08-11.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We  hope everyone is staying cool in the dog days of our August summer, but  just because it is hot doesn't mean the USASearch team isn't busy. <br/><br/>We  would like to point out an enhancement to our Add to Bing feature.  Immediately after you add a page to Bing, we automatically include it in  your Boosted Content. Once the document is added to the Bing index, we  automatically remove the entry from your Boosted Content. We hope you  enjoy this enhancement as it is something that many of you told us was a  high priority fix.<br/><br/>As a reminder, we divide our work into three categories:<br/><br/>1) FeaturesThings that you actually notice<br/>2) BugsFixes to any code issues that may arise<br/>3) ChoresBack-end improvements that aren't noticed<br/><br/>Without further adieu, below are the August release notes.<br/><br/><strong>Features </strong></p>


<ul><li>Users may find pages added via Add to Bing, even if the pages aren't yet indexed by Bing</li>
<li>Users see a white background color on the default search results page template. </li>
<li>Users see an improved <a href="http://search.usa.gov/thispagedoesnotexist">404 page</a> on Search.USA.gov. </li>
<li>Users see a fun, improved <a href="http://search.usa.gov/search?query=thisisapagewithnoresults">no results page</a> on Search.USA.gov</li>
<li>User sees blended USA.gov FAQs on Search.USA.gov results pages</li>
<li>Users see boosted URLs below boosted collections</li>
<li>Users can view up to 1000 results</li>
<li>Users don't trigger type-ahead suggestions when they use up or down arrows</li>
<li>Users see a three-column results page with vertical navigation in left column</li>
<li>Users go to the landing page when they click on the search button without a query </li>
<li>Users see related clinical trials in MedlinePlus Govboxes</li>
<li>Users see Related Topics below organic Bing web results</li>
<li>User sees improved pagination links on results pages</li>
<li>Users see Recommended by {affiliate_name} for URLs boosted content on affiliate results pages </li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Bugs </strong></p>


<ul><li>Affiliate users see a confirmation popup when they delete a site</li>
<li>Fixed a misspelled variable name</li>
<li>Hide phone icon when there's no number in Agency Govboxes</li>
<li>Words are no longer truncated in boosted content entries</li>
<li>HTML tags no longer show up in search results description</li>
<li>USA.gov FAQs now only appear on the first page</li>
<li>Search terms are no longer inadvertently selected as users type in the search box</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Chores</strong></p>


<ul><li>Imaging/images is no longer stemmed in Solr</li>
<li>Upgraded to Rails 3.0.9</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[June Release Notes & Happy Fourth of July]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-07-01.html"/>
    <updated>2011-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-07-01.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span><span>The USASearch Team wishes everyone a safe and happy Fourth of July. Before everyone departs for the long holiday, we wanted to post our June release notes.</span><br/></span></p>


<p>As a reminder, we divide our work into three categories:</p>


<p>1) Features  things that you actually notice<br/>2)Bugs  Fixes to any code issues that may arise<br/>3)Chores  back-end improvements that you don't notice</p>


<p>Features:</p>


<p>For End Users Users:</p>


<ul><li>Users see polished agency GovBox design</li>
<li>Users see aligned text on SERPs</li>
<li>Users don't see underlines on SERPs</li>
<li>User sees health GovBoxes</li>
<li>Users have improved accessibility for USASearch Program pages</li>
<li>Users see consistently-aligned items on landing pages</li>
<li>Users see added agency popular url model incl govbox view</li>
<li>Users see PDF before serp result titles for pdf urls</li>
<li>Users see improved basic_gray search term highlite visibility and removed</li>
<li>Mobile users can see SMS option</li>
<li>Spanish searchers can find web and imagenes landing pages</li>
</ul>


<p>For Admins:</p>


<ul><li>USAAdmins can easily batch process new users by status</li>
<li>Analysts see 4 column daily click module containing module name, impressions, clicks, and CTR%</li>
</ul>


<p>Fixes:</p>


<ul><li>Users should not have letters "skipped" as they're typing in the search box</li>
<li>Display shorter URLs on Affiliate SERPs</li>
<li>Affiliates should not see global terms populated in type ahead</li>
<li>Update API language</li>
<li>Fix type ahead suggestion drop down and font size in Grey Template</li>
<li>Modify indices on agency_urls</li>
<li>Boosted Sites/Spotlights/GovBoxes don't have proper precedence rules.</li>
<li>HTML shows up on affiliate confirmation screen</li>
<li>Users don't see web vertical spotlights on forms vertical</li>
<li>Search users should be able to see SAYT dropdown</li>
<li>Users get page not found error when logging out from some program/admin pages</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adopting Apache Hadoop in the Federal Government]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/adopting-hadoop.html"/>
    <updated>2011-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/adopting-hadoop.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Background</strong></p>


<p>The United States federal government's <a href="http://usasearch.howto.gov">USASearch program</a> provides hosted search services for government affiliate organizations, shares APIs and web services, and operates the government's official search engine at Search.USA.gov. The USASearch affiliate program offers free search services to any federal, state, local, tribal, or territorial government agency. Several hundred websites make use of this service, ranging from the smallest municipality to larger federal sites like <a href="http://weather.gov" target="_blank">weather.gov</a> and <a href="http://usa.gov" target="_blank">usa.gov</a>. The USASearch program leverages the Bing API as the basis for its web results and then augments the user search experience by providing a variety of government-centric information such as related search topics and highlighted editorial content. The entire system is comprised of a suite of open-source tools and resources, including Apache Solr/Lucene, OpenCalais, and Apache Hadoop. Of these, our usage of Hadoop is the most recent. We began using <a href="http://www.cloudera.com/hadoop/" target="_blank">Cloudera's Distribution including Apache Hadoop</a> (<a href="http://www.cloudera.com/hadoop" target="_blank">CDH3</a>) for the first time in the Fall, and since then we've seen our usage grow every month not just in scale, but in scope as well. But before highlighting everything the USASearch program is doing with Hadoop today, I should explain why we began using it in the first place.</p>


<p><strong>Phase 1: Search analytics</strong></p>


<p>All of the search and <a href="http://search.usa.gov/api" target="_blank">API</a> traffic across hundreds of affiliate sites, iPhone apps, and widgets comes through a single search service, and this generates a lot of data. To improve the service, administrators wanted to see aggregated information on what sorts of information searchers were looking for, how well they were finding it, what trends were forming, and so on. Once searches were initiated, they also wanted to know what results were shown and then what results were clicked on. They wanted to see all this information broken down by affiliate over time, and also aggregated across the entire affiliate landscape.</p>


<p>The initial system, like many initial systems, was fairly simple and did just enough to address our most pressing analytics needs. We took the logs from Apache and Ruby on Rails, put them in a big MySQL database on a separate machine, ran nightly and monthly jobs on them, and then exported the summary results to the main database cluster to be served up via a low-latency Rails web interface for analytics. We used a separate physical database machine with lots of memory and disk for the batch processing to keep our production MySQL instances from being impacted by this resource-intensive batch processing.</p>


<p><img alt="Diagram showing the initial dataflow of raw logfiles to analytics apps" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_lle73iJ2Ts1qid15q.png"/></p>


<p>As we watched the main database tables grow and the nightly batch jobs take longer and longer, it became clear that we would soon exhaust the resources available on the single database analytics processing node. We looked at scaling up the hardware vertically and sharding the database horizontally, but both options seemed like we were just kicking the can down the road. Larger database hardware would be both costly and eventually insufficient for our needs, and sharding promised to take all the usual issues associated with a single database system (backups, master/slaves, schema management) and multiply them. We wanted the system to be able to grow cost effectively and without downtime, be naturally resilient to failures, and have backups handled sensibly. It was at this point that we started investigating HDFS, Hadoop, and Apache Hive.</p>


<p>HDFS offered us a distributed, resilient, and scalable filesystem while Hadoop promised to bring the work to where the data resided so we could make efficient use of local disk on multiple nodes. Hive, however, really pushed our decision in favor of a Hadoop-based system. Our data is just unstructured enough to make traditional RDBMS schemas a bit brittle and restrictive, but has enough structure to make a schema-less NoSQL system unnecessarily vague. Hive let us compromise between the two it's sort of a "SomeSQL" system.</p>


<p>But best of all, we could layer the entire Cloudera stack on top of a subset of our existing production machines. By making use of each machine's excess reserve capacity of disk, CPU, and RAM, we were able to get a small proof-of-concept cluster stood up without purchasing any new hardware. The initial results confirmed that our workload lent itself well to distributed processing, as one job went from taking over an hour on a MySQL node to 20 minutes on a three machine Hadoop cluster. Within a week of getting the prototype up and running, we had transitioned all the remaining nightly analytics batch SQL jobs into Hive scripts. The job output fed into a collection of intermediate Hive tables, from which we generated summary data to export to MySQL as low-latency tables for the Rails web interface to use. To prove the scaling point, we spent five minutes adding another datanode/tasktracker to the mix, kicked off the cluster rebalancer, and the whole process ran faster the next day.</p>


<p><img alt="Diagram showing the current dataflow of raw logfiles to analytics apps" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_lle73rea1K1qid15q.png"/></p>


<p><strong>Phase 2: Feedback loop</strong></p>


<p>The result of all this analysis in Hive shows up not just in various analytics dashboards, but as part of the search experience on many government websites, too. For example, compare the different type-ahead suggestions for <strong>gran</strong>' on <a href="http://nps.gov/">nps.gov</a> and <a>usa.gov</a>. Both sites use the same USASearch backend system, but the suggestions differ completely. We use Hadoop to help us generate contextually relevant and timely search suggestions for hundreds of government sites like this.</p>


<p><img alt="Image showing different type-ahead suggestions on NPS.gov and USA.gov" src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/tumblr_lle73ymed31qid15q.png"/></p>


<p><strong>Phase 3: Internal monitoring</strong></p>


<p>Shortly after moving our event stream analysis from MySQL to Hadoop/Hive, we noticed a change in how we thought about data. Freed from the constant anxiety of wondering how we were going to handle an ever-increasing amount of data, we shifted from trying to store only what we really needed to storing whatever we thought might be useful. We first turned our attention to the performance data emitted by the various sub-systems that make up the search program.</p>


<p>Each search results page is potentially made up of many data modules sintered together from calls to the Bing API, our own Solr indexes, a MySQL cluster, and a Redis cache. A small latency problem with any one of them can propagate through the system to create much larger problems, so we want to have a deep knowledge of how each subsystem behaves throughout the day under various circumstances. We were already monitoring the availability of all these services with Opsview, but we had no insight into their performance over time. Whenever we sensed a problem ("Is one of the Solr indexes getting slow?"), we would liberally apply ssh, tail -f, and grep to try to see what was going on. This seemed like a good use case for Hive, so in the case of Solr, for example, we threw the compressed log files into HDFS, wrote a simple SerDe regular expression to define rows in a Hive table partitioned by date, and built a view on top of that for easy manipulation of extracted columns such as the Solr index name and the hour of day. Hive makes it trivially easy to do some fairly sophisticated aggregate analysis on the response times for each Solr index, such as generating a distribution histogram, or calculating the pth percentile.</p>


<p>Some of these Hive queries are not run very often perhaps just a few times a month so we don't want to spend time building them into our test-driven Rails analytics framework. On the other hand, they are complex enough that we don't want to rewrite them every time we want to use them. For these cases, we use Beeswax in HUE to save off parameterized queries that can then be shared among engineers or analysts to run on an ad hoc basis.</p>


<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>


<p>In the space of a few months, we've gone from having a brittle and hard-to-scale RDBMS-based analytics platform to a much more agile Hadoop-based system that was designed to scale intrinsically. We continue to see our Hadoop usage grow in scope with each new data source we add, and it's clear that we'll be relying on it more and more in the future as the suite of tools and resources around Hadoop grows and matures.</p>


<p><em>By Loren</em></p>


<p><em><strong>This post is cross-posted from <a href="http://www.cloudera.com/blog/2011/04/adopting-apache-hadoop-in-the-federal-government/" title="Cloudera">Cloudera</a>.</strong></em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Congratulations to Mary Sue Deffily, Program...]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/award-affirm.html"/>
    <updated>2011-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/blog/award-affirm.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/award-affirm.jpg" alt="Mary Sue Deffily accepts the 2011 AFFIRM Leadership Award for Innovative Applications" /></p>

<p>Congratulations to Mary Sue Deffily, USASearch Program Manager, for winning the 2011 AFFIRM Leadership Award for Innovative Applications presented for superior leadership in innovative government business applications or systems.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Release Notes]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-05-31.html"/>
    <updated>2011-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/releases/2011-05-31.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the ongoing government effort for transparency, we are going to use our blog to post our release notes on a monthly basis. While they may not be the most exciting posts ever, it seems the logical place to publish our activities. Search, as many know, is difficult with many of the improvements happening behind the scenes.</p>


<p>We divide our work into three categories:</p>


<p>1) Features &#8212; things that you actually notice</p>


<p>2) Bugs &#8212; Fixes to any code issues that may arise </p>


<p>3) Chores &#8212; back-end improvements that you don't notice </p>


<p>We did complete a big chore this month by upgrading to Rails 3 which will be invisible to you, but it will bring additional stability for our search environment and allow us to have longer feature list in the coming months.</p>


<p><strong>New/Enhanced Features:</strong></p>


<ul><li>Searchers see new second-level top navigation on landing pages and SERPs on <a href="http://Search.USA.gov">Search.USA.gov</a> and <a href="http://search.usa.gov/?locale=es">Buscador.USA.gov</a></li>
<li>Spanish searchers see improved <a href="http://search.usa.gov/?locale=es">web</a> and <a href="http://search.usa.gov/images?locale=es&amp;m=false">image</a> landing pages</li>
<li>Spanish searchers see brown color scheme</li>
<li>Visitors sees <a href="http://www.usa.gov">USA.gov</a>-branded search box on all pages</li>
<li>Searchers see updated affiliate and mobile type-ahead search suggestions</li>
<li>Mobile visitors can see SMS option on m.USA.gov</li>
<li><span>Searchers see updated affiliate and mobile pages</span><span> </span></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Bugs:</strong></p>


<ul><li>Fixed bugs/display problems with monthly clicks/queries</li>
<li>Inconsistent autocomplete on images landing page and image SERPs</li>
<li>Spanish searchers see updated text on Buscador.USA.gov <a href="http://search.usa.gov/search/advanced?locale=es&amp;m=false">advanced search page</a></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Chores:</strong></p>


<ul><li>Upgraded to Rails 3 &#8212; the chore list would be long, but let us know if anyone is interested in hearing about the upgrade</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spotlight: Broward County, Florida]]></title>
    <link href="http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/broward.html"/>
    <updated>2011-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://usasearch.howto.gov/customers/broward.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While USASearch is for all levels of government (federal, state, local, tribal, and territorial), most of our customers come from the federal sector. So, we are showcasing a highly-trafficked county site to show how other levels of government successfully leverage our site search service.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.broward.org">Broward County, Florida</a> has a popular web site that serves thousands of multi-lingual users from the Miami metropolitan area.</p>

<p><img src="https://9fddeb862c037f6d2190-f1564c64756a8cfee25b6b19953b1d23.ssl.cf2.rackcdn.com/customers-broward.png" alt="Broward.org homepage" /></p>

<p>We want to thank Rob Nadeau (Web Site Manager for Broward County) for being a good and supportive customer and someone who proactively implements our special features!</p>

<p>Rob offered these kind words about USASearch.</p>

<blockquote><p>When USASearch expanded their affiliate program, <a href="http://www.broward.org">Broward County</a> was fortunate to be the first County in the nation to participate in the effort. During times when budgets are limited, the partnership monetarily saved the County by not moving to a commercial search solution. As the program evolved to "new" technology and tools, the County and our visitors once again benefited from an ever-growing feature rich program that now offers a more accurate search with speed 9 times faster.</p>

<ul>
<li>a customized look and feel</li>
<li>the ability to immediately boost content to showcase specific pages to appear above the main results</li>
<li>type-ahead search suggestions for visitors to our site</li>
<li>the ability to add and remove search suggestions</li>
<li>the ability to generate reports</li>
</ul>


<p>Thank you for a program that keeps on giving.</p></blockquote>

<p>Thank you, Rob, and everyone please help us spread the word about USASearch to all levels of government.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
